<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2017 on tangly Components</title>
    <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2017 on tangly Components</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why Use Current Software Components?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/why-use-current-software-components/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/why-use-current-software-components/</guid>
      <description>Often, teams discuss if their digital product should upgrade to the current version of open-source or commercial used components.&#xA;The same discussion arises for development tools and programming language versions.&#xA;I have a strong opinion about upgrades. You should always use the current version of all components included in your product. The only discussion is the timely when and never the if.&#xA;Be realist, if your product is successful, you have to upgrade before the components are obsolete.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clean Your Desk and Define New Year Improvements</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/clean-your-desk-and-define-new-year-improvements/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/clean-your-desk-and-define-new-year-improvements/</guid>
      <description>It is Christmastime.&#xA;Clean your desk and the content of your workstation. Upgrade your tools and your development environment to the actual version.&#xA;It is time to add automated build pipelines, TDD, ATDD, and Docker to your toolbox. Embrace agile approaches.&#xA;Work focused and avoid overtime. Prioritize outcomes instead of outputs. Enjoy family life, practice sport, and pursue continuous training.&#xA;Clean Your Desk Digitalize Your Office It is time to sell the last fax device in your office and plan to remove your big printer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impediment List is of Tremendous Importance</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/impediment-list-is-of-tremendous-importance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/impediment-list-is-of-tremendous-importance/</guid>
      <description>An impediment is any aspect hindering the team or a company to deliver value and higher quality to the customers.&#xA;An agile organization continuously removes impediments. It is one of her major activities. This activity is ongoing and can never be completed.&#xA;Impediments resolution is Kaizen 改善, a key technique to lean, agile and Scrum approaches. The translation is change for better.&#xA;Often agile organizations forget to aggressively identify and resolve impediments.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Approaches and Fix Price Contracts</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/agile-approaches-and-fix-price-contracts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/agile-approaches-and-fix-price-contracts/</guid>
      <description>The difficulty with contracts is that it is about trust. Here lays the roots for success or disaster.&#xA;If no trust exists, the henceforth dreaded process is established. After tough negotiations, the development team starts but does not collaborate with the customer. They just build what is written in outdated requirements. A subpar solution is shipped and the relationship with the customer is deeply damaged.&#xA;We can do better. We shall collaborate, trust each other and create an awesome product.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your Management Job in an Agile Environment</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/your-management-job-in-an-agile-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/your-management-job-in-an-agile-environment/</guid>
      <description>You develop your software products using agile approaches. You are doing Scrum, Kanban, Scrumban, Lean Software Development, or LeSS.&#xA;Your collaborators start asking questions about their organization, management roles, and critique the internal processes.&#xA;How employee yearly evaluation, bonus evaluation – work? You hear strange statements such Be agile, do not do agile.&#xA;You as a manager realize you have to describe your role in an agile environment. What does it mean?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scrum Masters are not Administrators</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/scrum-masters-are-not-administrators/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/scrum-masters-are-not-administrators/</guid>
      <description>Readers know I am an early adopter of agile and Scrum approaches.&#xA;I experienced how much more effective and fun it is to work in an agile team developing digital products.&#xA;Lately I was asked if I was interested in working as a Scrum master [1, 2, 3].&#xA;The job description below was handed me over. What an experience it was.&#xA;The text with the regular font is the job description.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What does a Scrum Master?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/what-does-a-scrum-master/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/what-does-a-scrum-master/</guid>
      <description>What does a Scrum master the whole day?&#xA;Are you just a fancy administrator or are you actively removing impediments?&#xA;Do you coach your teams toward mastery?&#xA;Too often, Scrum masters become Scrum administrators.&#xA;They schedule meetings, moderate discussions, write progress reports and draw beautiful slides how to improve the organization.&#xA;Or worst, they collect extensive statistics about velocity, planned versus delivered story points or how precise story estimation was.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>So Called Agile and Scrum Failures</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/so-called-agile-and-scrum-failures/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/so-called-agile-and-scrum-failures/</guid>
      <description>Agile will never guarantee product success.&#xA;All projects, especially application development, entail risk.&#xA;If a product was risk-free, it is unlikely to provide significant benefits or competitive advantages.&#xA;There are a number of ways in which Agile Scrum projects repeatedly fail which are worth examining.&#xA;Agile approaches and Scrum framework can reduce risks in projects and increase the return on investment. Standish Group report is a proof of this statement.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Git Local Repositories for the Impatient</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/git-local-repositories-for-the-impatient/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/git-local-repositories-for-the-impatient/</guid>
      <description>You shall put your source code and text documentation under a version management system.&#xA;The actual industrial standard for version control systems is git, a distributed version control system - DVCS -. It tracks changes in any set of computer files, usually used for coordinating work among programmers who are collaboratively developing source code during software development.&#xA;Subversion was a great tool and should now be retired. Simple refactoring activities with renaming will already corrupt a subversion repository.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is Our Specialty as Agile Coaches at tangly?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/what-is-our-specialty-as-agile-coaches-at-tangly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/what-is-our-specialty-as-agile-coaches-at-tangly/</guid>
      <description>You have more agile coaches on the market than sand-corns on a regular beach.&#xA;They all promise the holly grail of agile product development, highly productive teams and perfect applications for internal and external customers.&#xA;Why should any sane customer hire us to deploy or perfect their agile approach?&#xA;Your overall goal is to continuously improve the products delivered to customers.&#xA;I am convinced to achieve ingrained success an agile coach shall:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Trends Switzerland 2017: We Won</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/agile-trends-switzerland-2017-we-won/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/agile-trends-switzerland-2017-we-won/</guid>
      <description>It is time to throw a big party in Switzerland. More than 60% of all projects are now realized using an agile approach (to see Agile Trends in Switzerland 2017] by SwissQ [1]. Scrum being the most popular one, Kanban as the second one. What a change in just one year. In 2016, we had 40% of projects being agile, one year later we have 60%. Time to adapt and become agile.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fun at Workplace</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/fun-at-workplace/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/fun-at-workplace/</guid>
      <description>It is Spring in Switzerland. We often have time for small talk because it is cold or rainy outside.&#xA;Quite a few of the discussions are about job opportunities, and how interesting and motivating the current activities are.&#xA;I selected two articles to help everybody to decide if your software development job is worth the effort.&#xA;Go through the questions and ask yourself if the current product provides the current settings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>List of Agile and Lean Books for Software Engineers or Students</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/list-of-agile-and-lean-books-for-software-engineers-or-students/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/list-of-agile-and-lean-books-for-software-engineers-or-students/</guid>
      <description>I am regularly asked by practitioners and technical universities, which books I shall recommend learning more about agile developers, agile projects, and agile companies.&#xA;Reading is a great way to learn and to get new ideas.&#xA;Below, a selection of books I read and found fascinating.&#xA;The selection is certainly not exhaustive.&#xA;The criteria are&#xA;I read the book and learnt something.&#xA;I have bought this book to have it as a reference.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Trends Switzerland 2016</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/agile-trends-switzerland-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/agile-trends-switzerland-2016/</guid>
      <description>What are the main hurdles to introducing agile approaches in Swiss companies? The last five years learn us that:&#xA;Introducing agile company-wide is a cultural change process. Such a change takes time and sometimes hurts.&#xA;Without the commitment of senior management, the initiative will fail.&#xA;You must teach, coach, support your collaborators through the transition. You need to believe in them and provide an environment where they can safely learn and experiment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seven Pitfalls with Agile or Scrum Methods</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/seven-pitfalls-with-agile-or-scrum-methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/seven-pitfalls-with-agile-or-scrum-methods/</guid>
      <description>The post describes a presentation I gave at a company internal technical day. It reflects situations we have seen in a lot of agile projects over the last years.&#xA;I assume that the Scrum approach is well introduced in your company.&#xA;You are already proficient with Scrum, eXtreme Programming, Clean Code, Code Refactoring, how to write stories and story maps, and techniques such as TDD, ATDD.&#xA;You are using Scrum well and can laugh about all these posts about Scrum-But(t).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
