<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tangly Components – Architecture Design Record (ADR)</title>
    <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/ui/adr/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Architecture Design Record (ADR) on tangly Components</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/ui/adr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: ERPUI-001: Markdown for all Text Fields</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/ui/adr/erpui-001-markdown-for-all-texts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/ui/adr/erpui-001-markdown-for-all-texts/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;div class=&#34;sect1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;_erpui_001_markdown_for_all_text_fields&#34;&gt;ERPUI-001 Markdown for all Text Fields&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sectionbody&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: 2021-06-01&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_status&#34;&gt;Status&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implemented&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_context&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markdown is a well-establish approach to write rich text documentation or comments.
The casual user can learn and use the notation without excessive effort.
The legibility and professional appearance of Markdown texts are markantly higher than plain text.
Markdown is an open standard and used in various environments and tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_decision&#34;&gt;Decision&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All texts and comments in the ERP components shall use Markdown notation to improve legibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternatives would be proprietary formats such as Microsoft Word or more sophisticated notations such as Asciidoc.
Our open source approach to product development rejects any propriatary formats.
Asciidoc is a very powerful and successful format.
The associated complexity for the users is probably an overkill for casual users of our product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Text and comments in our system should have a limited length complexity.
Markdown is an optimal balance between expression power and ease of use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_consequences&#34;&gt;Consequences&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markdown is backward compatible with text fields.
No migration of existing records is needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The user interface components shall be extended to support a Markdown visualiation and editing component.
Vaadin currently does not provide native support for Markdown.
The tangly-os components will be extended to provide such a component until Vaadin supports in the future such an approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
