<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vaadin UI on tangly Components</title>
    <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/ui/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vaadin UI on tangly Components</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.tangly.net/docs/ui/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Readme</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/ui/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/ui/readme/</guid>
      <description>Purpose The tangly ui erp component provides a Vaadin based user interfaces for enterprise applications written in Java. The component is using records and requires Java 21 LTS or higher.&#xA;Currently, we are moving at the bleeding edge of our components. Therefore, to build and execute the ERP application, please do:&#xA;mvn jetty:run The initial username and password are &amp;#39;administrator&amp;#39; and &amp;#39;aeon&amp;#39;.&#xA;The file application.properties in …/main/resources directory tailors the configuration of the application, mainly the location of data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Release Notes</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/ui/releasesnotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/ui/releasesnotes/</guid>
      <description>Commons UI Library Change Logs This document provides a high-level view of the changes introduced in the Common UI library by release. For a detailed view of what has changed, refer to the repository commits.&#xA;0.2.7 (2024-05-31) Update of library dependencies, update to JDK-21, and modern Gradle approach to build solutions.&#xA;0.2.6 (2021-08-31) Improvements CRM analytics are provided to have an analytics reporting of key indicators&#xA;Support for localized invoice generation and support of CHF and EUR as currency</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>User Guide UI</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/ui/userguide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/ui/userguide/</guid>
      <description>User Guide Commons Vaadin UI Views Views display a set of instances of an entity. The view provides the regular CRUD operations:&#xA;View details of an entity instance.&#xA;Modify an entity instance. The user can edit all properties of an object in the user interface. All changes are buffered in the user interface components. She can decide to propage the changes to the model or discard them through save or cancel operations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developer Guide UI</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/ui/developerguide/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/ui/developerguide/</guid>
      <description>Developer Guide Commons UI Develop ERP Application Run From Command Line To run quickly from the command-line in development mode:&#xA;./gradlew run (1) 1 Your app will be running on http://localhost:8080. Run From IDE Run ./gradle vaadinPrepareFrontend in the project, to configure Vaadin for npm mode.&#xA;Run/Debug the EmbeddedJetty class as an application (run the _main()- method). The app will use npm to download all javascript libraries (will take a long time) and will start in development mode.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>User Guide tangly ERP</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/ui/userguideerp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/ui/userguideerp/</guid>
      <description>ERP Introduction The tangly ERP application promotes the various open source components our tangly company develops, supports, and publishes.&#xA;We are a strong supporter of the eat your own dog food approach. The application is used to run daily business and all financial processes of our company. All data since the inception were moved in the application. This approach is ideal for the industrialization and validation of all features.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ERP Design</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/ui/design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/ui/design/</guid>
      <description>ERP Design Context Persistence Folder Structure Files are written in italics font, folders are written in bold font. Examples with content are provided for each file type as test resources. These resources are available in the git repository.&#xA;Entity Abstraction The entity abstraction has five kinds of properties&#xA;Simple Properties are all displayed in a form part of a properties tab for visualization or editing.&#xA;Comments are displayed as a CRUD Grid - Form component part of a comments tab for visualization or editing following CRUD approach.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
