<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hugo on tangly Components</title>
    <link>https://blog.tangly.net/tags/hugo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hugo on tangly Components</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.tangly.net/tags/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Asciidoc and Hugo Website Improvements</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/asciidoc-and-hugo-website-improvements/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/asciidoc-and-hugo-website-improvements/</guid>
      <description>The static website build tool Hugo is awesome.&#xA;The extensive built-in feature set of Hugo and the feature-rich typesetting that Asciidoc offers provide a blogging experience composed of easy content management and fun writing experience.&#xA;Source code highlighting and diagrams are extensively supported.&#xA;Hugo supports natively Asciidoc syntax. Asciidoc files are automatically compiled with Asciidoctor, so we do not need to configure anything. Have it installed and you are ready to go.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Static Website Improvements</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/static-website-improvements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/static-website-improvements/</guid>
      <description>The static website build tool Hugo is awesome.&#xA;The extensive built-in feature set of Hugo and the feature-rich text-formatting options that Asciidoc offers creates a blogging experience composed of easy content management and fun writing experience.&#xA;The Hugo theme Docsy is ideal to create a good-looking software documentation site. The templates for blogging are good enough for our needs.&#xA;This theme is currently the best match I found to combine product documentation with blogging.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving a Static Web Site Build With Hugo and Docsy</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/improving-a-static-web-site-build-with-hugo-and-docsy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/improving-a-static-web-site-build-with-hugo-and-docsy/</guid>
      <description>The static website build tool Hugo is awesome. With the extensive built-in feature set of Hugo and the feature-rich text formatting options that Asciidoc offers, it creates a blogging experience composed of easy content management and fun writing experience.&#xA;In most static site generators including Hugo, Markdown is the one and only first-class citizen when it comes to creating posts.&#xA;However, in recent Hugo versions, external helpers are an official feature.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Support Comments for Static Hugo Website</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/support-comments-for-static-hugo-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/support-comments-for-static-hugo-website/</guid>
      <description>There are times in software when you are facing a problem, you find an off-the-shelf solution, and a few lines of code later it just works.&#xA;Today I lived one of those moments.&#xA;The whole configuration of comments and modification of the Docsy theme took around one hour.&#xA;Motivation I wanted to add a comment section to this blog for a while. I was reluctant to implement one myself the classical way, using an external service such as disqus.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating a technical Website with Hugo and Asciidoc</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/creating-a-technical-website-with-hugo-and-asciidoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/creating-a-technical-website-with-hugo-and-asciidoc/</guid>
      <description>I hosted my technical blogs on blogger for years.&#xA;If I correctly remember, I started to use blogger ten years ago. It was a good choice at that time.&#xA;I could easily write blogs and publish them.&#xA;It is a great tool with some drawbacks. Over the years, the deficiencies sting more and more&#xA;The major drawbacks are:&#xA;Their editor is brittle, with limited functionality and unreliable. The generated HTML is not legible and does not support concepts such as micro fragments, meta information or simple functions such as source code highlighting.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
