<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2023 on tangly Components</title>
    <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2023 on tangly Components</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bus Sensors and Actuators</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/bus-sensors-and-actuators/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/bus-sensors-and-actuators/</guid>
      <description>Your embedded system has a set of sensors and actors.&#xA;Some sensors and actors are connected to a bus. Typical buses are CAN bus, Serial Peripherical Interface, Ethernet, Bluetooth, or I2C standards.&#xA;The bus is a shared medium used to communicate with a set of external active or passive components.&#xA;Which design rules shall you follow when designing sensors and actors using a bus architecture?&#xA;Do you need to consider threading design?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sensors and Actuators</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/sensors-and-actuators/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/sensors-and-actuators/</guid>
      <description>Embedded design maps domain abstractions to the underlying hardware.&#xA;A temperature sensor is a domain abstraction of a physical hardware temperature sensor.&#xA;A valve is a domain abstraction of a physical hardware valve. A physical valve can be a simple opened-closed device, or a proportional device.&#xA;The microcontroller board reads the temperature sensor through an I2C or SPI bus. It controls the valve through a GPIO, a PWM or a CAN bus controller.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Command Interpreter</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/command-interpreter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/command-interpreter/</guid>
      <description>Most digital products have a command interpreter.&#xA;External systems send requests to the system and often await an answer. A command interpreter can model this behavior.&#xA;The channels used to transmit requests and return answers are variable. Messages can be transmitted other various buses and protocols.&#xA;An operator can send a command over a CAN bus, Serial Peripherical Interface, Ethernet or Bluetooth connection.&#xA;A regular command line interpreter inputs commands as a string containing a request and associated parameters.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Commits for the Impatient</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/semantic-commits-for-the-impatient/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/semantic-commits-for-the-impatient/</guid>
      <description>The conventional commits specification is a lightweight convention on top of commit messages. The additional information classifies the type of work performed in the commit.&#xA;A developer infers the importance of the task by looking to the type of the commit. The message communicates the nature of changes to teammates, the public, and other stakeholders.&#xA;Contributors of project repositories know that a well-designed Git commit message is the best way to communicate the context about a change to other developers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gradle Good Practices</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/gradle-good-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/gradle-good-practices/</guid>
      <description>Gradle Build Tool is a fast, dependable, and adaptable open-source build automation tool with an elegant and extensible declarative build language. Java is the primary supported programming language.&#xA;Gradle Build Tool is a popular build system for the JVM and is the default system for Android and Kotlin Multi-Platform projects.&#xA;It has a rich community plugin ecosystem. Groovy, Kotlin, C++, and Swift stacks are well-supported.&#xA;Gradle is fast, scalable, and can build projects of any size and complexity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Static Website Improvements</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/static-website-improvements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/static-website-improvements/</guid>
      <description>The static website build tool Hugo is awesome.&#xA;The extensive built-in feature set of Hugo and the feature-rich text-formatting options that Asciidoc offers creates a blogging experience composed of easy content management and fun writing experience.&#xA;The Hugo theme Docsy is ideal to create a good-looking software documentation site. The templates for blogging are good enough for our needs.&#xA;This theme is currently the best match I found to combine product documentation with blogging.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pragmatic Java Application Design</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/pragmatic-java-application-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/pragmatic-java-application-design/</guid>
      <description>I attended the 20th edition of the Devoxx Belgium conference in Antwerp.&#xA;I heard about beautiful examples of how to design complex software applications written in Java.&#xA;The solutions scale to hundreds of thousands of users, are resilient to network disruption and use fancy libraries and tools.&#xA;The applications are deployed on cloud infrastructure and are available worldwide.&#xA;After the conference, I went to Ibiza for a family holiday. Our family enjoys prolonging the summer on this beautiful balearic island.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>C4 and UML with PlantUML</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/c4-and-uml-with-plantuml/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/c4-and-uml-with-plantuml/</guid>
      <description>You are creating an awesome digital product. The software part shall work flawlessly over the years.&#xA;Technology changes will be added to the product. Legal changes and security improvements are implemented in a timely manner over the years.&#xA;This application will evolve to satisfy new needs and customer segments. The life span of your product is probably more than a decade.&#xA;How can you document critical cross-cutting design decisions and key mechanisms?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java Certification</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/java-certification/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/java-certification/</guid>
      <description>Java expertise is in high demand for all kinds of projects, ranging from big enterprise software implementations down to little web projects. A huge number of enterprise applications are developed in Java.&#xA;But will those employers want you to have related certifications?&#xA;Even if you are not looking to move any time soon, getting certified boosts the value that you can bring to your organization.&#xA;Certifications can be a great bargaining chip when it comes to negotiating a raise or a promotion.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20th Devoxx Belgium Conference 2023</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/20th-devoxx-belgium-conference-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/20th-devoxx-belgium-conference-2023/</guid>
      <description>I attended the highly anticipated 20th edition of Devoxx Belgium 2023.&#xA;Building on the success of the previous year, which attracted over 3,200 attendees, this five-day technology conference is set to exceed expectations.&#xA;The fresh release of Java 21 is a hot topic. Renowned speakers share their knowledge and discuss the enhancements that this new version brings, providing a valuable learning opportunity.&#xA;Attending Devoxx Belgium presents a remarkable opportunity to broaden your knowledge, refine your skills, and gain firsthand experience with the most recent technologies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Software Architecture Themes and Questions</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/software-architecture-themes-and-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/software-architecture-themes-and-questions/</guid>
      <description>A software architect works with a development team to define how features shall be realized. The selected approach should support corporate governance and legal constraints.&#xA;A new digital product must fulfill a set of technical aspects to be usable. Technical constraints are the non-functional requirements of the product [1].&#xA;Some of these technical requirements are encountered again and again when developing digital products.&#xA;Any software product must provide solutions to standard problems.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Visual Tools</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/agile-visual-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/agile-visual-tools/</guid>
      <description>Why is visibility so important for any agile or Scrum team?&#xA;When you are running an agile product development initiative, your ultimate goal is customer satisfaction with the delivered solution.&#xA;The project coordination responsibilities are, however, not limited to this single goal.&#xA;The product owner shall nurture the vision, roadmap, the release plan and customer journey. You must coordinate the workflow of your team, refine the product backlog, control identified risks, and track deadlines.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Git Tag for the Impatient</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/git-tag-for-the-impatient/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/git-tag-for-the-impatient/</guid>
      <description>The development software team has reached a milestone.&#xA;A working application with a set of features is available. All tests are green.&#xA;The application can potentially be shipped to internal or external customers.&#xA;How can you mark this event in the git repository of the application?&#xA;Use tags to recognize this state in the list of changes of your shared Git repository.&#xA;Listing Your Tags Listing the existing tags in Git is straightforward.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Git Rebase and Merge for the Impatient</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/git-rebase-and-merge-for-the-impatient/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/git-rebase-and-merge-for-the-impatient/</guid>
      <description>Both the rebase and merge commands provide similar functionalities.&#xA;They combine the work of multiple developers into a single entity, integrating changes between branches.&#xA;That about sums up their similarities.&#xA;The operation git merge is a way of combining changes from one source branch into another target branch. The operation leaves commit messages in the history.&#xA;The operation git rebase is a way of moving the changes from one branch onto another branch.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java 21</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/java-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/java-21/</guid>
      <description>Java 21 LTS was released on time to the public. The release has been available for download since 21st September 2023.&#xA;Pattern matching is maturing nicely. The hope is that more solutions will more advanced data stream manipulation and functional programming algorithms. Complex inheritance structure are no more considered as good practices in regular application. The pattern matching extensions nicely provide idioms to solve similar design problems.&#xA;The support for virtual threads is reaching full integration in the official Java distribution.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Certifications Useful?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/are-certifications-useful/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/are-certifications-useful/</guid>
      <description>There are several benefits to getting an IT certification, and several associated costs too.&#xA;Certifications can give you the chance to learn needed skills, and be a quick way to show employers you have those skills.&#xA;On the other hand, certifications can require studying or coursework. You will invest a significant amount of time to master the material. They cost up to several hundred dollars to take.&#xA;So how do you know that the benefits will outweigh the costs for you?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Corporate Governance for Software Products</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/corporate-governance-for-software-products/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/corporate-governance-for-software-products/</guid>
      <description>Since good governance is about the processes for making and implementing decisions, then effective governance and accountability structures are vital.&#xA;Organizations shall successfully use an agile approach to deliver business change through the investment in programs and projects.&#xA;Agile approaches are the most used frameworks to develop successfully digital products.&#xA;Our corporate governance processes shall support agile values and development methods.&#xA;The four guiding principles to enable successful governance of agile delivery are:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Onboarding Software Developers in Your agile Team</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/onboarding-software-developers-in-your-agile-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/onboarding-software-developers-in-your-agile-team/</guid>
      <description>Now that you have gone through the long and tedious process of hiring a talented developer with vetting and interview activities, it is easy to think that the hard part is done [1] [2].&#xA;There is no doubt that hiring good people is challenging and competitive, but it is a mistake to think that the challenge ends when you hired a new collaborator.&#xA;Onboarding software developers is just as important for getting the most out of the hiring process.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Clojure II</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/teaching-clojure-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/teaching-clojure-ii/</guid>
      <description>Functional programming is hype for the last ten years.&#xA;All popular programming languages have added support to functional concepts for years.&#xA;Not all developers are embracing the new approach and using the provided constructs.&#xA;I often have to read source code which uses only idioms defined in the last millennium. I cringed and asked myself why developers are writing such awkward code?&#xA;What does it mean to code with functional paradigms?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Clojure I</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/teaching-clojure-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/teaching-clojure-i/</guid>
      <description>Functional programming is hype for the last ten years. You find a lot of blogs and videos stating object-oriented languages are doomed.&#xA;Almost all most popular languages have added some support to functional concepts in the last years.&#xA;Java introduced lambda expressions and single abstract method interfaces SAM with Java 8 in March 2014. Java developers are empowered to write functional code for almost ten years.&#xA;Other languages such as Python, C++ or C# added their own functional extensions in newer revisions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java 20</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/java-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/java-20/</guid>
      <description>Java 20 was released on time to the public. The release has been available for download since 21st March 2023.&#xA;Interestingly, the new Java release contains only incubating or preview JEP proposals. No final improvements are part of this version.&#xA;You are a Java developer, you should always install the latest JDK and try it out. Most of the time, all your products will compile and run on the new release without any changes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My New MacBookPro</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/my-new-macbookpro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/my-new-macbookpro/</guid>
      <description>I just received my new MacBookPro M2 Max with 32 GB of RAM and 1 TB SSD [1].&#xA;I know. I am a geek who loves his technical gadgets. I convinced my wife these gadgets are way cheaper than a sports car.&#xA;More seriously, I easily use my workstation forty hours a week. I really appreciate a stable and fast machine. My eyes are thankful if the display has a high resolution and the refresh rate fulfills ergonomic criteria [2].</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Software Developer Assumptions</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/software-developer-assumptions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/software-developer-assumptions/</guid>
      <description>Here are some software development topics I have learnt to like after 40 years in the industry.&#xA;I worked at quite a few industrial and commercial digital product development initiatives. I truly enjoyed creating successful solutions.&#xA;Over the years, I encountered similar architecture and design patterns when creating source code for these applications.&#xA;I started programming with languages such as Ada, Portal, and C. I embraced object-oriented languages with first C++ and later Java.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scrum Masters and Agile Coaches</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/scrum-masters-and-agile-coaches/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/scrum-masters-and-agile-coaches/</guid>
      <description>Scrum is the most popular agile approach used to develop digital products.&#xA;The Scrum master role is well-documented in the Scrum. There are probably more than one million of certified Scrum masters in the world.&#xA;To differentiate themselves from the numerous Scrum masters, consultants call themselves agile coaches.&#xA;Quite a fancy title.&#xA;Does a difference exist between a Scrum master and an agile coach?&#xA;A Scrum master is a type of Agile coach.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Quest for an Agile Company: Seven Years tangly llc</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/the-quest-for-an-agile-company-seven-years-tangly-llc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/the-quest-for-an-agile-company-seven-years-tangly-llc/</guid>
      <description>We are an agile software coaching and digital product development boutique.&#xA;Since our inception, we have created digital products using agile approaches. Our preferred tools are Scrum, Lean Software Development, DevOps, LeSS.&#xA;The created digital products are successful in the market.&#xA;They exhibit good quality. Sound engineering approaches were used to design and construct them in a timely and economical way.&#xA;Our customers learnt how to deploy updates and new functionalities in a matter of days.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Technical Interviews</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/technical-interviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/technical-interviews/</guid>
      <description>Your sole goal is to hire a qualified collaborator with potential.&#xA;For example, you need a great software engineer with social competence. He is a professional developer and has knowledge of the technology stack [1] your company is using. The candidate naturally understands agile and DevOps approaches.&#xA;How can you convince him to sign the contract and start working on your cool product?&#xA;Hiring is like dating.&#xA;Both parties shall be motivated to deepen their relationship and enter a binding agreement.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SME IT Responsible</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/sme-it-responsible/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/sme-it-responsible/</guid>
      <description>What does a senior manager in charge of information technology?&#xA;An IT director is the information technology right-hand man of the company’s manager. He sometimes has the shiny title of CIO. He proposes and implements the IT strategy of the company.&#xA;He intervenes at different levels in the management and optimization of the company’s information system.&#xA;This encompasses hardware and software infrastructures, information architecture, business tools, dedicated internal or external human resources, and often old technology.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Select An Agile Software Development Partner</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/select-an-agile-software-development-partner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/select-an-agile-software-development-partner/</guid>
      <description>It is not unusual for businesses to turn to third-party companies when they want help to achieve their goals without increasing internal overhead.&#xA;This type of outsourcing is especially common for projects that require tremendous amounts of effort or specific skill sets [1].&#xA;Time constraints are often a supplemental driving factor.&#xA;Partnering up with another business to help meet your needs is a viable and widespread solution [2]. It often makes sense for businesses trying to tackle a massive software development project while focusing on the current needs of their clients.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
