<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tangly Components – 2023</title>
    <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2023 on tangly Components</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Select An Agile Software Development Partner</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/select-an-agile-software-development-partner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/select-an-agile-software-development-partner/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;div class=&#34;sect1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;_select_an_agile_software_development_partner&#34;&gt;Select An Agile Software Development Partner&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sectionbody&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;imageblock left&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;../pics/2023-01-01-head.png&#34; alt=&#34;2023 01 01 head&#34; width=&#34;420&#34; height=&#34;360&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not unusual for businesses to turn to third-party companies when they want help to achieve their goals without increasing internal overhead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This type of outsourcing is especially common for projects that require tremendous amounts of effort or specific skill sets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time constraints are often a supplemental driving factor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Partnering up with another business to help meet your needs is a viable and widespread solution.
It often makes sense for businesses trying to tackle a massive software development project while focusing on the current needs of their clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_evaluation&#34;&gt;Evaluation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A professional and planned approach greatly improves the odds of success for the partnership:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;imageblock text-center&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;../pics/2023-01-01-evaluation-approach.png&#34; alt=&#34;2023 01 01 evaluation approach&#34; width=&#34;480&#34; height=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;dlist&#34;&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt class=&#34;hdlist1&#34;&gt;Identify Decision Criteria&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decide on your internal team, which help with making and supporting the decision.
Put together a &lt;em&gt;must-have&lt;/em&gt; checklist for the capabilities required from a software solution company.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research different approaches and methodologies to discuss with your potential business partner.
For instance, will you use Agile and should your partner need to practice it as well?
Should you emphasize corporate governance or technology agility?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about the services your business will need in the next few years.
Will you require an entire development team, including help with product support?&lt;br/&gt;
Consider the types of roles required to build your solution and note those you can fulfill with your internal staff.
Which positions will you need to fill with experts or dedicated people provided by your new partner?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt class=&#34;hdlist1&#34;&gt;Evaluate Candidates&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, you want to choose a partner with the right experience to help you achieve your goals&lt;a href=&#34;#evaluate-cv&#34;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;.
Avoid choosing a company just because they work with trendy technologies or because they list tons of services on their website.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The length of time they have been in business can be important.
The length of time they have worked with their own clients can be more telling of the level of expertise they provide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt class=&#34;hdlist1&#34;&gt;Evaluate Costs, Processes and Tools&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may be tempted to select the lowest cost option but be cautious.
The software company with the lowest bid might not be the most cost-effective.
You risk choosing a partner that will go fast but make mistakes, or complete chunks of the work and then need to redo them to match your standards.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not risk quality and reputation for a good price.
Ask about change orders.
Many companies will underbid a project and later add on new charges throughout the project.
It results a dramatic increase in the overall cost of development.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is true that aspects of your project will change during the development process.
Experienced software development companies should help you understand how they will handle changes while protecting both your budget and your timeline.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discuss the thorny aspect of scale up and down your external development team.&lt;br/&gt;
What are the consequences for you and your partner?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt class=&#34;hdlist1&#34;&gt;Consider the Location&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where will you want your external development partner to be &lt;a href=&#34;#agile-near-shore&#34;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it is important that they can integrate with your team and frequently work onsite, you might want to only look at local software companies.
Evaluate travel time and not the distance to your partner offices.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are open to working remotely with an onshore company, hold early conversations using the potential conferencing, documentation and chat systems.
You want to ensure your development team can provide help by video as much is lost in exclusively email team communications.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not forget to account for travel in your budget if you shall expect it from your software development team.
If you’re thinking of offshoring the work, be sure you consider how you will handle the difference in time zones and communication styles.
Many companies offer low-cost solutions that include working with offshore teams to handle services like the help desk, product support, and simple development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt class=&#34;hdlist1&#34;&gt;Start Searching&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not forget to keep track of your search as you go.
Create a document that records potential companies, their attributes, who you are talked to, what you’ve learned, and any decisions you’ve made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt class=&#34;hdlist1&#34;&gt;Ask Tough Questions&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn what challenges they have faced with previous clients and what they did to overcome them.
If there is something you are particularly worried about, ask about their experience dealing with your prospective challenges to helping their other clients with similar solutions in the past&lt;a href=&#34;#detecting-agile-bullshit&#34;&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt;.
Ask about their best clients, and the ones that did not stick around.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be sure they have clearly outlined what you can expect from working with their team, how you will measure progress, and how they help define success.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be wary of any potential development partner that struggles to answer these questions or does not provide stories of failure or follow them up with concrete ways they’ve adapted to ensure future success for their clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_evaluation_criteria&#34;&gt;Evaluation Criteria&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You shall implement a clear and founded evaluation approach:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;olist arabic&#34;&gt;
&lt;ol class=&#34;arabic&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research, learn, classify.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pick agile and DevOps as a development mantra [&lt;a href=&#34;#clean-agile&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;#agile-sw-development&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;#accelerate&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;#continuous-delivery-pipelines&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Characterize why you need a software development partner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shortlist the companies you can find to be promising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assess the company experience in your industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evaluate the adaptability of your potential partner to your future needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about cultural compatibility and communications skills [&lt;a href=&#34;#management-30&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;#future-of-management&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about time zone differences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check for technologies and knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See how cost-effective they work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider and evaluate the future of your relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meet the employees that will be working with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_checklist&#34;&gt;Checklist&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here our checklist we use to discuss a potential partnership:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;_hosting_and_operations&#34;&gt;Hosting and Operations&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;imageblock left&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;../pics/2023-01-01-checklist.png&#34; alt=&#34;2023 01 01 checklist&#34; width=&#34;480&#34; height=&#34;360&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;ulist&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How and where are the servers hosted?
Self-hosted or external providers have an impact on the applicable legal context.
Update policy and monitoring shall be compatible with corporate governance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where are the server instances physically located?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Backup and restore policy including location of backup and how they are protected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DevOps aspects: monitoring, alarming, logging, audit logs, security policy.
Is the deployment on the various staging areas automated?
How is the process of deploying a new version?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is the process of updating a productive application when security alarms are issued?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Document your decisions with a formal SLA document.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;_software_development&#34;&gt;Software Development&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;ulist&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where are the team members located?
Are they collocated, in the same area, in the same timezone, distributed over multiple timezones?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which training or certification do they have in the technical stack, programming languages and used tools?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which training or certification do they have in agile and Scrum approaches &lt;a href=&#34;#scrum-master&#34;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;#product-owner&#34;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;#developer&#34;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which training or certification do the senior developers and architects have to perform their work?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which languages are the team members proficient in?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which approaches are used for source code management?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where are the source artifacts stored?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can our collaborators have read access to all artifacts under source code management?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;_governance_and_methods&#34;&gt;Governance and Methods&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;ulist&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which approaches are used for insuring the quality of the written source code?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is the technical documentation such as installation scripts, design decisions, component documents written and managed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could you provide your coding guidelines and documentation guidelines?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are modern approaches such as domain-driven design, unit testing, acceptance testing, continuous integration, continuous delivery in place?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can involved people have read-access to all artifacts?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you trace requirements to deliver versions of the product?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you upgrade an application to a newer version of the technology stack or newer libraries?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which approaches do you use to continuously improve?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;_build_partnership&#34;&gt;Build Partnership&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;ulist&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is your understanding of a partnership?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How would you like to start the partnership between your company and ours?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_lessons_learnt&#34;&gt;Lessons Learnt&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Respect your partner [&lt;a href=&#34;#lead-with-respect&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;#leading-quietly&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;].
You will work together for years.
Both parties shall be interested in improving the delivered solutions and increasing product success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Challenge yourself and your partner to improve the quality and efficiency of delivering digital solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All involved companies and people shall harvest the fruits of success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agile approaches are the process for developing software products in the twenty-first century.
Your organizations shall be proficient with agile, lean approaches.
These frameworks are the most successful approaches for software product development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_links&#34;&gt;Links&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;ulist bibliography&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;bibliography&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;technical-interviews&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[1] &lt;a href=&#34;../../2023/technical-interviews&#34;&gt;Technical Interviews&lt;/a&gt;
Marcel Baumann. 2023&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;agile-near-shore&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[2] &lt;a href=&#34;../../2022/agile-and-nearshore-development/&#34;&gt;Agile and Nearshore Development&lt;/a&gt;
Marcel Baumann. 2022&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;evaluate-cv&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[3] &lt;a href=&#34;../../2022/evaluate-technical-cvs/&#34;&gt;Evaluate Technical CVs&lt;/a&gt;.
Marcel Baumann. 2022&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;scrum-master&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[4] &lt;a href=&#34;../../2021/scrum-master-formation/&#34;&gt;Scrum Master Formation&lt;/a&gt;.
Marcel Baumann. 2021&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;product-owner&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[5] &lt;a href=&#34;../../2021/product-owner-formation/&#34;&gt;Product Owner Formation&lt;/a&gt;.
Marcel Baumann. 2021&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;developer&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[6] &lt;a href=&#34;../../2021/scrum-developer-formation/&#34;&gt;Scrum Developer Formation&lt;/a&gt;.
Marcel Baumann. 2021&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;detecting-agile-bullshit&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[7] &lt;a href=&#34;../../2019/detecting-agile-bullshit/&#34;&gt;Detecting Agile Bullshit&lt;/a&gt;.
Marcel Baumann. 2019&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;clean-agile&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[1] R. C. Martin, &lt;em&gt;Clean Agile&lt;/em&gt;. Prentice Hall, 2020 [Online]. Available: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/dp/0135781868&#34; class=&#34;bare&#34;&gt;https://www.amazon.com/dp/0135781868&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;agile-sw-development&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[2] A. Cockburn, &lt;em&gt;Agile Software Development&lt;/em&gt;, Second. Addison-Wesley Professional, 2006 [Online]. Available: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/dp/0321482751&#34; class=&#34;bare&#34;&gt;https://www.amazon.com/dp/0321482751&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;accelerate&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[3] N. Forsgren, J. Humble, and G. Kim, &lt;em&gt;Accelerate: The Science of Lean Software and DevOps&lt;/em&gt;. IT Revolution Press [Online]. Available: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07B9F83WM&#34; class=&#34;bare&#34;&gt;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07B9F83WM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;continuous-delivery-pipelines&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[4] D. Farley, &lt;em&gt;Continuous Delivery Pipelines&lt;/em&gt;. 2021 [Online]. Available: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B096YGZVZ9&#34; class=&#34;bare&#34;&gt;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B096YGZVZ9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;management-30&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[5] J. Appelo, &lt;em&gt;Management 3.0&lt;/em&gt;. Addison-Wesley, 2011 [Online]. Available: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/dp/0321712471&#34; class=&#34;bare&#34;&gt;https://www.amazon.com/dp/0321712471&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;future-of-management&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[6] H. Hamel and B. Breen, &lt;em&gt;The Future of Management&lt;/em&gt;. Harvard Business Review Press, 2007 [Online]. Available: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/dp/1422102505&#34; class=&#34;bare&#34;&gt;https://www.amazon.com/dp/1422102505&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;lead-with-respect&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[7] M. Ballé and F. Ballé, &lt;em&gt;Lead with Respect&lt;/em&gt;. Len Publishing, 2014 [Online]. Available: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/dp/1934109479&#34; class=&#34;bare&#34;&gt;https://www.amazon.com/dp/1934109479&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;leading-quietly&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[8] J. Badaracco, &lt;em&gt;Leading Quietly&lt;/em&gt;. Harvard Business School Press, 2002 [Online]. Available: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B005DI8XSK&#34; class=&#34;bare&#34;&gt;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B005DI8XSK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
