<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Commons - Common utility libraries on tangly Components</title>
    <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/commons/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Commons - Common utility libraries on tangly Components</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.tangly.net/docs/commons/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Readme</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/commons/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/commons/readme/</guid>
      <description>Purpose A behavior-driven development library that provides a custom extension based on the JUnit 5 Jupiter Extension Model. This library can be used to create and run stories and behaviors as BDD specification tests.&#xA;The library is a developer-first approach. Developers write acceptance tests to validate the functions they have implemented. The generated report provides a living documentation of the features and allows customers to validate the acceptance criteria.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Release Notes</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/commons/releasesnotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/commons/releasesnotes/</guid>
      <description>Commons Library Change Logs This document provides a high-level view of the changes introduced in the Commons library by release. For a detailed view of what has changed, refer to the repository commits.&#xA;0.2.7 (2024.05.31) Update of library dependencies, update to JDK-21, and modern Gradle approach to build solutions&#xA;0.2.6 (2021-08-31) Update of the dependencies&#xA;0.2.5 (2020-08-31) Initial release of the library</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reference Codes</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/commons/referencecodes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/commons/referencecodes/</guid>
      <description>Reference Codes Design Considerations The application is the sole and exclusive owner of the database instance. Instances can never be changed from another system when the application is running.&#xA;The domain model shall not be tainted with active record interfaces or forced inheritance structure. This decision reflects the hexagon architecture.&#xA;Unique object identifiers are necessary to identify instances outside the Java virtual machine, such as databases, CSV files or JSON files.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
