<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2020 on tangly Components</title>
    <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2020 on tangly Components</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Support Comments for Static Hugo Website</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/support-comments-for-static-hugo-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/support-comments-for-static-hugo-website/</guid>
      <description>There are times in software when you are facing a problem, you find an off-the-shelf solution, and a few lines of code later it just works.&#xA;Today I lived one of those moments.&#xA;The whole configuration of comments and modification of the Docsy theme took around one hour.&#xA;Motivation I wanted to add a comment section to this blog for a while. I was reluctant to implement one myself the classical way, using an external service such as disqus.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advocate Zero Bug Policy in Your Projects!</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/advocate-zero-bug-policy-in-your-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/advocate-zero-bug-policy-in-your-projects/</guid>
      <description>At many customer sites I visit, I see a lot of effort being put into classifying and managing bugs.&#xA;Their bug list may contain more than a thousand items. All are neatly documented with screenshots, ways to reproduce the problem and a severity and impact classification. In the worst case, a specialist has worked hard and estimated the effort to correct each of these bugs.&#xA;A change management board meets every few weeks to decide which bugs have a higher priority and should urgently be fixed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Quest for an Agile Company: Five Years tangly llc</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/the-quest-for-an-agile-company-five-years-tangly-llc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/the-quest-for-an-agile-company-five-years-tangly-llc/</guid>
      <description>An agile company is a business with the ability to quickly adapt to market changes [1].&#xA;tangly is an agile and digital development boutique. We must swiftly react to market changes to survive.&#xA;Agility is woven into our culture and processes.&#xA;Agile organizations must be fast-moving and flexible, have rapid response to unexpected obstacles, lead change, be in touch with customers.&#xA;They have a continuous competitive advantage, and a flat organizational structure for quick communication [2].</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reference Codes</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/reference-codes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/reference-codes/</guid>
      <description>Reference codes are an old concept. They are often used in the relational database schema definition as enumeration values. The database specialists often call them lookup tables.&#xA;Reference codes are dynamic enumeration values. By dynamic, we mean you can add values without recompiling the source code.&#xA;In modern DevOps environments where deployment of a new version is performed in minutes, this advantage is somewhat shallow. We view reference codes more as strongly typed and efficient tags.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating a technical Website with Hugo and Asciidoc</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/creating-a-technical-website-with-hugo-and-asciidoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/creating-a-technical-website-with-hugo-and-asciidoc/</guid>
      <description>I hosted my technical blogs on blogger for years.&#xA;If I correctly remember, I started to use blogger ten years ago. It was a good choice at that time.&#xA;I could easily write blogs and publish them.&#xA;It is a great tool with some drawbacks. Over the years, the deficiencies sting more and more&#xA;The major drawbacks are:&#xA;Their editor is brittle, with limited functionality and unreliable. The generated HTML is not legible and does not support concepts such as micro fragments, meta information or simple functions such as source code highlighting.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The power of Tags and Comments</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/the-power-of-tags-and-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/the-power-of-tags-and-comments/</guid>
      <description>A software architect models customer domains and maps them to excellent software constructs. The solution shall support future customer groups and expand to store additional information.&#xA;Tags, also called labels, provide an informal ontology to classify customer data.&#xA;Tags are extensible and are machine-readable.&#xA;Comments empower users to store relevant unstructured information.&#xA;Comments are only for human beings.&#xA;What are good approaches to provide searchable tags and labels and avoid wild growth of useless records?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Entities, Identifiers, External identifiers and Names</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/entities-identifiers-external-identifiers-and-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/entities-identifiers-external-identifiers-and-names/</guid>
      <description>A software architect models customer domains and maps them to powerful software abstractions [1]. Soon you correlate internal efficient identifiers, meaningful external identifiers, and domain entities.&#xA;You enjoy long conversations with the enterprise data architect and identify the system owning a specific external identifier.&#xA;How do you relate to external systems and communicate with other companies?&#xA;How do you define internal identifiers, which grow with application success?&#xA;How can you bridge the customer world with your software solution?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Journey Implementing Digital Invoices</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/a-journey-implementing-digital-invoices/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/a-journey-implementing-digital-invoices/</guid>
      <description>Our company has the ambition to digitize all our workflows since our inception. We proudly state we never bought a printer or a fax machine. Analog machines should become obsolete in the digital age.&#xA;Companies should be more environment-aware and save some trees. See our blog on A Journey to Be a Digital Company.&#xA;Switzerland finally introduced a digital payment slip. It uses a QR code and still assumes you need to print it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Legacy Systems Refactoring</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/legacy-systems-refactoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/legacy-systems-refactoring/</guid>
      <description>In computer programming and software design, code refactoring is the process of restructuring existing computer code without changing its external behavior.&#xA;Refactoring is intended to improve the design, structure, or implementation of the software (its non-functional attributes), while preserving its functionality.&#xA;Using refactoring, you can take bad design, even chaos software and rework it into well-designed code. Most often, it is cheaper to refactoring a legacy application instead of rewriting it from scratch.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gradle 6.4 Finally Supports Java Modules</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/gradle-6.4-finally-supports-java-modules/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/gradle-6.4-finally-supports-java-modules/</guid>
      <description>Java 9 release introduced the concept of modules within the Java language. Java 9 was released in September 2017.&#xA;Until now, creating Java modules was quite cumbersome and Gradle did only offer limited support through external plugins.&#xA;With the release of Gradle 6.4 in May 2020, software developers can finally easily generate well-behaved Java modules. We had to wait almost three years for native support!&#xA;Support for modules is native in the Java plugin.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Component Design</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/agile-component-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/agile-component-design/</guid>
      <description>You are an experienced programmer. You master your primary technology stack and systematically write clean code.&#xA;Your team recognized your merits and asked you to take ownership of whole packages in the application.&#xA;You are now responsible for creating or modifying a software component in your current application.&#xA;This is a design activity.&#xA;How can you create a good, legible, maintainable component architecture?&#xA;How can you validate your functional and non-functional requirements?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java Records Are Here - Available in JDK 14</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/java-records-are-here-available-in-jdk-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/java-records-are-here-available-in-jdk-14/</guid>
      <description>We need justification not to use immutable objects in our solutions, rather than an affirmative reason to use them. Records provide a first-class means for modeling data-only aggregates. They have been available in Java since the release of JDK 14.&#xA;Records are often seen as syntactic sugar to easily create immutable objects without having to write too much boilerplate code. Records as a clean definition of immutable objects can have a tremendous impact on your component design.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Agile Collaborators Learn</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/how-agile-collaborators-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/how-agile-collaborators-learn/</guid>
      <description>Most products are developed by a team, and these achievements are the fruit of teamwork.&#xA;Software product development is now agile, and most often uses the Scrum approach.&#xA;Just putting a bunch of people together in the same open office will not produce a high performance agile team. Quite a few companies find that out the hard way.&#xA;How can you increase the odds to create an environment where agile teams bloom and perform?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Calibrate Your Agile Approach: Bill of Rights</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/calibrate-your-agile-approach-bill-of-rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/calibrate-your-agile-approach-bill-of-rights/</guid>
      <description>When eXtreme Programming first came out, one expectation it worked hard to set is who gets to make what calls on software projects.&#xA;For example, business has the right to know how long something is going to take and when it can expect things to be done.&#xA;Conversely, developers have the right to know what the priorities are, and to be able to do good work.&#xA;To that end, eXtreme Programming created the Customer and Development Team Bill of Rights.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
