<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tangly OS components on tangly Components</title>
    <link>https://blog.tangly.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tangly OS components on tangly Components</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.tangly.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>OS 001: System Guava Removal</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/adr/os-001-system-guava-removal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/adr/os-001-system-guava-removal/</guid>
      <description>OS-001 Removes usage of Google Guava Library Date: 2018-02-20&#xA;Status Implemented&#xA;Context Guava is an historical effort to provide much-needed functionalities to the Java community. The Java ecosystem evolves quite slowly at the beginning of the millennium. Later stewardship clearly improved with a six-month release schedule approach. Preview and incubator initiatives allowed timely evaluation of new features and idioms in the Java language and ecosystem.&#xA;JDK versions from release 8 often provide better replacement methods for a lot of Guava functions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LED 001</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/adr/led-001-ledger-tag-for-vat-costs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/adr/led-001-ledger-tag-for-vat-costs/</guid>
      <description>LED-001 Use Tag for VAT costs computation Date: 2017-12-01&#xA;Status Discarded: Redesign provides a better solution.&#xA;Context We need to record the VAT components of transactions in our ledger system. The VAT value can be different for each position in a transaction therefore the VAT information shall be defined on each part of a transaction.&#xA;The value of the VAT is computed based on the VAT percentage. The percentage can change over time due to regulatory changes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OS 002: Unit Test Conventions</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/adr/os-002-unit-test-conventions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/adr/os-002-unit-test-conventions/</guid>
      <description>OS-002 Define Unit Test Conventions Date: 2020-06-15&#xA;Status Implemented&#xA;Context Some libraries need to create files on a file system. For example, you want to generate human-readable paper invoices.&#xA;Decision We recommend the following conventions when writing unit tests which need to create files. Use Google Java in memory file system Jimfs. Additional file systems can only be used in Java if all operations are performed through Path objects. Path objects have a reference to the file system; File objects always referenced the default file system.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PRJ 001</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/adr/prj-001-project-tag-for-project-costs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/adr/prj-001-project-tag-for-project-costs/</guid>
      <description>PRJ-001 Use Tag for product costs computation Date: 2017-12-01&#xA;Status Implemented&#xA;Context We would like to compute earnings and costs on per product base. Each transaction entry should support tags to identify the associated projects or departments. The tag approach supports multiple consolidation of an orthogonal cost structure.&#xA;Decision We will support tags at the transaction entry. The tags are a triplet [namespace:]name[=value] format. We recommend the namespace &amp;#34;fin&amp;#34;, the name &amp;#34;segment&amp;#34;, and a text identifier has value.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OS 003: Use Modern Java Constructs</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/adr/os-003-use-modern-java-constructs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/adr/os-003-use-modern-java-constructs/</guid>
      <description>OS-003 Remove usage of Google Guava Library Date: 2020-01-01&#xA;Status Implemented&#xA;Context JDK is released every six months to all Java developers. The latest approach is to release a long-term supported version every two years.&#xA;Better approaches support clean code, less verbose source code and reduce programming [5] [2]. These constructs shall be used in our modules as soon as they are released to the developers.&#xA;The advantage is better integration, always synchronized with the current release of the JDK and no incompatibilities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OS 004: Publish Technical Documentation Through Static Website</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/adr/os-004-publish-technical-documentation-through-static-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/adr/os-004-publish-technical-documentation-through-static-website/</guid>
      <description>OS-004 Publish Technical Documentation Through Static Website Date: 2020-01-01&#xA;Status Implemented&#xA;Context Legible, well-structured and up-to-date technical documentation of released open source components is a service to all our users. Due to the small size of our team, we want a straight forward tool chain to generate the website. In the future, we could move our product to another hosting platform. The solution should be built on a standard to minimize porting overhead.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OS 005: Publish Maven Central Artifacts</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/adr/os-005-publish-maven-central-artifact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/adr/os-005-publish-maven-central-artifact/</guid>
      <description>OS-005 Publish Artifacts on Public Java Components Repository Date: 2019-05-01&#xA;Status Implemented&#xA;Links Supersede: FSM-0002&#xA;Context The tangly open source libraries are mature enough to be used in public commercial and academic projects.&#xA;The libraries were used in internal projects and refined to fulfill these requirements. More customers will validate the usefulness of the library and identify extensions for further releases.&#xA;We want to provide a standard and well-known approach for our customers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OS 006: Dependency Injection with Guice</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/adr/os-006-dependency-injection-guice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/adr/os-006-dependency-injection-guice/</guid>
      <description>OS-006 Dependency Injection with Guice Date: 2018-02-20&#xA;Status Implemented&#xA;Context The modules provided as tangly open source components are used in more complex applications.&#xA;These applications often use dependency injection frameworks to construct and initialize their instances. Dependency injection is a technique in which an object receives other objects that it depends on, called dependencies.&#xA;Typically, the receiving object is called a client. The passed-in injected object is called a service.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OS 007: Persistence with MicroStream</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/adr/os-007-persistence-microstream/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/adr/os-007-persistence-microstream/</guid>
      <description>OS-007: Persistence with MicroStream Date: 2020-11-13&#xA;Status Implemented&#xA;Context The modules provided as tangly open source components are used in more complex applications. These applications require a reliable and performant persistence approach for their data.&#xA;In Java, everything is an object. In contrast, all databases come with their own specific data structure that is incompatible with Java objects.&#xA;This is called impedance mismatch.&#xA;As a consequence, a mapping is required, which means all data must be converted behind the scenes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OS 008: Use log4j2 as default logging framework</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/adr/os-008-use-log4j2-as-default-logger/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/adr/os-008-use-log4j2-as-default-logger/</guid>
      <description>OS-008 Use log4j2 as default logging framework Date: 2021-06-15&#xA;Status Implemented&#xA;Context The logging library slf4j seems to be a dead project for at least one year. The last commit in the GitHub slf4j repository was performed two years ago. Version 2.0 of the library is an alpha release on Maven Central dating back to October 2019.&#xA;The apache project log4j has made tremendous progress with the creation of the log4j2 library.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OS 009: Use HSQLDB as an SQL DB</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/adr/os-009-use-hsqldb-as-sql-store/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/adr/os-009-use-hsqldb-as-sql-store/</guid>
      <description>OS-009 Uses HSQLDB as an SQL store Date: 2022-01-01&#xA;Status Implemented&#xA;Context Applications regularly need to store information in a persistent store. A proven approach is to use an SQL database solution for such activities. The Java ecosystem supports a relational database with libraries.&#xA;The JPA approach provides an object relational mapper. The JOOQL approach has a genuine mapping of SQL statements to type verified Java expressions.&#xA;Decision The HSQLDB SQL database java solution is the preferred choice when an application needs to store data in a relational store.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OS 010: Archive Data using TSV and JSON</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/adr/os-010-archive-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/adr/os-010-archive-data/</guid>
      <description>OS-010 Archive Data using TSV and JSON Date: 2022-01-01&#xA;Status Implemented&#xA;Context Contrary to XML or JSON, TSV is perfectly suited to represent records with the least possible overhead. There are a lot of tools, like spreadsheet editors, which can read and modify TSV files. The file’s size is at the possible minimum, and the performance of the converter is significantly better than with the other formats.&#xA;Decision TSV is preferred to import data into the application or export information from the solution.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OS 011: Vaadin User Interface</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/adr/os-011-vaadin-as-user-interface/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/adr/os-011-vaadin-as-user-interface/</guid>
      <description>OS-011 Vaadin User Interface Date: 2022-01-01&#xA;Status Implemented&#xA;Context Our primary and almost exclusive technical stack is Modern Java.&#xA;A major weakness of the Java ecosystem is the user interface aspects. Swing is old and no more actively supported by Oracle or other major players. JavaFX has a small active community. The platform never had a huge acceptance.&#xA;We could use various JavaScript frameworks to realize our user interfaces. The drawback is supporting an additional technology stack.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FSM tests</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/fsm/examples/fsm-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/fsm/examples/fsm-tests/</guid>
      <description>Finite State Machines Below different formats to document automatically a finite state machine description.&#xA;The nicest diagrams are often produced through PlantUML. Sometimes you must tinker with the declaration order of the state to improve the layout result.&#xA;Finite State Machine bbv fsm-bbv States Name Context Description Final Initial Composite Entry Action Exit Action Root&#xA;-&#xA;true&#xA;true&#xA;true&#xA;-&#xA;-&#xA;Off&#xA;Root&#xA;false&#xA;true&#xA;false&#xA;Entry action of Off state</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction and Goals</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/01-introduction-and-goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/01-introduction-and-goals/</guid>
      <description>Introduction and Goals Application Goals The application is an application of modern software engineering principles.&#xA;The essential features are used to implement all acquisition, project management and financial process of an agile software consulting company.&#xA;The smoke test is to run the tangly processes on the ERP solution.&#xA;User Journey Leads After meeting a prospect at a conference, I create a lead. I follow up with the lead and add the information in the text of the lead.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Readme</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/apps/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/apps/readme/</guid>
      <description>Purpose The library provides the abstractions to create a Vaadin user interface with multiple bounded domains. The application can optionally declares ports to provide a REST interface for selected bounded domains.&#xA;Download and Documentation You need to add JUnit 5 dependencies before using this library. If you are using Maven or Gradle, add the following dependency after declaring the JUnit 5 dependency. We recommend using assertJ assertion library to write more legible conditions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Readme</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/bdd/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/bdd/readme/</guid>
      <description>Purpose A behavior-driven development library that provides a custom extension based on the JUnit 5 Jupiter Extension Model. This library can be used to create and run stories and behaviors as BDD specification tests.&#xA;The library is a developer-first approach. Developers write acceptance tests to validate the functions they have implemented. The generated report provides a living documentation of the features and allows customers to validate the acceptance criteria.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Readme</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/commons/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/commons/readme/</guid>
      <description>Purpose A behavior-driven development library that provides a custom extension based on the JUnit 5 Jupiter Extension Model. This library can be used to create and run stories and behaviors as BDD specification tests.&#xA;The library is a developer-first approach. Developers write acceptance tests to validate the functions they have implemented. The generated report provides a living documentation of the features and allows customers to validate the acceptance criteria.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Readme</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/core/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/core/readme/</guid>
      <description>Purpose The tangly core component provides a key abstraction for domain-driven development approach and entities with tags and comments. It requires Java 21 LTS or higher.&#xA;Download and Documentation The library can be included in Maven as&#xA;&amp;lt;dependency&amp;gt; &amp;lt;groupId&amp;gt;net.tangly&amp;lt;/groupId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;artifactId&amp;gt;core&amp;lt;/artifactId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;version&amp;gt;0.2.8&amp;lt;/version&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/dependency&amp;gt; The library can be included in Gradle as&#xA;implementation &amp;#34;net.tangly:core:0.2.8&amp;#34; The documentation can be found under Core.&#xA;Awesome Sponsors and Developers Corporate sponsors are&#xA;tangly llc&#xA;Individual developers are</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Readme</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/dev/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/dev/readme/</guid>
      <description>Purpose Download and Documentation The library can be included in Maven as&#xA;&amp;lt;dependency&amp;gt; &amp;lt;groupId&amp;gt;net.tangly&amp;lt;/groupId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;artifactId&amp;gt;dev&amp;lt;/artifactId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;version&amp;gt;0.2.8&amp;lt;/version&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/dependency&amp;gt; The library can be included in Gradle as&#xA;implementation &amp;#34;net.tangly:dev:0.2.8&amp;#34; The documentation can be found under Commons documentation&#xA;For any further questions, you can use the forum tangly-Discussions.&#xA;Awesome Sponsors and Developers Corporate sponsors are&#xA;tangly llc&#xA;Individual developers are&#xA;Marcel Baumann&#xA;Alexandra Junghans</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Readme</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/agile/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/agile/readme/</guid>
      <description>Purpose The tangly erp agile bounded domain component provides regular business model abstractions for business applications written in Java. The component is using records and requires Java 21 LTS or higher.&#xA;Try it out.&#xA;Download and Documentation The library can be included in Maven as&#xA;&amp;lt;dependency&amp;gt; &amp;lt;groupId&amp;gt;net.tangly.erp&amp;lt;/groupId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;artifactId&amp;gt;collaborators&amp;lt;/artifactId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;version&amp;gt;0.2.8&amp;lt;/version&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/dependency&amp;gt; Download and Documentation The library can be included in Gradle as&#xA;implementation &amp;#34;net.tangly.erp:collaborators:0.2.8&amp;#34; The documentation can be found under Business documentation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Readme</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/collaborators/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/collaborators/readme/</guid>
      <description>Purpose The tangly erp collaborators bounded domain component provides regular business model abstractions for business applications written in Java. The component is using records and requires Java 21 LTS or higher.&#xA;Try it out.&#xA;Download and Documentation The library can be included in Maven as&#xA;&amp;lt;dependency&amp;gt; &amp;lt;groupId&amp;gt;net.tangly.erp&amp;lt;/groupId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;artifactId&amp;gt;collaborators&amp;lt;/artifactId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;version&amp;gt;0.2.8&amp;lt;/version&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/dependency&amp;gt; The library can be included in Gradle as&#xA;implementation &amp;#34;net.tangly.erp:collaborators:0.2.8&amp;#34; The documentation can be found under {-url}/domains/collaborators/[Business documentation].&#xA;For any further questions, you can use the forum tangly-Discussions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Readme</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/crm/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/crm/readme/</guid>
      <description>Purpose The tangly erp crm bounded domain component provides regular business model abstractions for business applications written in Java. The component is using records and requires Java 21 LTS or higher.&#xA;Try it out.&#xA;Download and Documentation The library can be included in Maven as&#xA;&amp;lt;dependency&amp;gt; &amp;lt;groupId&amp;gt;net.tangly.erp&amp;lt;/groupId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;artifactId&amp;gt;crm&amp;lt;/artifactId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;version&amp;gt;0.2.8&amp;lt;/version&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/dependency&amp;gt; The library can be included in Gradle as&#xA;implementation &amp;#34;net.tangly.erp:crm:0.2.8&amp;#34; The documentation can be found under Business documentation.&#xA;For any further questions, you can use the forum tangly-Discussions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Readme</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/invoices/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/invoices/readme/</guid>
      <description>Purpose The tangly erp invoices bounded domain component provides regular business model abstractions for business applications written in Java. The component is using records and requires Java 21 LTS or higher.&#xA;Try it out.&#xA;Download and Documentation The library can be included in Maven as&#xA;&amp;lt;dependency&amp;gt; &amp;lt;groupId&amp;gt;net.tangly.erp&amp;lt;/groupId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;artifactId&amp;gt;invoices&amp;lt;/artifactId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;version&amp;gt;0.2.8&amp;lt;/version&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/dependency&amp;gt; The library can be included in Gradle as&#xA;implementation &amp;#34;net.tangly.erp:invoices:0.2.8&amp;#34; The documentation can be found under Business documentation.&#xA;Awesome Sponsors and Developers Corporate sponsors are</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Readme</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/ledger/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/ledger/readme/</guid>
      <description>Purpose The tangly erp crm bounded domain component provides regular business model abstractions for business applications written in Java. The component is using records and requires Java 21 LTS or higher.&#xA;Try it out.&#xA;Download and Documentation The library can be included in Maven as&#xA;&amp;lt;dependency&amp;gt; &amp;lt;groupId&amp;gt;net.tangly.erp&amp;lt;/groupId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;artifactId&amp;gt;crm&amp;lt;/artifactId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;version&amp;gt;0.2.8&amp;lt;/version&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/dependency&amp;gt; The library can be included in Gradle as&#xA;implementation &amp;#34;net.tangly.erp:crm:0.2.8&amp;#34; The documentation can be found under Business documentation.&#xA;Awesome Sponsors and Developers Corporate sponsors are</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Readme</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/products/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/products/readme/</guid>
      <description>Purpose The tangly erp products bounded domain component provides regular business model abstractions for business applications written in Java. The component is using records and requires Java 21 LTS or higher.&#xA;Try it out.&#xA;Download and Documentation The library can be included in Maven as&#xA;&amp;lt;dependency&amp;gt; &amp;lt;groupId&amp;gt;net.tangly.erp&amp;lt;/groupId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;artifactId&amp;gt;products&amp;lt;/artifactId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;version&amp;gt;0.2.8&amp;lt;/version&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/dependency&amp;gt; The library can be included in Gradle as&#xA;implementation &amp;#34;net.tangly.erp:products:0.2.8&amp;#34; The documentation can be found under Business documentation.&#xA;Awesome Sponsors and Developers Corporate sponsors are</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Readme</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/ui/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/ui/readme/</guid>
      <description>Purpose The tangly erp ui bounded domain component provides regular business model abstractions for business applications written in Java. The component is using records and requires Java 21 LTS or higher.&#xA;Try it out.&#xA;Download and Documentation Include the library in your Maven configuration as:&#xA;&amp;lt;dependency&amp;gt; &amp;lt;groupId&amp;gt;net.tangly.erp&amp;lt;/groupId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;artifactId&amp;gt;ui&amp;lt;/artifactId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;version&amp;gt;0.2.8&amp;lt;/version&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/dependency&amp;gt; Include the library in your Gradle configuration as:&#xA;implementation &amp;#34;net.tangly.erp:ui:0.2.8&amp;#34; The documentation can be found under Business documentation.&#xA;For any further questions, you can use the forum tangly-Discussions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Readme</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/fsm/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/fsm/readme/</guid>
      <description>Purpose The tangly fsm is a finite state machine library. You can use it in productive projects and academic assignments. The component is using records and requires Java 21 LTS or higher.&#xA;The library provides&#xA;Definition of hierarchical state machine descriptions. The machine states and transitions are generic classes. You provide an enumeration for the set of states, and an enumeration for the set of events triggering the machine. The builder pattern is used to create complex state machine definition declaratively,</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Readme</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/gleam/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/gleam/readme/</guid>
      <description>Purpose Download and Documentation The library can be included in Maven as&#xA;&amp;lt;dependency&amp;gt; &amp;lt;groupId&amp;gt;net.tangly&amp;lt;/groupId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;artifactId&amp;gt;gleam&amp;lt;/artifactId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;version&amp;gt;0.2.8&amp;lt;/version&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/dependency&amp;gt; The library can be included in Gradle as&#xA;implementation &amp;#34;net.tangly:gleam:0.2.8&amp;#34; The documentation can be found under Commons documentation.&#xA;Awesome Sponsors and Developers Corporate sponsors are&#xA;tangly llc&#xA;Individual developers are&#xA;Marcel Baumann&#xA;Alexandra Junghans</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Readme</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/ui/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/ui/readme/</guid>
      <description>Purpose The tangly ui erp component provides a Vaadin based user interfaces for enterprise applications written in Java. The component is using records and requires Java 21 LTS or higher.&#xA;Currently, we are moving at the bleeding edge of our components. Therefore, to build and execute the ERP application, please do:&#xA;mvn jetty:run The initial username and password are &amp;#39;administrator&amp;#39; and &amp;#39;aeon&amp;#39;.&#xA;The file application.properties in …/main/resources directory tailors the configuration of the application, mainly the location of data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Architecture</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/expertise/expertise-technical/agile-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/expertise/expertise-technical/agile-architecture/</guid>
      <description>Evolvable Architectures Every product is unique and needs a tailored architecture. The goal is to identify an architecture that evolves with new requirements and constraints. Constraints are new technologies, regulatory changes or improvements in reliability and scalability.&#xA;Transform the architecture to a more modular solution Validate continuously the design against the requirements Identify and automate fitness functions to verify constraints Move from a monolithic to a service architecture Domain-Driven Development Agile cross-functional teams implement and deliver features to the customers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Organizations</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/expertise/expertise-agile/agile-organizations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/expertise/expertise-agile/agile-organizations/</guid>
      <description>Digital Delivery Our Scrum Masters and agile coaches help organizations develop a foundation of Scrum good practices and grow the internal expertise needed to become a true learning organization.&#xA;Teach Scrum, Kanban on the job Formulate a vision, a roadmap, a release plan and act on Create a team contract and definition of done DoD Continuously improve team effectiveness Growth your Scrum masters and product owners to high performers Agile Techniques Expertly trained agile and Scrum teams are critical to your company’s business agility.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Release Notes</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/ui/releasesnotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/ui/releasesnotes/</guid>
      <description>Commons UI Library Change Logs This document provides a high-level view of the changes introduced in the Common UI library by release. For a detailed view of what has changed, refer to the repository commits.&#xA;0.2.8 (2024-09-30) Update of library dependencies, update to JDK-22, and modern Gradle approach to build solutions.&#xA;Comments have an automatic timestamp and the author name is the logged-in user.&#xA;0.2.7 (2024-05-31) Update of library dependencies, update to JDK-21, and modern Gradle approach to build solutions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Architecture</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/agile-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/agile-architecture/</guid>
      <description>Agile Architecture Principles You are applying the agile and lean approach to your software products development. Your teams use Scrum Guide or Kanban to deliver running software at least every two weeks. The product launch is a tremendous success. You will likely sell the solution for the next ten years.&#xA;How shall you define and nurture the software architecture of your product and insure a long living and high-quality solution?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Architecture Constraints</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/02-architecture-constraints/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/02-architecture-constraints/</guid>
      <description>Architecture Constraints The programming language is Java. The version is the current released JDK.&#xA;Embedded programming language is C++. The version is the current released ISO standard.&#xA;Th user interface for all Java applications is build with Vaadin. The version is the current released version available on Maven Central.&#xA;The documentation language is English US.&#xA;Exchange of data is over TSV files.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Release Notes</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/apps/releasesnotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/apps/releasesnotes/</guid>
      <description>Apps Library Changes Logs This document provides a high-level view of the changes introduced in the apps library by release. For a detailed view of what has changed, refer to the repository commits.&#xA;0.2.8 (2024-09-30) Uer management, authorization and authentication is now supported. The list of users and active users of a domain can be retrieved.&#xA;Tenancy support is available.&#xA;0.2.7 (2024-05-31) Initial release of the library</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Release Notes</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/bdd/releasesnotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/bdd/releasesnotes/</guid>
      <description>BDD Library Change Logs This document provides a high-level view of the changes introduced in the BDD library by release. For a detailed view of what has changed, refer to the repository commits.&#xA;0.2.8 (2024-09-30) 0.2.7 (2024-05-31) Update of library dependencies, update to JDK-21, and modern Gradle approach to build solutions.&#xA;0.2.6 (2021-08-31) Update of the dependencies&#xA;0.2.5 (2020-08-31) Update of the dependencies&#xA;0.2.4 (2020-06-30) BDD library is now a regular Java 9 module (thanks to the new module support in Gradle 6.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Release Notes</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/commons/releasesnotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/commons/releasesnotes/</guid>
      <description>Commons Library Change Logs This document provides a high-level view of the changes introduced in the Commons library by release. For a detailed view of what has changed, refer to the repository commits.&#xA;0.2.8 (2024-09-30) 0.2.7 (2024-05-31) Update of library dependencies, update to JDK-21, and modern Gradle approach to build solutions&#xA;0.2.6 (2021-08-31) Update of the dependencies&#xA;0.2.5 (2020-08-31) Initial release of the library</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Release Notes</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/core/releasesnotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/core/releasesnotes/</guid>
      <description>Core Library Change Logs This document provides a high-level view of the changes introduced in the Core library by release. For a detailed view of what has changed, refer to the repository commits.&#xA;0.2.8 (2024-09-30) 0.2.7 (2024-05-31) Update of library dependencies, update to JDK-21, and modern Gradle approach to build solutions.&#xA;0.2.6 (2021-08-31) Initial release of the library</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Release Notes</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/dev/releasesnotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/dev/releasesnotes/</guid>
      <description>DEV Library Change Logs This document provides a high-level view of the changes introduced in the DEV library by release. For a detailed view of what has changed, refer to the repository commits.&#xA;0.2.8 (2024-09-30) 0.2.7 (2024-05-31) Update of library dependencies, update to JDK-21, and modern Gradle approach to build solutions.&#xA;0.2.6 (2021-08-31) Update of the dependencies&#xA;0.2.5 (2020-08-31) Initial release of the library</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Release Notes</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/agile/releasesnotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/agile/releasesnotes/</guid>
      <description>Agile Change Logs This document provides a high-level view of the changes introduced in the agile ERP library by release. For a detailed view of what has changed, refer to the repository commits.&#xA;0.2.8 (2024-09-30) 0.2.7 (2024-05-31) Update of library dependencies, update to JDK-20, and modern Gradle approach to build solutions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Release Notes</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/collaborators/releasesnotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/collaborators/releasesnotes/</guid>
      <description>ERP Collaborators Library Change Logs This document provides a high-level view of the changes introduced in the ERP CRM library by release. For a detailed view of what has changed, refer to the repository commits.&#xA;0.2.8 (2024-09-30) 0.2.7 (2024-05-31) Initial release of the library as a DDD bounded domain</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Release Notes</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/crm/releasesnotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/crm/releasesnotes/</guid>
      <description>ERP CRM Library Change Logs This document provides a high-level view of the changes introduced in the ERP CRM library by release. For a detailed view of what has changed, refer to the repository commits.&#xA;0.2.8 (2024-09-30) 0.2.7 (2024-05-31) Update of library dependencies, update to JDK-21, and modern Gradle approach to build solutions.&#xA;Fix: photo of a natural entity is persisted and displayed without distortions.&#xA;Fix: analytics diagrams display correctly upon initial import of data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Release Notes</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/invoices/releasesnotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/invoices/releasesnotes/</guid>
      <description>ERP Invoices Library Change Logs This document provides a high-level view of the changes introduced in the ERP Invoices library by release. For a detailed view of what has changed, refer to the repository commits.&#xA;0.2.8 (2024-09-30) 0.2.7 (2024-05-31) Update of library dependencies, update to JDK-21, and modern Gradle approach to build solutions.&#xA;0.2.6 (2021-08-31) First version of the library packed as a DDD bounded domain&#xA;Requires Java 16 or higher due to extensive usage of records and sealed classes</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Release Notes</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/ledger/releasesnotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/ledger/releasesnotes/</guid>
      <description>ERP Ledger Library Change Logs This document provides a high-level view of the changes introduced in the Ledger CRM library by release. For a detailed view of what has changed, refer to the repository commits.&#xA;0.2.8 (2024-09-30) 0.2.7 (2024-05-31) Update of library dependencies, update to JDK-21, and modern Gradle approach to build solutions.&#xA;0.2.6 (2021-08-31) Initial version of the library packed as a DDD bounded domain.&#xA;Requires Java 16 or higher due to extensive usage of records and sealed classes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Release Notes</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/products/releasesnotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/products/releasesnotes/</guid>
      <description>ERP Products Library Change Logs This document provides a high-level view of the changes introduced in the ERP Products library by release. For a detailed view of what has changed, refer to the repository commits.&#xA;0.2.8 (2024-09-30) 0.2.7 (2024-05-31) Update of library dependencies, update to JDK-21, and modern Gradle approach to build solutions&#xA;Efforts are now stored in YAML files. The library provides a parser to read and write YAML files.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Release Notes</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/ui/releasesnotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/ui/releasesnotes/</guid>
      <description>UI Library Change Logs This document provides a high-level view of the changes introduced in the ERP UI library by release. For a detailed view of what has changed, refer to the repository commits.&#xA;0.2.8 (2024-09-30) 0.2.7 (2024-05-31) Update of library dependencies, update to JDK-21, and modern Gradle approach to build solutions&#xA;0.2.6 (2021-08-31) Initial version of the library packed as a DDD bounded domain&#xA;Requires Java 16 or higher due to extensive usage of records and sealed classes</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Release Notes</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/fsm/releasesnotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/fsm/releasesnotes/</guid>
      <description>FSM Library Change Logs This document provides a high-level view of the changes introduced in the FSM library by release. For a detailed view of what has changed, refer to the repository git commits.&#xA;0.2.8 (2024-09-30) 0.2.7 (2024-05-31) Update of library dependencies, update to JDK-21, and modern Gradle approach to build solutions.&#xA;Added statechart diagram support for smcat and mermaid formats.&#xA;Actor library now uses the standard API FLow implementation and virtual thread executor.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Release Notes</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/gleam/releasesnotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/gleam/releasesnotes/</guid>
      <description>Gleam Library Change Logs This document provides a high-level view of the changes introduced in the Gleam library by release. For a detailed view of what has changed, refer to the repository commits.&#xA;0.2.8 (2024-09-30) 0.2.7 (2024-05-31) Update of library dependencies, update to JDK-21, and modern Gradle approach to build solutions&#xA;0.2.6 (2021-08-31) Update of the dependencies&#xA;0.2.5 (2020-08-31) Initial release of the library&#xA;Framework to generate the TSV representation of business entities</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Products</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/expertise/expertise-agile/agile-products/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/expertise/expertise-agile/agile-products/</guid>
      <description>Effective Product Strategy Developing a successful product is not down to luck or trying hard. Product success starts with making the right strategic decisions.&#xA;Validate product strategy with design thinking Review product performance with lean budgets Set the right priorities and establish a growth mindset Implement your digital transformation with your product portfolio Product Leadership with Scrum The product owner is a product management role. Product management is a complex, multi-faceted discipline that takes time and effort to master.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Software Craftsmanship</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/expertise/expertise-technical/software-craftsmanship/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/expertise/expertise-technical/software-craftsmanship/</guid>
      <description>Agile Technical Coach Improving software design and construction is our passion. The goal is to help you become a more productive developer—and that does not stop at the end of your training and coaching sessions. Your success is important to us.&#xA;Reflect on new solutions to existing challenges Review artefacts from sprint planning and design sessions Periodically retrospect on your progress and challenges Promote team learning with coding dojos, pair programming, design workshops, agile architecture Introduce techniques like static code analysis, TDD, ATDD, zero bug policy Be available to answer questions as they come Design Workshops It is often useful to get an outside perspective.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Good Practices for Enterprise Java Solutions</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/development-good-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/development-good-practices/</guid>
      <description>Good Practices for Enterprise Java Solutions Bounded Domain Development Knowledge Database Todo&#xA;Write FAQ in Asciidoc</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design Conventions</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/design-conventions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/design-conventions/</guid>
      <description>Design Conventions Audit Event Conventions The event field is one of the following values&#xA;import Any entity imported from an external source is audited.&#xA;export Any entity exported to an external source is audited.&#xA;create Each time a file is generated and exported shall be audited. For example, the creation of an invoice document is audited.&#xA;login Login of a user.&#xA;logout Logout of a user.&#xA;The component field has the structure net.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>User Guide UI</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/ui/userguide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/ui/userguide/</guid>
      <description>User Guide Commons Vaadin UI Views Views display a set of instances of an entity. The view provides the regular CRUD operations:&#xA;View details of an entity instance.&#xA;Modify an entity instance. The user can edit all properties of an object in the user interface. All changes are buffered in the user interface components. She can decide to propage the changes to the model or discard them through save or cancel operations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SWAT Lecture</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/learnings/lectures/swat-lecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/learnings/lectures/swat-lecture/</guid>
      <description>SWAT Lecture Introduction The software architecture and techniques SWAT lecture conveys the basics of systematic agile design for a software architecture. The approach is adequate for the problem of (agile architectural thinking) as well as methods of agile quality assurance. Students apply the learnt principles of their semester or private software projects.&#xA;It is particularly suitable for students who are working on a larger software project at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>System Scope and Context</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/03-system-scope-and-context/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/03-system-scope-and-context/</guid>
      <description>System Scope and Context Contents System scope and context - as the name suggests - delimits your system (i.e. your scope) from all its communication partners (neighboring systems and users, i.e. the context of your system). It thereby specifies the external interfaces.&#xA;If necessary, differentiate the business context (domain specific inputs and outputs) from the technical context (channels, protocols, hardware).&#xA;Motivation The domain interfaces and technical interfaces to communication partners are among your system’s most critical aspects.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>User Guide Behavior Driven Design Library</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/bdd/userguidebdd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/bdd/userguidebdd/</guid>
      <description>Ideas Behavior-driven development BDD is an agile software development process that encourages collaboration among developers, quality assurance experts, and customer representatives in a software project. It encourages teams to use conversation and concrete examples to formalize a shared understanding of how the application should behave. It emerged from test-driven development TDD. Behavior-driven development combines the general techniques and principles of TDD with ideas from domain-driven design and object-oriented analysis and design to provide software development and management teams with shared tools and a shared process to collaborate on software development.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>User Guide Finite State Machine</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/fsm/userguidefsm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/fsm/userguidefsm/</guid>
      <description>Features The FSM library aims to provide the following features:&#xA;Easy to use flat state machine for simple use cases. This type of FSM is taught in bachelor engineering courses.&#xA;Hierarchical state machine structure to ease complex state configuration. The hierarchical type of FSM is part of the UML notation.&#xA;Usage of events, transitions, guards and actions. Transition actions, state entry actions, and state exit actions are supported.&#xA;Builder pattern for easy creation of a complete state machine declaration using a fluent approach,</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Components Publication</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/components-publication/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/components-publication/</guid>
      <description>Components Publication Regular Git Repository Update Push the changes to the GitHub repository Open Source Components.&#xA;Verify that the build job in the CI pipeline was successful.&#xA;Push the changes to the GitHub repository. The statistics for developer activities will be automatically updated.&#xA;Continuous Delivery Pipelines See Readme.&#xA;Maven Central Publication The following process is used to publish tangly open source component on Maven Central.&#xA;Publish artifacts of a component with the script uploadToMavenCentral.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Collaborators Design</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/collaborators/collaborators-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/collaborators/collaborators-design/</guid>
      <description>Collaborators Bounded Domain Domain Model Scenario Yearly Legal Salary Form As a collaborator I have a work contract with an organization. The organization provides legal insurances, social insurances and pension funds. The minimal coverage is defined by law in Switzerland. Companies are free to provide additional services.&#xA;I shall receive a yearly legal salary form documenting my salary and paid insurances. The form is a key document for the Swiss tax declaration.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developer Guide UI</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/ui/developerguide/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/ui/developerguide/</guid>
      <description>Developer Guide Commons UI Develop ERP Application Run From Command Line To run quickly from the command-line in development mode:&#xA;./gradlew run (1) 1 Your app will be running on http://localhost:8080. Run From IDE Run ./gradle vaadinPrepareFrontend in the project, to configure Vaadin for npm mode.&#xA;Run/Debug the EmbeddedJetty class as an application (run the _main()- method). The app will use npm to download all javascript libraries (will take a long time) and will start in development mode.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extendable Models</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/extendable-domain-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/extendable-domain-models/</guid>
      <description>Extendable Domain Models - === Introduction&#xA;Identifiers Names Codes Tags Comments Lessons Learnt Future Research Themes To be written&#xA;Links [1] The power of Tags and Comments. Marcel Baumann. 2020&#xA;[1] Reference Codes. Marcel Baumann. 2020&#xA;[1] Meaningful Identifiers. Marcel Baumann. 2021&#xA;[1] Identifiers and Names. Marcel Baumann. 2020</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>User Guide tangly ERP</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/ui/userguideerp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/ui/userguideerp/</guid>
      <description>ERP Introduction The tangly ERP application promotes the various open source components our tangly company develops, supports, and publishes.&#xA;We are a strong supporter of the eat your own dog food approach. The application is used to run daily business and all financial processes of our company. All data since the inception were moved in the application. This approach is ideal for the industrialization and validation of all features.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bounded Domain CRM Model</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/crm/models/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/crm/models/</guid>
      <description>Bounded Domain CRM Context The bounded domain contextCRM implements&#xA;The core domain Customer Relationship Management&#xA;It uses the shared kernel Core providing core abstractions to modeling&#xA;Bounded Domain Workflow The workflows describe the regular activities a service company has with their contacts and customers.&#xA;Table 1. CRM Workflows ID Description CRM-001&#xA;As a salesperson I want to create and modify a legal entity so that I have a record of every organization my company is working with.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bounded Domain Invoice Model</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/invoices/models/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/invoices/models/</guid>
      <description>Invoices Model Concepts Invoices define a business-bounded domain as defined in domain-driven design approach. They are not constrained through external entities such as products, contracts or legal entities. External entities can provide hints to streamline the creation of regular invoices. The invoice article identifier is available as an external identifier to the article bounded domain. Similar identifiers are available for legal entities.&#xA;The currency is defined at the invoice level, meaning all invoice items and subtotals should use the same currency.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PCP Lecture</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/learnings/lectures/pcp-lecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/learnings/lectures/pcp-lecture/</guid>
      <description>PCP Lecture Introduction The programming concepts and paradigms PCP convey the basic for functional programming and modern java programming. The Clojure language [1] is used to teach functional programming approaches. The focus is on immutability, functions as first-class citizens, and parallel programming. We analyze later how far it is possible to use these techniques in the modern Java language.&#xA;Slides and reference literature are in English and published under Slides and Literature.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solution Strategy</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/04-solution-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/04-solution-strategy/</guid>
      <description>Solution Strategy Technical Approach Software Development Modern Java is the preferred programming language for realization.&#xA;Embedded Software Development Modern C++ is the preferred programming language for embedded functionalities. The source code is object-oriented.&#xA;A realtime operating system RTOS provides scheduling and concurrent processing.&#xA;The communication uses asynchronous message passing. Messages are immutable value objects.&#xA;Thread logic is realized as a finite state machine.&#xA;Documentation Approach Follow the recommendations of arc42 approach for document structure and content.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>User Guide Actors</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/fsm/userguideactor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/fsm/userguideactor/</guid>
      <description>User Guide Actors Get Starting A finite state machine actor class is provided to easily create an active class whose behavior is defined through a finite state machine&#xA;class FsmActor&amp;lt;O extends FsmActor&amp;lt;O, S, E&amp;gt;, S extends Enum&amp;lt;S&amp;gt;, E extends Enum&amp;lt;E&amp;gt;&amp;gt; extends Actor&amp;lt;Event&amp;lt;?&amp;gt;, Void&amp;gt; { private static final Logger logger = LoggerFactory.getLogger(); private final StateMachine&amp;lt;O, S, E&amp;gt; fsm; public FsmActor(@Nonnull FsmBuilder&amp;lt;O, S, E&amp;gt; builder, String name) throws SuspendExecution { super(name, new MailboxConfig()); fsm = builder.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>User Guide Gleam</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/gleam/userguide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/gleam/userguide/</guid>
      <description>User Guide Gleam JSON Mapping Strengths The advantages of the Gleam JSON mapping library are:&#xA;Use POJO - Plain Old Java Objects - and do not require Java Bean naming conventions for getters and setters.&#xA;Support immutable record constructs of Java. The field values are retrieved from CSV record in the first step. The record is constructed with values in the second step.&#xA;Support heterogeneous collections and can instantiate the expected instances through a user provided discriminator function.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ERP Design</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/ui/design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/ui/design/</guid>
      <description>ERP Design Context Persistence Folder Structure Files are written in italics font, folders are written in bold font. Examples with content are provided for each file type as test resources. These resources are available in the git repository.&#xA;Entity Abstraction The entity abstraction has five kinds of properties&#xA;Simple Properties are all displayed in a form part of a properties tab for visualization or editing.&#xA;Comments are displayed as a CRUD Grid - Form component part of a comments tab for visualization or editing following CRUD approach.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ERP Ports</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/ledger/userguideports/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/ledger/userguideports/</guid>
      <description>CRM Ports The CRM ports provide a bidirectional interface to persistent file storage.&#xA;CRM entities can be stored to and retrieved from tab separated values TSV files.&#xA;Invoices Ports Invoices are stored to and retrieved from JSON files.&#xA;Ledger Ports To be written&#xA;Ledger Banana Import Handler Importing Ledger Structure The following steps export the information from the banana application:&#xA;Select the accounts tab displaying all the accounts and their structure of the period</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Architecture Code Scene</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/architecture-code-scene/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/architecture-code-scene/</guid>
      <description>Architecture Code Scene Purpose Agile development teams shall manage and diminish their technical debt. We provide instruments to increase the pay-off of refactoring measures. The most relevant source code parts should be refactored first. But how can we identify them?&#xA;Git is the de facto standard for version management systems. Git contains the whole evolution story of our source code. We use these data to identify areas under repetitive change or often needing fixing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Books</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/learnings/books/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/learnings/books/</guid>
      <description>Unknown reference: skilled-facilitator-resoruce Unknown reference: agile-produt-management Agile and Technical Excellence Books Agile J. Hesselberg, Unlocking Agility. Addison-Wesley Professional, 2019 [Online]. Available: https://www.amazon.com/dp/0134542843&#xA;M. Poppendieck and T. Poppendieck, Implementing Lean Software Development. Addison-Wesley Professional, 2006 [Online]. Available: https://www.amazon.com/dp/0321437381&#xA;J. Appelo, Management 3.0. Addison-Wesley, 2011 [Online]. Available: https://www.amazon.com/dp/0321712471&#xA;F. Laloux, Reinventing Organizations. Nelson Parker, 2014 [Online]. Available: https://www.amazon.com/dp/2960133501&#xA;H. Hamel and B. Breen, The Future of Management. Harvard Business Review Press, 2007 [Online].</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bounded Domain Invoice Model</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/ledger/-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/ledger/-models/</guid>
      <description> Ledger Model </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bounded Domain Products Model</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/products/models/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/products/models/</guid>
      <description> Bounded Domain Products Model Efforts Importing Efforts Reporting Efforts </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bounded Domain UI Model</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/ui/models/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/ui/models/</guid>
      <description> Bounded Domain UI Model </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Block View</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/05-building-block-view/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/05-building-block-view/</guid>
      <description>Building Block View A bounded domain is the key building block for a modular monolith architecture approach. The ERP application is consisting of multiple bounded domains.&#xA;The same approach should be used for a distributed microservice architecture.&#xA;Each bounded domain is a self-contained module that encapsulates the business logic and data for a specific domain. Persistence shall be handled per bounded domain. Ideally, the domain model should be designed to be independent of the persistence technology.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Core Models</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/core/models/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/core/models/</guid>
      <description>Core Models Codes Model The abstraction of a reference table or reference codes. A code table is an extensible set of values. You can add values when needed and extend the model with temporal activation if desired. For example, currencies are typical code values with a temporal duration; well-known retired currencies are the European Currency Unit ECU or the German deutsche mark DM. New values can be added without recompiling the application.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design Considerations</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/fsm/design/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/fsm/design/</guid>
      <description>Design Finite State Machine Definitions A person who never made a mistake never tried anything new. — Albert Einstein What is a finite state machine? A Finite State Machine or FSM is an abstract model of deterministic computation, which can be in only one finite state at a specific moment. Finite State Machines are used to model problems in different domains such as AI, games, or application flows. It describes how a program should behave by specifying states and routes between them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reference Codes</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/commons/referencecodes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/commons/referencecodes/</guid>
      <description>Reference Codes Design Considerations The application is the sole and exclusive owner of the database instance. Instances can never be changed from another system when the application is running.&#xA;The domain model shall not be tainted with active record interfaces or forced inheritance structure. This decision reflects the hexagon architecture.&#xA;Unique object identifiers are necessary to identify instances outside the Java virtual machine, such as databases, CSV files or JSON files.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>bdd Report</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/bdd/bdd-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/bdd/bdd-report/</guid>
      <description>Feature: Sell items to customers The customer can buy various items from the store. Upon completion the stock of the store reflects the purchasing action. The store carries black and blue sweaters. The store should refuse to sell more sweaters than it has in stock.&#xA;tags: &amp;#39;Feature Example&amp;#39; &amp;#39;Mandatory&amp;#39;&#xA;Story: Buy Sweater As a store owner I want to update the stock when I am selling sweaters to customers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/learnings/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/learnings/links/</guid>
      <description>Agile and Technical Excellence Links - === Scrum Food For Thoughts Links&#xA;We are continuously looking for fresh approaches and implementing continuous improvements. These sites and blogs are a source of knowledge and experience.&#xA;Scrum Alliance&#xA;Scrum Alliance Blog&#xA;Scrum Alliance Labs videos&#xA;Scrum.org&#xA;Scrum.org Blog&#xA;Scrum Master Reading List Scrum masters shall read these books to achieve proficiency.&#xA;LeSS - extensive documentation on important aspects using Large Scaled Scrum approach -</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Runtime View</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/06-runtime-view/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/06-runtime-view/</guid>
      <description>Runtime View Contents The runtime view describes concrete behavior and interactions of the system’s building blocks in form of scenarios from the following areas:&#xA;important use cases or features: how do building blocks execute them?&#xA;interactions at critical external interfaces: how do building blocks cooperate with users and neighboring systems?&#xA;operation and administration: launch, start-up, stop&#xA;error and exception scenarios&#xA;Remark: The main criterion for the choice of possible scenarios (sequences, workflows) is their architectural relevance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deployment View</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/07-deployment-view/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/07-deployment-view/</guid>
      <description>Deployment View Content The deployment view describes:&#xA;technical infrastructure used to execute your system, with infrastructure elements like geographical locations, environments, computers, processors, channels and net topologies as well as other infrastructure elements and&#xA;mapping of (software) building blocks to that infrastructure elements.&#xA;Often systems are executed in different environments, e.g., development environment, test environment, production environment. In such cases, you should document all relevant environments.&#xA;Especially document a deployment view if your software is executed as a distributed system with more than one computer, processor, server or container or when you design and construct your own hardware processors and chips.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Transformations</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/agile-transformations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/agile-transformations/</guid>
      <description>Agile Transformations Agile transformation is as an act of transforming an organization’s form or nature gradually. The new form is able to thrive in a flexible, collaborative, self-organizing, fast changing environment.&#xA;The Agile Manifesto values and principles can be taught and exercised throughout any type of organization as it is not limited to development teams.&#xA;The entire organization needs to understand the values and principles of an agile transformation to benefit from the rewards of achieving healthy agility.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cross-cutting Concepts</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/08-crosscutting-concepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/08-crosscutting-concepts/</guid>
      <description>Cross-cutting Concepts Content This section describes overall, principal regulations and solution ideas that are relevant in multiple parts (= cross-cutting) of your system. Such concepts are often related to multiple building blocks. They can include many different topics, such as&#xA;models, especially domain models&#xA;architecture or design patterns&#xA;rules for using specific technology&#xA;principal, often technical decisions of an overarching (= cross-cutting) nature&#xA;implementation rules&#xA;Motivation Concepts form the basis for conceptual integrity (consistency, homogeneity) of the architecture.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Smoke Tests</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/ui/smoketests/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/ui/smoketests/</guid>
      <description>Smoke Tests The goal is to test the ERP functionalities in a quick and efficient way. The smoke tests are a subset of the test cases that are run on the ERP system to ensure that the most crucial functions of a program work. The smoke tests are run to determine if the ERP system is stable and can be used for further testing.&#xA;The tests are:&#xA;Login to the ERP system with the default user</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Functional Programming</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/functional-programming-in-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/functional-programming-in-java/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Functional Object-Oriented Order of execution is not always important. It can be asynchronous.&#xA;A specific execution sequence of statements is crucial&#xA;Functions are basic building elements to work with data structures.&#xA;Objects are the main abstractions for data&#xA;Follows the declarative paradigm.&#xA;Follows the imperative paradigm.&#xA;Focuses on the result desired and its final conditions.&#xA;Focuses on how the desired result can be achieved.&#xA;Ensure immutability; programs should be stateless.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Architecture Decisions</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/09-architecture-decisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/09-architecture-decisions/</guid>
      <description>Architecture Decisions Overall Decisions System Guava Removal&#xA;Unit Test Conventions&#xA;Use Modern Java Constructs&#xA;Publish Technical Documentation through Static Website&#xA;Publish Maven Central Artifacts&#xA;Dependency Injection Guice&#xA;Persistence with MicroStream&#xA;Use log4j2 as Default Logger&#xA;Use hsqldb as SQL store&#xA;Archive Data&#xA;Vaadin as User Interface Approach&#xA;ERP UI Decisions Asciidoc for all Texts&#xA;FSM Decisions Move Abstractions to JDK Classes&#xA;Publish Maven Central Artifacts&#xA;PRJ Decisions link:../adr/prj-001-project-tag-for-project-costs/Project Tag for Project Costs]</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quality Requirements</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/10-quality-requirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/10-quality-requirements/</guid>
      <description>Quality Requirements Content This section contains all quality requirements as quality tree with scenarios. The most important ones have already been described in section 1.2. (quality goals)&#xA;Here you can also capture quality requirements with lesser priority, which will not create high risks when they are not fully achieved.&#xA;Motivation Since quality requirements will have a lot of influence on architectural decisions you should know for every stakeholder what is really important to them, concrete and measurable.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ERPUI-001: AsciiDoc for Text Fields</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/adr/erpui-001-asciidoc-for-all-texts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/adr/erpui-001-asciidoc-for-all-texts/</guid>
      <description>ERPUI-001 Asciidoc for Text Fields Date: 2021-06-01&#xA;Status Implemented&#xA;Context Asciidoc is a well-established approach to write rich text documentation or comments. The casual user can learn and use the notation without excessive effort. The legibility and professional appearance of asciidoc texts are striking higher than plain text. Asciidoc is an open standard and used in various environments and tools [1].&#xA;Decision All texts and comments in the ERP components shall use Asciidoc notation to improve legibility.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Technical Risks and Debts</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/11-technical-risks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/11-technical-risks/</guid>
      <description>Risks and Technical Debts Contents A list of identified technical risks or technical debts, ordered by priority&#xA;Motivation “Risk management is project management for grown-ups” (Tim Lister, Atlantic Systems Guild.)&#xA;This should be your motto for systematic detection and evaluation of risks and technical debts in the architecture, which will be needed by management stakeholders (e.g. project managers, product owners) as part of the overall risk analysis and measurement planning.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>User Manual</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/12-user-manual/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/12-user-manual/</guid>
      <description>User Manual Idea The tangly services ERP provides the functionalities to manage service company offerings and legal documents.&#xA;The first customer ever using the application is tangly llc company. The company is an agile consulting and Java stack boutique organization.&#xA;A service company has no inventory, production, or logistics departments.&#xA;A service company has a strong focus on customers, digital products, projects and associated efforts. Cash flow is dictated by the timely invoicing of performed activities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Glossary</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/13-glossary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/13-glossary/</guid>
      <description>Glossary Term Definition Remarks ADR&#xA;Architecture Design Record&#xA;DDD&#xA;Domain-Driven Design&#xA;DoD&#xA;Definition of Done&#xA;FSM&#xA;Finite State Machine&#xA;SDL&#xA;Specification and Description Language&#xA;UML&#xA;Unified Modeling Language&#xA;VAT&#xA;Value-Added Tax</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FSM 001: Move Abstractions to JDK Classes</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/adr/fsm-001-move-abstractions-to-jdk-classes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/adr/fsm-001-move-abstractions-to-jdk-classes/</guid>
      <description>FSM-001 Replace Guard and Action classes with JDK BiPredicate and BiFunction Classes Date: 2017-06-01&#xA;Status Implemented&#xA;Context We need a legible data model for finite state machine definitions. New users should easily understand the finite state machine abstractions and map them to their domain.&#xA;Decision We use standard classes of the JDK to minimize contextual complexity when learning and using the FSM library. We will evaluate if the loss of domain names for classes has a negative impact on the legibility of the library.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FSM-002: Publish Maven Central Artifacts</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/adr/fsm-002-publish-maven-central-artifact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/architecture/adr/fsm-002-publish-maven-central-artifact/</guid>
      <description>FSM-002 Publish Artifacts on Public Java Components Repository Date: 2020-01-01&#xA;Status Retired&#xA;Links Superseded by: OS-0005&#xA;Context The library is mature enough to be used in commercial and academic projects. The library was used in internal projects and refined to fulfill these requirements. More customers will validate the usefulness of the library and identify extensions for further releases.&#xA;Decision The library shall be published on maven central and be accessible to a wide range of developers and organizations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contributing Guidelines</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/contribution-guidelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/contribution-guidelines/</guid>
      <description>This is an open source product. We love getting patches and contributions to make our components, and their documentation even better.&#xA;Contributing to tangly Open Source Components The components live in Open Source Components. The git repository and the issue tracker are public and accessible to all interested parties.&#xA;You can create the set of git remotes with the following instructions.&#xA;git remote add origin-github git@github.com:marcelbaumann/tangly-os.git (1) git remote add origin-gitlab git@gitlab.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development Environment</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/development-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/development-environment/</guid>
      <description>The development environment is MacOS [1].&#xA;Java JDKs Install Java development kits. You should at least install the last released version and the last LTS version. We use the distributions of Oracle.&#xA;alias java17 = &amp;#34;export JAVA_HOME=`/usr/libexec/java_home -v 17`; java -version&amp;#34; alias java19 = &amp;#34;export JAVA_HOME=`/usr/libexec/java_home -v 19`; java -version&amp;#34; alias java20 = &amp;#34;export JAVA_HOME=`/usr/libexec/java_home -v 20`; java -version&amp;#34; Tools We use brew to install. The following tools shall be installed [2].</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Actors with CMSIS OS in Cpp</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/actors-with-cmsis-os-in-cpp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/actors-with-cmsis-os-in-cpp/</guid>
      <description>The actor library defines the actor abstraction with mailboxes and concrete implementation for various target platforms.&#xA;The CMSIS-RTOS v2 platform provides an actor implementation for all realtime kernels supporting the CMSIS API. The API is under the stewardship of ARM company.&#xA;Any kernel with a CMSIS-RTOS v2 compatible layer is eligible.&#xA;STM provides the CMSIS integration with freeRTOS for all STM32 microcontrollers.&#xA;Library The library defines key abstractions as abstract classes [1] [2].</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Actors in Cpp</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/actors-in-cpp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/actors-in-cpp/</guid>
      <description>There is a strong need for higher-level frameworks ensuring safe concurrent programming.&#xA;The Actor Model is one of the best approaches to safe concurrency and legible code [1]. The model is based on Message Passing.&#xA;Although multiple actors can run at the same time, an actor will process a given message sequentially. This means that if you send three messages to the same actor, it will just execute one at a time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daily Scrum Questions</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/daily-scrum-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/daily-scrum-questions/</guid>
      <description>The daily Scrum meeting is a key event for the development team.&#xA;It is a time-boxed event of maximum 15 minutes.&#xA;The developers find out if the Sprint Goal is still achievable and what are the identified impediments to be tackled.&#xA;Often the collaborators use the meeting to synchronize their work and to plan the day.&#xA;It is a great opportunity to ask questions and to learn from each other.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Love My Nerdy Job</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/i-love-my-nerdy-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/i-love-my-nerdy-job/</guid>
      <description>I am a computer science engineer. I love to solve problems and provide cool solutions to users [1].&#xA;I love my software development job. I am already sixty years old. I started programming before I was 20.&#xA;And I still tremendously love developing digital products and writing software applications.&#xA;My passion is tinkering with source code to have a maintainable and efficient solution. I love to work with other developers and to coach them to become better software engineers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Actor Model</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/actor-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/actor-model/</guid>
      <description>Concurrent programming has always been tricky. Accessing a shared state from multiple threads is a central problem, where hard-to-catch errors may easily appear.&#xA;Protected access to identified shared variables is easy to realize. Mechanisms to avoid deadlocks or starvation are cumbersome to implement and almost impossible to validate.&#xA;The need for concurrent programming has increased tremendously with the fact that all modern processors and many microcontrollers have multiple cores.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Document Your Software Architecture</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/how-to-document-your-software-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/how-to-document-your-software-architecture/</guid>
      <description>You are creating the next digital software masterpiece.&#xA;How can you document your software architecture in a way that is useful for your team and stakeholders?&#xA;A software architecture document SAD is a document that describes the structure of a software solution.&#xA;It includes the architecture of its components, the relationships between those components, and the principles that guide its design.&#xA;The solution architecture document is typically used as a reference for designing, building, and maintaining a software system.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modern Java Rant</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/modern-java-rant/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/modern-java-rant/</guid>
      <description>The Java community releases a new version every six months. This is a good thing, it means that the language is evolving at a steady pace.&#xA;New language features are added in each release. Much effort is put into improving the performance of the JVM and solving small issues.&#xA;The community provides beta releases for developers to test and provide feedback during the six months before the next release. You have the possibility and time to migrate and test your code before the official release.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure Your Concurrency</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/structure-your-concurrency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/structure-your-concurrency/</guid>
      <description>Writing concurrent software is one of the greatest challenges for software developers [1, 2].&#xA;A professional software developer must understand the principles of concurrent programming and the tools available to write concurrent software.&#xA;Only concurrent applications can access all cores of modern multicore processors and provide the best performance.&#xA;Java thread model makes it a strong contender among concurrent languages, but multithreading has always been inherently tricky.&#xA;The introduction of virtual threads empowered Java to provide a unique and highly-optimized threading system that is also easy to understand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asciidoc and Hugo Website Improvements</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/asciidoc-and-hugo-website-improvements/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/asciidoc-and-hugo-website-improvements/</guid>
      <description>The static website build tool Hugo is awesome.&#xA;The extensive built-in feature set of Hugo and the feature-rich typesetting that Asciidoc offers provide a blogging experience composed of easy content management and fun writing experience.&#xA;Source code highlighting and diagrams are extensively supported.&#xA;Hugo supports natively Asciidoc syntax. Asciidoc files are automatically compiled with Asciidoctor, so we do not need to configure anything. Have it installed and you are ready to go.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nice Statechart Diagrams</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/nice-statechart-diagrams/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/nice-statechart-diagrams/</guid>
      <description>What are statecharts, also called hierarchical state machines?&#xA;Put simply, a statechart is a beefed-up state machine [1] [2]. The syntax is formally defined in the UML standard.&#xA;The beefing up solves a lot of the problems that state machines have, especially state explosion that happens as state machines grow.&#xA;We explain below what statecharts are and how they are useful.&#xA;Statecharts offer a surprising array of benefits:&#xA;It is easier to understand a statechart than many other forms of code.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java Modules</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/java-modules/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/java-modules/</guid>
      <description>Java 9 introduces a new level of abstraction above packages, known as the Java Platform Module System JPMS, or Modules for short [1].&#xA;Modules emphasize at compilation time modern software engineering principles such as encapsulation, and modularity [2, 3, 4].&#xA;Java 9 was released in September 2017.&#xA;Most Java developers are still not using this powerful and elegant construct to modularize their applications.&#xA;Modules A module is a group of closely related Java packages and resources along with a new module descriptor file.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How To Improve</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/how-to-improve/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/how-to-improve/</guid>
      <description>You attended a famous or a local technical school. You are the proud owner of a bachelor or a master degree in science.&#xA;You are a certified engineer.&#xA;You are now a full-time software developer. You write daily productive code with your colleagues in your current company.&#xA;Hopefully you studied software engineering at least as a minor.&#xA;How can you continuously improve in your profession?&#xA;How can you become proficient in the new features and possibilities of the technologies you use daily?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Quest for an Agile Company: Eight Years tangly llc</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/the-quest-for-an-agile-company-eight-years-tangly-llc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/the-quest-for-an-agile-company-eight-years-tangly-llc/</guid>
      <description>We are an agile and software technology boutique.&#xA;We often work as Scrum masters, product owners and technical agile coaches. Regularly we are involved in the architecture and development of software products.&#xA;Our collaborators love to coaching, mentoring, and training.&#xA;We regularly work at the customer site. We also more and more often work online with our international customers.&#xA;How do you organize such a company?&#xA;How do collaborators work together?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Streams</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/advanced-streams/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/advanced-streams/</guid>
      <description>The Java Stream API is a powerful and simple to understand set of tools for processing sequences of elements. The standard collections were retrofitted with the stream() method, which allows us to convert any collection to a stream.&#xA;Modern Java code has almost no loops and conditional statements. It relies on the Stream API and the functional programming style to implement algorithms.&#xA;When used properly, it allows us to reduce a huge amount of boilerplate code, create more readable programs, and improve productivity [1, 2].</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EclipseStore</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/eclipsestore/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/eclipsestore/</guid>
      <description>Eclipse Store [1] is a Java-native persistence layer built for cloud-native microservices and serverless systems. EclipseStore is the only data storage solution that uses the native Java object model instead of database-specific structure or format.&#xA;It enables storing any Java object graph of any size and complexity transaction-safe into any binary data storage such as plain files, persistent volumes, or cloud object storage.&#xA;Snapshots of the object graph differences are regularly saved to the storage.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Classes, Sealed Types and Pattern Matching</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/data-classes-sealed-types-and-pattern-matching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/data-classes-sealed-types-and-pattern-matching/</guid>
      <description>Records, sealed types, enumerations are the key language features for Algebraic Data Types.&#xA;The features have been available since Java 17.&#xA;Latter JDK releases provide additional capabilities and syntactic sugar.&#xA;Based on the features of JDK 22, we are still missing with constructors for records and primitive support for pattern matching [1].&#xA;Pattern matching capabilities empower the developer to implement complex algorithms in a compact and legible way.&#xA;Patterns such as visitor pattern are obsolete.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bus Sensors and Actuators</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/bus-sensors-and-actuators/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/bus-sensors-and-actuators/</guid>
      <description>Your embedded system has a set of sensors and actors.&#xA;Some sensors and actors are connected to a bus. Typical buses are CAN bus, Serial Peripherical Interface, Ethernet, Bluetooth, or I2C standards.&#xA;The bus is a shared medium used to communicate with a set of external active or passive components.&#xA;Which design rules shall you follow when designing sensors and actors using a bus architecture?&#xA;Do you need to consider threading design?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sensors and Actuators</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/sensors-and-actuators/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/sensors-and-actuators/</guid>
      <description>Embedded design maps domain abstractions to the underlying hardware.&#xA;A temperature sensor is a domain abstraction of a physical hardware temperature sensor.&#xA;A valve is a domain abstraction of a physical hardware valve. A physical valve can be a simple opened-closed device, or a proportional device.&#xA;The microcontroller board reads the temperature sensor through an I2C or SPI bus. It controls the valve through a GPIO, a PWM or a CAN bus controller.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Command Interpreter</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/command-interpreter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/command-interpreter/</guid>
      <description>Most digital products have a command interpreter.&#xA;External systems send requests to the system and often await an answer. A command interpreter can model this behavior.&#xA;The channels used to transmit requests and return answers are variable. Messages can be transmitted other various buses and protocols.&#xA;An operator can send a command over a CAN bus, Serial Peripherical Interface, Ethernet or Bluetooth connection.&#xA;A regular command line interpreter inputs commands as a string containing a request and associated parameters.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Commits for the Impatient</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/semantic-commits-for-the-impatient/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/semantic-commits-for-the-impatient/</guid>
      <description>The conventional commits specification is a lightweight convention on top of commit messages. The additional information classifies the type of work performed in the commit.&#xA;A developer infers the importance of the task by looking to the type of the commit. The message communicates the nature of changes to teammates, the public, and other stakeholders.&#xA;Contributors of project repositories know that a well-designed Git commit message is the best way to communicate the context about a change to other developers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gradle Good Practices</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/gradle-good-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/gradle-good-practices/</guid>
      <description>Gradle Build Tool is a fast, dependable, and adaptable open-source build automation tool with an elegant and extensible declarative build language. Java is the primary supported programming language.&#xA;Gradle Build Tool is a popular build system for the JVM and is the default system for Android and Kotlin Multi-Platform projects.&#xA;It has a rich community plugin ecosystem. Groovy, Kotlin, C++, and Swift stacks are well-supported.&#xA;Gradle is fast, scalable, and can build projects of any size and complexity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Static Website Improvements</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/static-website-improvements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/static-website-improvements/</guid>
      <description>The static website build tool Hugo is awesome.&#xA;The extensive built-in feature set of Hugo and the feature-rich text-formatting options that Asciidoc offers creates a blogging experience composed of easy content management and fun writing experience.&#xA;The Hugo theme Docsy is ideal to create a good-looking software documentation site. The templates for blogging are good enough for our needs.&#xA;This theme is currently the best match I found to combine product documentation with blogging.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pragmatic Java Application Design</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/pragmatic-java-application-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/pragmatic-java-application-design/</guid>
      <description>I attended the 20th edition of the Devoxx Belgium conference in Antwerp.&#xA;I heard about beautiful examples of how to design complex software applications written in Java.&#xA;The solutions scale to hundreds of thousands of users, are resilient to network disruption and use fancy libraries and tools.&#xA;The applications are deployed on cloud infrastructure and are available worldwide.&#xA;After the conference, I went to Ibiza for a family holiday. Our family enjoys prolonging the summer on this beautiful balearic island.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>C4 and UML with PlantUML</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/c4-and-uml-with-plantuml/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/c4-and-uml-with-plantuml/</guid>
      <description>You are creating an awesome digital product. The software part shall work flawlessly over the years.&#xA;Technology changes will be added to the product. Legal changes and security improvements are implemented in a timely manner over the years.&#xA;This application will evolve to satisfy new needs and customer segments. The life span of your product is probably more than a decade.&#xA;How can you document critical cross-cutting design decisions and key mechanisms?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java Certification</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/java-certification/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/java-certification/</guid>
      <description>Java expertise is in high demand for all kinds of projects, ranging from big enterprise software implementations down to little web projects. A huge number of enterprise applications are developed in Java.&#xA;But will those employers want you to have related certifications?&#xA;Even if you are not looking to move any time soon, getting certified boosts the value that you can bring to your organization.&#xA;Certifications can be a great bargaining chip when it comes to negotiating a raise or a promotion.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20th Devoxx Belgium Conference 2023</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/20th-devoxx-belgium-conference-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/20th-devoxx-belgium-conference-2023/</guid>
      <description>I attended the highly anticipated 20th edition of Devoxx Belgium 2023.&#xA;Building on the success of the previous year, which attracted over 3,200 attendees, this five-day technology conference is set to exceed expectations.&#xA;The fresh release of Java 21 is a hot topic. Renowned speakers share their knowledge and discuss the enhancements that this new version brings, providing a valuable learning opportunity.&#xA;Attending Devoxx Belgium presents a remarkable opportunity to broaden your knowledge, refine your skills, and gain firsthand experience with the most recent technologies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Software Architecture Themes and Questions</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/software-architecture-themes-and-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/software-architecture-themes-and-questions/</guid>
      <description>A software architect works with a development team to define how features shall be realized. The selected approach should support corporate governance and legal constraints.&#xA;A new digital product must fulfill a set of technical aspects to be usable. Technical constraints are the non-functional requirements of the product [1].&#xA;Some of these technical requirements are encountered again and again when developing digital products.&#xA;Any software product must provide solutions to standard problems.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Visual Tools</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/agile-visual-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/agile-visual-tools/</guid>
      <description>Why is visibility so important for any agile or Scrum team?&#xA;When you are running an agile product development initiative, your ultimate goal is customer satisfaction with the delivered solution.&#xA;The project coordination responsibilities are, however, not limited to this single goal.&#xA;The product owner shall nurture the vision, roadmap, the release plan and customer journey. You must coordinate the workflow of your team, refine the product backlog, control identified risks, and track deadlines.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Git Tag for the Impatient</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/git-tag-for-the-impatient/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/git-tag-for-the-impatient/</guid>
      <description>The development software team has reached a milestone.&#xA;A working application with a set of features is available. All tests are green.&#xA;The application can potentially be shipped to internal or external customers.&#xA;How can you mark this event in the git repository of the application?&#xA;Use tags to recognize this state in the list of changes of your shared Git repository.&#xA;Listing Your Tags Listing the existing tags in Git is straightforward.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Git Rebase and Merge for the Impatient</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/git-rebase-and-merge-for-the-impatient/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/git-rebase-and-merge-for-the-impatient/</guid>
      <description>Both the rebase and merge commands provide similar functionalities.&#xA;They combine the work of multiple developers into a single entity, integrating changes between branches.&#xA;That about sums up their similarities.&#xA;The operation git merge is a way of combining changes from one source branch into another target branch. The operation leaves commit messages in the history.&#xA;The operation git rebase is a way of moving the changes from one branch onto another branch.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java 21</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/java-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/java-21/</guid>
      <description>Java 21 LTS was released on time to the public. The release has been available for download since 21st September 2023.&#xA;Pattern matching is maturing nicely. The hope is that more solutions will more advanced data stream manipulation and functional programming algorithms. Complex inheritance structure are no more considered as good practices in regular application. The pattern matching extensions nicely provide idioms to solve similar design problems.&#xA;The support for virtual threads is reaching full integration in the official Java distribution.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Certifications Useful?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/are-certifications-useful/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/are-certifications-useful/</guid>
      <description>There are several benefits to getting an IT certification, and several associated costs too.&#xA;Certifications can give you the chance to learn needed skills, and be a quick way to show employers you have those skills.&#xA;On the other hand, certifications can require studying or coursework. You will invest a significant amount of time to master the material. They cost up to several hundred dollars to take.&#xA;So how do you know that the benefits will outweigh the costs for you?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Corporate Governance for Software Products</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/corporate-governance-for-software-products/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/corporate-governance-for-software-products/</guid>
      <description>Since good governance is about the processes for making and implementing decisions, then effective governance and accountability structures are vital.&#xA;Organizations shall successfully use an agile approach to deliver business change through the investment in programs and projects.&#xA;Agile approaches are the most used frameworks to develop successfully digital products.&#xA;Our corporate governance processes shall support agile values and development methods.&#xA;The four guiding principles to enable successful governance of agile delivery are:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Onboarding Software Developers in Your agile Team</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/onboarding-software-developers-in-your-agile-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/onboarding-software-developers-in-your-agile-team/</guid>
      <description>Now that you have gone through the long and tedious process of hiring a talented developer with vetting and interview activities, it is easy to think that the hard part is done [1] [2].&#xA;There is no doubt that hiring good people is challenging and competitive, but it is a mistake to think that the challenge ends when you hired a new collaborator.&#xA;Onboarding software developers is just as important for getting the most out of the hiring process.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Clojure II</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/teaching-clojure-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/teaching-clojure-ii/</guid>
      <description>Functional programming is hype for the last ten years.&#xA;All popular programming languages have added support to functional concepts for years.&#xA;Not all developers are embracing the new approach and using the provided constructs.&#xA;I often have to read source code which uses only idioms defined in the last millennium. I cringed and asked myself why developers are writing such awkward code?&#xA;What does it mean to code with functional paradigms?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Clojure I</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/teaching-clojure-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/teaching-clojure-i/</guid>
      <description>Functional programming is hype for the last ten years. You find a lot of blogs and videos stating object-oriented languages are doomed.&#xA;Almost all most popular languages have added some support to functional concepts in the last years.&#xA;Java introduced lambda expressions and single abstract method interfaces SAM with Java 8 in March 2014. Java developers are empowered to write functional code for almost ten years.&#xA;Other languages such as Python, C++ or C# added their own functional extensions in newer revisions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java 20</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/java-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/java-20/</guid>
      <description>Java 20 was released on time to the public. The release has been available for download since 21st March 2023.&#xA;Interestingly, the new Java release contains only incubating or preview JEP proposals. No final improvements are part of this version.&#xA;You are a Java developer, you should always install the latest JDK and try it out. Most of the time, all your products will compile and run on the new release without any changes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My New MacBookPro</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/my-new-macbookpro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/my-new-macbookpro/</guid>
      <description>I just received my new MacBookPro M2 Max with 32 GB of RAM and 1 TB SSD [1].&#xA;I know. I am a geek who loves his technical gadgets. I convinced my wife these gadgets are way cheaper than a sports car.&#xA;More seriously, I easily use my workstation forty hours a week. I really appreciate a stable and fast machine. My eyes are thankful if the display has a high resolution and the refresh rate fulfills ergonomic criteria [2].</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Software Developer Assumptions</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/software-developer-assumptions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/software-developer-assumptions/</guid>
      <description>Here are some software development topics I have learnt to like after 40 years in the industry.&#xA;I worked at quite a few industrial and commercial digital product development initiatives. I truly enjoyed creating successful solutions.&#xA;Over the years, I encountered similar architecture and design patterns when creating source code for these applications.&#xA;I started programming with languages such as Ada, Portal, and C. I embraced object-oriented languages with first C++ and later Java.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scrum Masters and Agile Coaches</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/scrum-masters-and-agile-coaches/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/scrum-masters-and-agile-coaches/</guid>
      <description>Scrum is the most popular agile approach used to develop digital products.&#xA;The Scrum master role is well-documented in the Scrum Guide. There are probably more than one million of certified Scrum masters in the world.&#xA;To differentiate themselves from the numerous Scrum masters, consultants call themselves agile coaches.&#xA;Quite a fancy title.&#xA;Does a difference exist between a Scrum master and an agile coach?&#xA;A Scrum master is a type of Agile coach.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Quest for an Agile Company: Seven Years tangly llc</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/the-quest-for-an-agile-company-seven-years-tangly-llc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/the-quest-for-an-agile-company-seven-years-tangly-llc/</guid>
      <description>We are an agile software coaching and digital product development boutique.&#xA;Since our inception, we have created digital products using agile approaches. Our preferred tools are Scrum, Lean Software Development, DevOps, LeSS.&#xA;The created digital products are successful in the market.&#xA;They exhibit good quality. Sound engineering approaches were used to design and construct them in a timely and economical way.&#xA;Our customers learnt how to deploy updates and new functionalities in a matter of days.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Technical Interviews</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/technical-interviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/technical-interviews/</guid>
      <description>Your sole goal is to hire a qualified collaborator with potential.&#xA;For example, you need a great software engineer with social competence. He is a professional developer and has knowledge of the technology stack [1] your company is using. The candidate naturally understands agile and DevOps approaches.&#xA;How can you convince him to sign the contract and start working on your cool product?&#xA;Hiring is like dating.&#xA;Both parties shall be motivated to deepen their relationship and enter a binding agreement.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SME IT Responsible</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/sme-it-responsible/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/sme-it-responsible/</guid>
      <description>What does a senior manager in charge of information technology?&#xA;An IT director is the information technology right-hand man of the company’s manager. He sometimes has the shiny title of CIO. He proposes and implements the IT strategy of the company.&#xA;He intervenes at different levels in the management and optimization of the company’s information system.&#xA;This encompasses hardware and software infrastructures, information architecture, business tools, dedicated internal or external human resources, and often old technology.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Select An Agile Software Development Partner</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/select-an-agile-software-development-partner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/select-an-agile-software-development-partner/</guid>
      <description>It is not unusual for businesses to turn to third-party companies when they want help to achieve their goals without increasing internal overhead.&#xA;This type of outsourcing is especially common for projects that require tremendous amounts of effort or specific skill sets [1].&#xA;Time constraints are often a supplemental driving factor.&#xA;Partnering up with another business to help meet your needs is a viable and widespread solution [2]. It often makes sense for businesses trying to tackle a massive software development project while focusing on the current needs of their clients.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Steps DevOps</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/first-steps-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/first-steps-devops/</guid>
      <description>The DevOps movement started to gather momentum with the first DevOps conference held in Ghent, Belgium in 2009 [1].&#xA;The approach aims to shorten the system development life-cycle and to provide continuous delivery with high software quality. DevOps is complementary with agile software development approaches.&#xA;Several DevOps aspects came from the Agile method.&#xA;Seminal books [1, 2, 3, 4] and good practices were published around the same time.&#xA;The DevOps approach belongs to the regular instruments of professional software developers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Module Test Reporting with Gradle 7.x</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/multi-module-test-reporting-with-gradle-7.x/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/multi-module-test-reporting-with-gradle-7.x/</guid>
      <description>I love Gradle as the building tool for all my Java projects.&#xA;But sometimes I was discouraged about how spotty or cumbersome the support for multi-module project is.&#xA;I struggled for years to generate test and code overage reports over modules included in a Gradle Build Tool project.&#xA;Gradle finally provides a better approach to generate aggregated test and code coverage reports over multiple modules belonging to the same project.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Behavior Driven Design</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/behavior-driven-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/behavior-driven-design/</guid>
      <description>Domain-Driven Design DDD has been around since Eric Evans published his book about the subject in 2003 [1].&#xA;Vernon Vaugh published powerful approaches how to implement DDD concepts into a software solution [2, 3].&#xA;How do you validate and test your DDD digital solutions?&#xA;Behavior Driven Development BDD is an inversion how systems are often developed. In some ways, it is an extension of Test Driven Development TDD approach to the whole application.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modern Java Constructs</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/modern-java-constructs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/modern-java-constructs/</guid>
      <description>Modern Java is quite a departure from the traditional Java available at the beginning of the millennium.&#xA;The most visible change is certainly lambda expressions and stream, enabling a more functional programming approach in Java.&#xA;Functional programming is a paradigm that supports developers to think in terms of functions instead of classes. Functions are stateless and without side effects. Avoiding state can lead to better software, especially in high-performance, concurrent applications [1].</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vaadin</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/vaadin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/vaadin/</guid>
      <description>Vaadin is an ideal solution if you are a Java developer and wants to provide a user interface for your product. Vaadin is a framework to create graphical user interfaces using plain Java, or any JVM-based language for that matter.&#xA;You develop in Java, and the framework takes care of all the rest. It generates the client-side code, and the communication between the client-side code in the browser and the backend code on the server.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eliminate Your Printer</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/eliminate-your-printer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/eliminate-your-printer/</guid>
      <description>In an increasingly technology-focused world, the demand for businesses to digitize has grown dramatically.&#xA;So, what does it mean to digitize your business?&#xA;Essentially, it means incorporating technology into your business operations to increase efficiency, enhance customer experience, and boost sales.&#xA;This could mean developing a mobile application for your startup, transitioning into ecommerce, offering mobile payment options, and more.&#xA;The goal of digitizing your business is to keep up with the rapidly changing economy by offering your customers more ways to access your business, and streamline daily operations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Experiences</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/expertise/expertise-agile/agile-experiences/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/expertise/expertise-agile/agile-experiences/</guid>
      <description>Agile Experiences Context Scrum is the industrial standard to create and develop awesome digital products.&#xA;Scrum Scrum is a minimalist framework empowering your organization to deliver digital products.&#xA;Scrum is an additive framework. Please be pragmatic and professional.&#xA;Roles: Product Owner, Scrum Master, Team Member&#xA;Events: Sprint, Sprint Planning, Daily Scrum, Review, Retrospective, Backlog Refinement&#xA;Artifacts: Product Increment, Product Backlog, Spring Backlog, Definition of Done&#xA;Technical Agile and Scrum</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ArchUnit</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/archunit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/archunit/</guid>
      <description>How often have you experienced a well-defined and understood software architecture on paper? And it falls apart when developers start implementing it?&#xA;While re-architecting recently legacy components in an application, I experienced the same.&#xA;As more and more developers joined the team, it became a constant routine to make them aware of the design and how to adhere to it.&#xA;I know some of you may say, Why not control the implementation during code-review sessions?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transfer a Software Project</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/transfer-a-software-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/transfer-a-software-project/</guid>
      <description>You developed a new digital product for an internal or external customer. Your solution is awesome.&#xA;The product is released to delighted users. Your users love your solution.&#xA;The project is now winding down and closing activities are initiated. The customer organization shall take ownership of all product related artifacts. The handover is a vital part of closing a project [1].&#xA;Your customer paid for the development and own the produced artifacts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Detect Fake Scrum?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/how-to-detect-fake-scrum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/how-to-detect-fake-scrum/</guid>
      <description>Some organisations are adopting agile and Scrum approaches simply because they see competitors doing it. In these situations, there is rarely a desire to adopt a new mindset and culture, or motivation for true change.&#xA;A common pattern is the adoption of a new nomenclature. Project Managers are renamed as Scrum Masters. Business Analysts become Product Owners.&#xA;Very little actually changes. Few benefits of agility are realised.&#xA;If anything, the situation may become worse as some previous structures are lost, yet the discipline for Agile is just not there.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Would You Enjoy Being a Scrum Master?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/would-you-enjoy-being-a-scrum-master/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/would-you-enjoy-being-a-scrum-master/</guid>
      <description>Scrum is the most popular approach to create awesome new digital products.&#xA;Perhaps you are thinking of pursuing a career as a Scrum master. You read the Agile Manifesto and memorized the 12 Agile Manifesto Principles.&#xA;Perhaps you have recently been moved into that role and are wondering if being a Scrum master is right for you.&#xA;There are plenty of good reasons to become a Scrum master. The job is fascinating, in demand and pays well.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modular Monoliths are the new Graal</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/modular-monoliths-are-the-new-graal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/modular-monoliths-are-the-new-graal/</guid>
      <description>A modular monolith is a software design approach in which a monolith is designed with an emphasis on interchangeable and potentially reusable modules.&#xA;A modular monolith can be split in the future into a set of microservices.&#xA;Delay the split as long as you can. Microservices have a steep price tag during operations.&#xA;A modular monolith provides:&#xA;Independent and parallel development approach.&#xA;Diminish coupling and improve cohesion. The interfaces are better documented and thinner.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Software Structure with DDD</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/software-structure-with-ddd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/software-structure-with-ddd/</guid>
      <description>Domain Driven Development DDD is the preferred software architecture approach for designing digital products. The method nicely matches with the operational concepts of microservices.&#xA;Domain-driven design is a holistic approach to understanding, designing and building software applications.&#xA;Seminal books [1, 2, 3] describes the approach and key concepts defining the development method.&#xA;Concrete recipes and examples of code structure are still sparse.&#xA;How should you structure your namespaces and modules?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Measurements and Units</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/measurements-and-units/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/measurements-and-units/</guid>
      <description>JSR-385 could have saved Mars Climate Orbiter[2] in year 1999.&#xA;Accidents in computer applications happen again and again due to calculation errors.&#xA;The International System of Units SI, commonly known as the metric system, is the international standard for measurement.&#xA;The International Treaty of the Mete was signed in Paris on May 20, 1875, by seventeen countries, including the United States.&#xA;In May 2019, the system of units was updated.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing DevOps Ideas</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/introducing-devops-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/introducing-devops-ideas/</guid>
      <description>Your organization heard of DevOps, and your developers clamor you should adopt the approach.&#xA;Each organization I talk with has some DevOps initiative. Often because they read that DevOps approach puts customers and end-user satisfaction at the center.&#xA;Does DevOps really improve the quality of your digital products and customer satisfaction?&#xA;Or is it only the next silver bullet fad used to increase the bonus of consultants and managers?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digital Product Manager</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/digital-product-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/digital-product-manager/</guid>
      <description>Effective product management is driven by a customer-centric mindset. The customer is placed at the center of every decision.&#xA;Supported by tools and techniques such as design thinking, this mindset focuses the entire organization on creating desirable, viable, feasible, and sustainable solutions.&#xA;Good product managers balance customer needs, adequate technologies, product delivery, and governance or legal constraints.&#xA;They shall master project management approaches, financing mechanisms and collaborator nurturing.&#xA;Responsibilities The primary responsibilities of product management often fall into the following areas.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yet Another Hybrid Method</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/yet-another-hybrid-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/yet-another-hybrid-method/</guid>
      <description>SoDa Software Development Agile is a homebrew project development method created at the technical university of Lucerne. It is a mixture of Waterfall, RUP and Scrum approaches. It uses a distorted Scrum for the concept and implementation phase[2].&#xA;The documentation was not updated the last ten years. The approach is clinically dead and should not be promoted for active software development efforts.&#xA;A similar approach exists with the official governmental Swiss project method HERMES.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java, Groovy, Clojure</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/java-groovy-clojure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/java-groovy-clojure/</guid>
      <description>Professional software developers shall master their primary technology stack and programming language.&#xA;I am a proficient and experienced programmer in Java.&#xA;I have written production code in Java for the last twenty years.&#xA;I decided to study the language in depth and acquired various Java developer certifications.&#xA;I truly love the modern Java language and the available development environments.&#xA;I want to understand the strengths and weaknesses of Java.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modernize Your Java Landscape</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/modernize-your-java-landscape/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/modernize-your-java-landscape/</guid>
      <description>The dreaded attack through the log4j logging library was a wake-up call for all companies using obsolete libraries. Many organizations found out the hard way they cannot update the library and deploy the new version in a matter of minutes as professional developers should do. They needed weeks to perform such a simple activity.&#xA;They also found out that they had no process for such regular situations when a critical flaw is detected in some software they are using.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modern Java with Spring</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/modern-java-with-spring/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/modern-java-with-spring/</guid>
      <description>Spring and Spring Boot frameworks are the standard for enterprise Java applications.&#xA;Spring Boot makes it easy to create stand-alone, production-grade Spring-based Applications that you can just run.&#xA;They take an opinionated view of the Spring platform and third-party libraries, so you can get started with minimum fuss.&#xA;Most Spring Boot applications need minimal Spring configuration.&#xA;Minimize Boilerplate Code One of the key reasons for the success of Spring is the approach of convention over configuration.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doing Agile</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/doing-agile/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/doing-agile/</guid>
      <description>In the midst of the agile adoption explosion, many teams are experiencing difficulties.&#xA;Organizations often mix agile with Scrum.&#xA;One of the most common misconceptions about Scrum is that it is synonymous with agile. Agile Manifesto is an umbrella term that refers to a family of approaches that share common values and principles.&#xA;Scrum is a commonly used agile framework that offers suggestions for how work can be organized to maximize the value of the end-user.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile and Nearshore Development</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/agile-and-nearshore-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/agile-and-nearshore-development/</guid>
      <description>The majority of software product development initiatives use an agile approach. The most popular framework is currently Scrum.&#xA;It is natural that organizations would gravitate towards the many benefits agile ideas provide.&#xA;Scarce resources and time-to-market constraints have driven the implementation of shoring development initiatives. Awareness that talent can be found at any location speeds up the trend.&#xA;The outsourcing market is undergoing constant evolution. Traditionally, cost reduction was the key driver for software development outsourcing, but now it doesn’t even make the top five, according to Deloitte’s 2018 Global Outsourcing Survey.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Quest for an Agile Company: Six Years tangly llc</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/the-quest-for-an-agile-company-six-years-tangly-llc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/the-quest-for-an-agile-company-six-years-tangly-llc/</guid>
      <description>Historically, big beats small. Scale was a sufficient advantage to be successful in the market.&#xA;Now, fast and adaptive beats slow and steadfast.&#xA;New technologies, evolving customer preferences and changing employee expectations are fundamentally challenging established ways of working [1].&#xA;It is time to move beyond rigid hierarchies, siloed business units, crippling bureaucracy and an increasingly unwieldy matrix.&#xA;Agile organizations combine the efficiencies of scale with the speed, flexibility and resilience to compete and win in today’s world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluate Technical CVs</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/evaluate-technical-cvs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/evaluate-technical-cvs/</guid>
      <description>The goal of a curriculum vitae is to get an invitation to a job interview. I review hundreds of CVs and must select a few candidates we should invite.&#xA;Each interview will cost hundreds of Euros to the company. I must minimize the number of interviews and increase the probability of a match.&#xA;Over the years, I developed a checklist to select promising candidates.&#xA;The below checklist is biased to the Java technology check.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Immutability in Java</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/immutability-in-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/immutability-in-java/</guid>
      <description>Immutability is a powerful and simple concept in programming theory that is strangely underused.&#xA;An immutable object is simply a class whose instances cannot be modified. This is in contrast to a mutable object or changeable object, which can be modified after it is created.&#xA;Immutable objects are also useful because they are inherently thread-safe. Other benefits are that they are simpler to understand and reason about and offer higher security than mutable objects</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Technical Debt</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/technical-debt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/technical-debt/</guid>
      <description>The technical debt or code debt is a concept in software development that reflects the implied cost of additional rework. The rework is caused by choosing an easy limited solution now instead of using a better approach that would take longer to realize.&#xA;Another source of technical debt is natural technical obsolescence.&#xA;As with monetary debt, if technical debt is not repaid, it accumulates interest, making it harder and harder to implement changes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spotify Cultural Elements</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/spotify-cultural-elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/spotify-cultural-elements/</guid>
      <description>Recently, a client told me that they were adopting the Spotify Model. This statement sounded great for him.&#xA;Spotify has published some great articles and videos about how they have grown and transformed their organization to be agile. Then it occurred to me that what my customer was saying was completely wrong.&#xA;I don’t think you can really understand what it is like to work at Spotify without actually living it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gradle 7</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/gradle-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/gradle-7/</guid>
      <description>Gradle Build Tool is my preferred build tool for all Java applications I am developing.&#xA;Google chose Gradle as the official build tool for Android.&#xA;Not only because build scripts are code, but because Gradle is modeled in a way that is extensible in the most fundamental ways.&#xA;Gradle’s model also allows it to be used for native development with C/C++ and can be expanded to cover any ecosystem.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Choice is Good</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/choice-is-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/choice-is-good/</guid>
      <description>First and foremost, our primary goal is to develop successful products and delight users. We are always looking for good practices to improve our odds.&#xA;Product development is a risky business.&#xA;We want to expand our toolbox with proven approaches. We use these tools to experiment when confronted with new problems. There is No Silver Bullet to solve our specific challenges.&#xA;Using a goal-driven approach that guides people through process-related options is one powerful approach.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JDk 17</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/jdk-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/jdk-17/</guid>
      <description>I truly love the new release rhythm of the Java ecosystem. Every six months a new JDK is delivered. Being able to use new features every six months is awesome.&#xA;The new release JDK 17 [3] is the next long term support LTS release. The migration overhead is held to a minimum thanks to the incredible backward compatibility. The early-access builds give you more than enough opportunities and time to migrate all your applications on time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Design Modeling</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/agile-design-modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/agile-design-modeling/</guid>
      <description>Unknown reference: implementing-domain-driven-desing The line between software development and software architecture is a tricky one.&#xA;Some people will tell you that it does not exist and that architecture is simply an extension of the design process undertaken by developers. Others will make out it is a massive gaping chasm that can only be crossed by lofty developers. They believe you must always abstract your abstractions and not get bogged down by those pesky implementation details.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scrum Developer Formation</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/scrum-developer-formation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/scrum-developer-formation/</guid>
      <description>You are working as a developer in a Scrum team.&#xA;Congratulations, working as a professional Scrum developer is a fulfilling and exciting job.&#xA;You should attend professional training.&#xA;Formal training is often the difference between being a professional instead of just pretending to be one.&#xA;Scrum Developer Role Here the official definition of the developer team member role taken from the Scrum Guide.&#xA;Developers are the people in the Scrum Team that are committed to creating any aspect of a usable Increment each Sprint.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I Learnt Teaching Agile Software Architecture</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/what-i-learnt-teaching-agile-software-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/what-i-learnt-teaching-agile-software-architecture/</guid>
      <description>I am teaching agile software architecture and techniques SWAT as advanced bachelor level lecture weighted with 3 ECTS.&#xA;I gave this training the last three years at Lucerne University of Applied Sciences and Arts HSLU in Switzerland.&#xA;All materials are released under the Creative Commons copyright.&#xA;The course contents are aligned with the big software architecture programs.&#xA;The Open Group organization is the steward of TOGAF standard. TOGAF is the worldwide industrial standard for enterprise software architecture.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving a Static Web Site Build With Hugo and Docsy</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/improving-a-static-web-site-build-with-hugo-and-docsy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/improving-a-static-web-site-build-with-hugo-and-docsy/</guid>
      <description>The static website build tool Hugo is awesome. With the extensive built-in feature set of Hugo and the feature-rich text formatting options that Asciidoc offers, it creates a blogging experience composed of easy content management and fun writing experience.&#xA;In most static site generators including Hugo, Markdown is the one and only first-class citizen when it comes to creating posts.&#xA;However, in recent Hugo versions, external helpers are an official feature.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scrum Master Formation</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/scrum-master-formation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/scrum-master-formation/</guid>
      <description>You work as a Scrum master.&#xA;Congratulations, working as a professional Scrum master is a fulfilling and exciting job.&#xA;You should attend professional training.&#xA;Not only attend the two-day training to receive a shiny diploma.&#xA;Being a Scrum master and coach is a profession, not a fancy title!&#xA;Please reflect on your goals and ethics.&#xA;Scrum Master Role Here the official definition of the product owner role taken from the Scrum Guide.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DevOps for Small Applications</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/devops-for-small-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/devops-for-small-applications/</guid>
      <description>DevOps is the combination of cultural philosophies, practices and tools that increase an organization’s ability to deliver at high velocity.&#xA;It evolves and improves products at a faster pace than organizations using traditional software development and infrastructure management processes.&#xA;This speed enables organizations to better serve their customers [1, 2].&#xA;A surprising side effect of this speed-up is a documented improvement of the delivered quality.&#xA;How It Works Under a DevOps model, development and operations teams are no longer siloed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Leadership</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/agile-leadership/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/agile-leadership/</guid>
      <description>Everybody is talking about being agile.&#xA;Companies institutionalize agile change programs and send all their collaborators in training to learn the agile way.&#xA;What does that mean?&#xA;How should I as a manager work the agile way?&#xA;Does this agile way exist, or is it simply a fad created by the consulting industry?&#xA;This article provides some pointers and hypotheses what agile leadership could be.&#xA;Feel free to experiment and refine your successful approach to be agile as an organization.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Technical Team Lead</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/technical-team-lead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/technical-team-lead/</guid>
      <description>I lately had to explain to customers what are the responsibilities of a technical team lead. Managers often grasp the people aspects embedded in the words team lead. The understanding of the word technical is strangely often missing.&#xA;A technical team leads coaches and teaches the subtleties of the used technology stack to his team and organization. This person should be able to create or review a software architecture. He has a deep understanding of technological concepts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Enterprise Architecture?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/why-enterprise-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/why-enterprise-architecture/</guid>
      <description>Architecture principles hold true in agile environments. The major difference between older traditional approaches and modern agile ones is the way of performing enterprise architecture.&#xA;The last years have shown a promising evolution of plan-based, centralist enterprise architecture approaches to more agile, decentralized, meritocracy driven processes.&#xA;These new approaches are way more compatible with modern and agile software product development framework such as Scrum, eXtreme Programming, and LeSS&#xA;Traditional processes use dedicated persons or departments to define architecture principles in a top-down approach.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Product Owner Formation</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/product-owner-formation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/product-owner-formation/</guid>
      <description>You are acting as a product owner in your organization.&#xA;Congratulations, working as a professional product owner is a fulfilling and exciting job.&#xA;You should attend professional training.&#xA;Being a product owner and requirements engineer is a profession, not a hobby!&#xA;Formal training is often the difference between being a professional instead of just pretending to be one.&#xA;Product Owner Role Here the official definition of the product owner role taken from the Scrum Guide.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Temporal Aspects of Rolling ERP Planning</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/temporal-aspects-of-rolling-erp-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/temporal-aspects-of-rolling-erp-planning/</guid>
      <description>Agile approaches advocate dynamic planning and adaptation to new inputs and priority changes. The Beyond Budgeting Round Table movement promotes rolling planning, budgeting and reporting.&#xA;The beyond budgeting techniques recommend the complete abolition of traditional budgeting processes. They require the implementation of new techniques that will replace them. The BB framework does not specify the exact techniques that are applicable to all companies.&#xA;However, there are some techniques that have proven to be effective in real cases in the past.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Trends Switzerland 2021</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/agile-trends-switzerland-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/agile-trends-switzerland-2021/</guid>
      <description>As a modern leader, you are aware of the importance of transforming your organization to become more agile. Indeed, you have successfully implemented first steps.&#xA;Trouble is brewing. Things are not moving forward as quickly as they should, especially in the current challenging situation. The leadership behaviour of your colleagues is only changing slowly. Your key developers are grumbling you are faking it.&#xA;Many companies around the world discover their agile transformation is stalling.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on Agile Fluency Model</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/reflections-on-agile-fluency-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/reflections-on-agile-fluency-model/</guid>
      <description>Agile fluency model is a powerful abstraction to better understand your agile transition. It does not matter which flavor of agile you are deploying in your organization; the agile fluency model can be applied in all cases.&#xA;The agile fluency model has a powerful message about agile and technical excellence. The second zone of the model is all about software craftsmanship and eXtreme Programming.&#xA;One key lesson of the fluency model is it takes time until you are professional at your chosen level.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Certified Java Developer</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/certified-java-developer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/certified-java-developer/</guid>
      <description>Java is celebrating 25 years of existence.&#xA;I discovered the anniversary offer to certify for Java SE 11 Developer.&#xA;This special certification has a cool logo with the remainder of the Java 25-year anniversary.&#xA;Oracle offers this certification for only 25 dollars [1] and provides free access to their learning platform.&#xA;The offer and logo availability are time limited.&#xA;The free learning subscription includes:&#xA;The Java Explorer learning path for basic Java skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Trends Switzerland 2020</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/agile-trends-switzerland-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/agile-trends-switzerland-2020/</guid>
      <description>As a modern leader, you are aware of the importance of transforming your organization to become more agile. Indeed, you have successfully implemented first steps.&#xA;Trouble is brewing. Things are not moving forward as quickly as they should, especially in the current challenging situation. The leadership behaviour of your colleagues is only changing slowly. Your key developers are grumbling you are faking it.&#xA;Many companies around the world discover their agile transformation is stalling.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Requirements Engineering</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/agile-requirements-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/agile-requirements-engineering/</guid>
      <description>Lately, I was asked which new approaches should be used for agile requirements engineering. Did we find a new silver bullet to write software specifications the agile way?&#xA;The answer is easy. We do not need new approaches or complicated processes. Start with proven principles and learn.&#xA;Impact Mapping and Story Mapping are successful approaches to identify and prioritize your functions. Specification by Example and User Stories as a discussion allow you to refine your understanding of what your customers need.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Service for Developer Game Changer</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/self-service-for-developer-game-changer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/self-service-for-developer-game-changer/</guid>
      <description>Often, I hear complain that the IT department is not reacting to developer’s needs. They are slow, clumsy and too administrative. Harsher words state they are incompetent.&#xA;I have observed a clear trend in Switzerland since around 2015 to solve these tensions.&#xA;Standard IT services such as docker images, database instances or internal domain names are provided through self-service kiosks.&#xA;What are the advantages of this approach?&#xA;Advantages The advantages to providing a self-service kiosk for users in an academical or industrial environment are:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JDk 16</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/jdk-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/jdk-16/</guid>
      <description>I truly love the new release rhythm of the Java ecosystem. It is awesome to be able to use new features every six months.&#xA;The migration overhead is held to a minimum thanks to incredible backward compatibility.&#xA;The new features greatly simplify the existing code and tremendously increase legibility.&#xA;Features like records, sealed types, or switch expressions are wonderful. The promise of advanced pattern matching constructs is sweet.&#xA;Polishing of functional programming approach improved my source code quite stupendously.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Software Architecture is Mainstream</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/agile-software-architecture-is-mainstream/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/agile-software-architecture-is-mainstream/</guid>
      <description>Slowly, slowly major actors in the software architecture landscape acknowledge agile development is state of the industry approach to building software products.&#xA;They are still struggling to integrate their older views in a faster, iterative, incremental development approach. The duration of a regular Scrum sprint is usually two weeks.&#xA;More important, they have discovered we build products because no customers buy projects. They buy solutions and products.&#xA;I am relieved I need less fight to convince enterprise architects that agile is the way.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MicroStream 4.x</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/microstream-4.x/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/microstream-4.x/</guid>
      <description>MicroStream approach empowers Java developers. The library provides a cool and compact approach to persist complex data models. You can persist your whole data model with less than a hundred lines of code. The library is efficient and works reliably.&#xA;Modern architectures based on bounded domains and Domain Driven Design are supported.&#xA;The company behind the product has promised to open source their product beginning of 2021.&#xA;I use the library to prototype bounded domain implementations requiring persistent data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modern Java Development</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/modern-java-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/modern-java-development/</guid>
      <description>Java development activities have won traction since the decision to release a new version to the community every six months. Preview and incubator features promote feedback from the community and users.&#xA;Some tool builders, such as JetBrains are working proactively and provide support for JDK in developments.&#xA;Other tool maintainers such as JaCoCo are dreadfully behind the release cycle.&#xA;We learnt to deal with the new speed and how to tackle the laggards.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective Working in Digital Age</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/effective-working-in-digital-age/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/effective-working-in-digital-age/</guid>
      <description>Home office is the new way of working. A lot of friends and business partners are working from home. Our meetings are mostly online. We share documents and results through digital platforms.&#xA;I truly hope we continue to work online in the future. I would like to mix home office, local coworking space, and regular office attendance. I am convinced less commute time and a greener approach to work are certainly great improvements.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Is Java Path Class Better?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/why-is-java-path-class-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/why-is-java-path-class-better/</guid>
      <description>Java NIO New Input Output is an alternative IO API for Java, meaning alternative to the standard Java IO and Java Networking APIs.&#xA;Java NIO offers a different IO programming model than the traditional IO APIs.&#xA;One major feature of interest is the support of alternate file systems. An in-memory file system is ideal for test file related operations in unit and integration tests.&#xA;Sometimes NIO is claimed to mean Non-blocking IO.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LeSS Lessons Learnt</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/less-lessons-learnt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/less-lessons-learnt/</guid>
      <description>Scaling Agile, Lean and Scrum to the whole product development department is hard work.&#xA;You start a change journey in murky waters. Best to communicate a lot, strengthen your teams and have total support of upper management.&#xA;Technical agile coaching usefully describes the work I do. Agile coaching helps your business to become more successful, often improve the way you plan and deliver software.&#xA;Technical agile coaching focuses on how people design products, write code and deliver high-quality products.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Software Development for Students</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/software-development-for-students/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/software-development-for-students/</guid>
      <description>Computer science students shall achieve technical excellence when reaching bachelor level. They should be proficient with industry good practices.&#xA;Students understand the theory and principles behind these practices. Experience with one of the best of breed tools enforces learning and automatism.&#xA;The focus of a technical university is to teach the concepts and methods. The tools are used to practice and to increase student learning.&#xA;Source Code Version Management with Git Git is the standard tool for the distributed source code management system.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gitlab for Bachelor Students</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/gitlab-for-bachelor-students/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/gitlab-for-bachelor-students/</guid>
      <description>Computer science students shall be proficient with a basic set of software development techniques.&#xA;Technical excellence is a mandatory skill for all software developers.&#xA;Agile development approaches are state of the industry and used in almost all software development initiatives.&#xA;DevOps approaches are used in modern organizations. They predate agile development approaches.&#xA;Technical schools should provide an in-depth experience in these areas to prepare their students for their future activities after completing their bachelor.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meaningful Identifiers</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/meaningful-identifiers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/meaningful-identifiers/</guid>
      <description>Identifiers are a key concept to successfully model complex business domains. They permeate how our modern civilization functions.&#xA;Could you imagine a country without a car registration number of vehicles, internet addresses, postal addresses or social security numbers?&#xA;Identifiers are identifiers.&#xA;Identifiers cannot be changed at any time.&#xA;Updating identifiers means introducing mapping relations between the old and the new values.&#xA;In computer science, identifiers IDs are lexical tokens that name entities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Value Objects as Embedded Entities</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/value-objects-as-embedded-entities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/value-objects-as-embedded-entities/</guid>
      <description>This post discusses the value object pattern, and the factory pattern, which are tactical patterns in the domain-driven design Domain-Driven Design approach.&#xA;Value objects represent typed values that have no conceptual identity in your domain. They can help you write better codes that are less error-prone, more performant and more expressive.&#xA;Value objects define the second kind of domain objects besides entities. Their main characteristic is immutability:&#xA;Attributes of a value object never change.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Support Comments for Static Hugo Website</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/support-comments-for-static-hugo-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/support-comments-for-static-hugo-website/</guid>
      <description>There are times in software when you are facing a problem, you find an off-the-shelf solution, and a few lines of code later it just works.&#xA;Today I lived one of those moments.&#xA;The whole configuration of comments and modification of the Docsy theme took around one hour.&#xA;Motivation I wanted to add a comment section to this blog for a while. I was reluctant to implement one myself the classical way, using an external service such as disqus.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advocate Zero Bug Policy in Your Projects!</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/advocate-zero-bug-policy-in-your-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/advocate-zero-bug-policy-in-your-projects/</guid>
      <description>At many customer sites I visit, I see a lot of effort being put into classifying and managing bugs.&#xA;Their bug list may contain more than a thousand items. All are neatly documented with screenshots, ways to reproduce the problem and a severity and impact classification. In the worst case, a specialist has worked hard and estimated the effort to correct each of these bugs.&#xA;A change management board meets every few weeks to decide which bugs have a higher priority and should urgently be fixed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Quest for an Agile Company: Five Years tangly llc</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/the-quest-for-an-agile-company-five-years-tangly-llc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/the-quest-for-an-agile-company-five-years-tangly-llc/</guid>
      <description>An agile company is a business with the ability to quickly adapt to market changes [1].&#xA;tangly is an agile and digital development boutique. We must swiftly react to market changes to survive.&#xA;Agility is woven into our culture and processes.&#xA;Agile organizations must be fast-moving and flexible, have rapid response to unexpected obstacles, lead change, be in touch with customers.&#xA;They have a continuous competitive advantage, and a flat organizational structure for quick communication [2].</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reference Codes</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/reference-codes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/reference-codes/</guid>
      <description>Reference codes are an old concept. They are often used in the relational database schema definition as enumeration values. The database specialists often call them lookup tables.&#xA;Reference codes are dynamic enumeration values. By dynamic, we mean you can add values without recompiling the source code.&#xA;In modern DevOps environments where deployment of a new version is performed in minutes, this advantage is somewhat shallow. We view reference codes more as strongly typed and efficient tags.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating a technical Website with Hugo and Asciidoc</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/creating-a-technical-website-with-hugo-and-asciidoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/creating-a-technical-website-with-hugo-and-asciidoc/</guid>
      <description>I hosted my technical blogs on blogger for years.&#xA;If I correctly remember, I started to use blogger ten years ago. It was a good choice at that time.&#xA;I could easily write blogs and publish them.&#xA;It is a great tool with some drawbacks. Over the years, the deficiencies sting more and more&#xA;The major drawbacks are:&#xA;Their editor is brittle, with limited functionality and unreliable. The generated HTML is not legible and does not support concepts such as micro fragments, meta information or simple functions such as source code highlighting.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The power of Tags and Comments</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/the-power-of-tags-and-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/the-power-of-tags-and-comments/</guid>
      <description>A software architect models customer domains and maps them to excellent software constructs. The solution shall support future customer groups and expand to store additional information.&#xA;Tags, also called labels, provide an informal ontology to classify customer data.&#xA;Tags are extensible and are machine-readable.&#xA;Comments empower users to store relevant unstructured information.&#xA;Comments are only for human beings.&#xA;What are good approaches to provide searchable tags and labels and avoid wild growth of useless records?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Entities, Identifiers, External identifiers and Names</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/entities-identifiers-external-identifiers-and-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/entities-identifiers-external-identifiers-and-names/</guid>
      <description>A software architect models customer domains and maps them to powerful software abstractions [1]. Soon you correlate internal efficient identifiers, meaningful external identifiers, and domain entities.&#xA;You enjoy long conversations with the enterprise data architect and identify the system owning a specific external identifier.&#xA;How do you relate to external systems and communicate with other companies?&#xA;How do you define internal identifiers, which grow with application success?&#xA;How can you bridge the customer world with your software solution?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Journey Implementing Digital Invoices</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/a-journey-implementing-digital-invoices/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/a-journey-implementing-digital-invoices/</guid>
      <description>Our company has the ambition to digitize all our workflows since our inception. We proudly state we never bought a printer or a fax machine. Analog machines should become obsolete in the digital age.&#xA;Companies should be more environment-aware and save some trees. See our blog on A Journey to Be a Digital Company.&#xA;Switzerland finally introduced a digital payment slip. It uses a QR code and still assumes you need to print it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Legacy Systems Refactoring</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/legacy-systems-refactoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/legacy-systems-refactoring/</guid>
      <description>In computer programming and software design, code refactoring is the process of restructuring existing computer code without changing its external behavior.&#xA;Refactoring is intended to improve the design, structure, or implementation of the software (its non-functional attributes), while preserving its functionality.&#xA;Using refactoring, you can take bad design, even chaos software and rework it into well-designed code. Most often, it is cheaper to refactoring a legacy application instead of rewriting it from scratch.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gradle 6.4 Finally Supports Java Modules</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/gradle-6.4-finally-supports-java-modules/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/gradle-6.4-finally-supports-java-modules/</guid>
      <description>Java 9 release introduced the concept of modules within the Java language. Java 9 was released in September 2017.&#xA;Until now, creating Java modules was quite cumbersome and Gradle did only offer limited support through external plugins.&#xA;With the release of Gradle 6.4 in May 2020, software developers can finally easily generate well-behaved Java modules. We had to wait almost three years for native support!&#xA;Support for modules is native in the Java plugin.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Component Design</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/agile-component-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/agile-component-design/</guid>
      <description>You are an experienced programmer. You master your primary technology stack and systematically write clean code.&#xA;Your team recognized your merits and asked you to take ownership of whole packages in the application.&#xA;You are now responsible for creating or modifying a software component in your current application.&#xA;This is a design activity.&#xA;How can you create a good, legible, maintainable component architecture?&#xA;How can you validate your functional and non-functional requirements?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java Records Are Here - Available in JDK 14</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/java-records-are-here-available-in-jdk-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/java-records-are-here-available-in-jdk-14/</guid>
      <description>We need justification not to use immutable objects in our solutions, rather than an affirmative reason to use them. Records provide a first-class means for modeling data-only aggregates. They have been available in Java since the release of JDK 14.&#xA;Records are often seen as syntactic sugar to easily create immutable objects without having to write too much boilerplate code. Records as a clean definition of immutable objects can have a tremendous impact on your component design.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Agile Collaborators Learn</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/how-agile-collaborators-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/how-agile-collaborators-learn/</guid>
      <description>Most products are developed by a team, and these achievements are the fruit of teamwork.&#xA;Software product development is now agile, and most often uses the Scrum approach.&#xA;Just putting a bunch of people together in the same open office will not produce a high performance agile team. Quite a few companies find that out the hard way.&#xA;How can you increase the odds to create an environment where agile teams bloom and perform?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Calibrate Your Agile Approach: Bill of Rights</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/calibrate-your-agile-approach-bill-of-rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/calibrate-your-agile-approach-bill-of-rights/</guid>
      <description>When eXtreme Programming first came out, one expectation it worked hard to set is who gets to make what calls on software projects.&#xA;For example, business has the right to know how long something is going to take and when it can expect things to be done.&#xA;Conversely, developers have the right to know what the priorities are, and to be able to do good work.&#xA;To that end, eXtreme Programming created the Customer and Development Team Bill of Rights.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Journey to be a Digital Company - tangly llc</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/a-journey-to-be-a-digital-company-tangly-llc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/a-journey-to-be-a-digital-company-tangly-llc/</guid>
      <description>I long dreamed of working in a digital environment. I shall no longer print out a form, sign it by hand and use snake mail to deliver it to the receiving party. All company documents are stored electronically. I can search any artifacts by content and get a list of all interesting items in seconds.&#xA;Our software service company is an ideal candidate to validate if this assumption is realistic.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile @ Scale</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/agile-@-scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/agile-@-scale/</guid>
      <description>Your organization has decided to introduce agile at scale in all development departments or better in the whole company.&#xA;Your Chief of Agility COA, Chief of Digitalization COD or Chief of Change COC was in an expensive training. After a few drinks, he has selected the appropriate framework for your company.&#xA;Welcome to the club of companies introducing agile approaches and having no clues why they do it and how they could be successful.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Time to Migrate to a Modern JDK, Laggards!</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/time-to-migrate-to-a-modern-jdk-laggards/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/time-to-migrate-to-a-modern-jdk-laggards/</guid>
      <description>Are you still using Java 8 to run your mission-critical systems?&#xA;Are you truly using daily a six years old technology stack?&#xA;Are you already applying for a Java laggard club membership?&#xA;If you are still using Java 8, you are using technologies released in Spring 2014. You are missing all the improvements in the garbage collector, runtime engine, and various APIs.&#xA;Java 11 LTS was released in September 2018.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Commons View on Scrum</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/a-commons-view-on-scrum/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/a-commons-view-on-scrum/</guid>
      <description>Agile approaches encourage common ownership of artifacts during product development. Historically, the commons is the term used for shared resources. Can we apply the commons learnings to agile and Scrum approaches?&#xA;Interestingly, economists were kind to state common ownership is doomed to fail through the theory published at the end of the sixties [1].&#xA;Thirty years later, Elinor Ostrom showed that commons can indeed work well if you follow a small set of rules.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Architecture within Scrum</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/agile-architecture-within-scrum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/agile-architecture-within-scrum/</guid>
      <description>You are applying the agile, lean approach to your software product development. Your teams use Scrum or Kanban to deliver running software every two weeks.&#xA;Agile architecture is a key element to improve the quality of your solution and reduce the overall cycle-time of your product delivery.&#xA;Your journey toward greater business agility starts by identifying what outcomes are most important to your company’s success.&#xA;Outcomes are codified in functional and non-functional requirements your product shall fulfill.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The World is a Better Place and We Must Tackle Climate Change</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/the-world-is-a-better-place-and-we-must-tackle-climate-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/the-world-is-a-better-place-and-we-must-tackle-climate-change/</guid>
      <description>The world has really improved in a lot of areas.&#xA;_Stop whining we are doomed.&#xA;And yes, we must act strong and fast to tackle the climate change disaster._&#xA;Remember how much the world bettered the last centuries.&#xA;We are not doomed, we must solve the next challenges instead of just complaining and doing nothing.&#xA;Ask yourself if you need a car.&#xA;Travel by train instead of flying.&#xA;Schedule a video conference instead of a business trip.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Code is Clean Code!</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/agile-code-is-clean-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/agile-code-is-clean-code/</guid>
      <description>You are applying the agile, lean approach to your software product development.&#xA;Congratulations, you are applying state of the industry good practices.&#xA;Your teams use Scrum or Kanban to deliver running software every two weeks.&#xA;To create an agile architecture, you must write agile worthy code. Agile code is always clean code.&#xA;Start early, do it continuously and soon your code will be clean, legible and free of known defects.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Architecture Principles</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/agile-architecture-principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/agile-architecture-principles/</guid>
      <description>You are applying the agile, lean approach to your software product development. Your teams use Scrum or Kanban to deliver running software every two weeks. The product market introduction is a success. You will successfully sell the solution for the next ten years.&#xA;How shall you define the software architecture of your product and ensure a long living and high-quality solution?&#xA;The experts tell you the design is emergent.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I still love to use a MacBookPro and MacOS in 2019</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/why-i-still-love-to-use-a-macbookpro-and-macos-in-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/why-i-still-love-to-use-a-macbookpro-and-macos-in-2019/</guid>
      <description>As a young developer, I loved Linux, compiled new kernels during evening sessions and struggled days to have the correct drivers for the graphic card and communication components of my notebook.&#xA;I grew older and decided to enjoy my weekends, family and outdoor activities.&#xA;And surely I shall have no virus, trojan and other evils in my workstation. So I went to macOS and Apple notebooks without regrets.&#xA;Gains The major gains using macOS are</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Code Scene as Crime Scene</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/code-scene-as-crime-scene/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/code-scene-as-crime-scene/</guid>
      <description>You have a successful product and happy users. Slowly, the cost of adding new features is creeping up and product margins are shrinking. Which crimes did put us in this dreaded situation?&#xA;How can you analyze the history of your product’s source code?&#xA;How can you explore the social dimension of your product development? How can you find good approaches to increase time to market and improve development costs?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You Need an Engineering Culture</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/you-need-an-engineering-culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/you-need-an-engineering-culture/</guid>
      <description>Agile approaches are not enough. You need a strong engineering culture to achieve quality and lasting success.&#xA;Often, coaches and Scrum masters tinker with the processes and invest effort and blood to improve the ceremonies and the company structure.&#xA;But at the end of the day, the success of your application is defined by its adequacy to customer needs and its overall quality. You need a solid and professional engineering culture to produce high-quality products and release them at a high rate.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Healthy is Your Product? - Company Culture Check</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/how-healthy-is-your-product-company-culture-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/how-healthy-is-your-product-company-culture-check/</guid>
      <description>You are developing your application using agile and lean approaches.&#xA;How can you check your approach and distill improvements?&#xA;Health check of your product and your development approach are certainly a good solution.&#xA;This post is the fourth and last of a set of articles identifying health checks with different focus.&#xA;We will identify strengths, potential weaknesses and hopefully find room for improvement.&#xA;What is your company culture?&#xA;How are collaborators focused on delighting your customers?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Detecting Agile Bullshit</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/detecting-agile-bullshit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/detecting-agile-bullshit/</guid>
      <description>The Defense Innovation Board DIB advises the secretary of defense of the United States of America.&#xA;Members of the board are recognizable names like Eric Schmidt who was CEO of Google and Alphabet, or Instagram COO Marne Levine.&#xA;So I was quite surprised that a government committee was so straightforward to publish a document called Detecting Agile Bullshit [1].&#xA;Simple questions are used as a bullshit detector to identify organizations faking agile.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Healthy is Your Product? - Product Strategy Check</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/how-healthy-is-your-product-product-strategy-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/how-healthy-is-your-product-product-strategy-check/</guid>
      <description>You are developing your product using agile and lean approaches.&#xA;How can you check your approach and distill improvements?&#xA;Health check of your product and your development approach are certainly a good solution.&#xA;This post is the third of a set of articles identifying health checks with different focus. We will identify strengths, potential weaknesses and hopefully find room for improvement.&#xA;What is your product strategy? How do you involve your customers and stakeholders?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SAFE 4.6: Improvements Direly Needed</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/safe-4.6-improvements-direly-needed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/safe-4.6-improvements-direly-needed/</guid>
      <description>It is official.&#xA;The power engine of the SAFe 4.6 vehicle is the team and technical agility. View the SAFe for more information [1].&#xA;It is one of their five Lean Enterprise competencies and one of their four core values. SAFe finally recognizes the tremendous importance of technical proficiency and craftsmanship.&#xA;They advocate two findings. First, you need team agility, how you apply Scrum or Kanban.&#xA;In other words, being agile instead of doing agile.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Healthy is Your Product? - Delivery Pipeline Check</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/how-healthy-is-your-product-delivery-pipeline-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/how-healthy-is-your-product-delivery-pipeline-check/</guid>
      <description>You are developing your product using agile and lean approaches.&#xA;How can you check your approach and distill improvements? A health check of your product and your development approach is certainly a good solution.&#xA;This post is the second of a series identifying health checks with different focus. We will identify strengths, potential weaknesses and hopefully find room for improvement.&#xA;How you build and deliver your software product has direct implications on your liquidity and cash flow.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Should You handle Definition of Done?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/how-should-you-handle-definition-of-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/how-should-you-handle-definition-of-done/</guid>
      <description>An agile team is the sole responsible for the internal quality of the product they build and maintain.&#xA;The developers shall be accountable for producing the expected quality and optimizing long term goals of the organization.&#xA;You as a developer have an ethical, professional and legal responsibility to ensure adequate quality for your products.&#xA;Laws protect the confidentiality of their personal and financial data.&#xA;It is a potential crime to leak credit card information, geolocation data or the worst personal documents.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Healthy is Your Product? - Source Code Check</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/how-healthy-is-your-product-source-code-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/how-healthy-is-your-product-source-code-check/</guid>
      <description>You are developing your product using agile and lean approaches.&#xA;How can you check your approach and distill improvements? Health check of your product and your development approach are certainly a good solution.&#xA;This post is the first of a series identifying health checks with different focus. We will identify strengths, potential weaknesses and hopefully find room for improvement.&#xA;The initial examination shall always be the source code. Your code base is a key asset of your company.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduce Agile in A Company</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/introduce-agile-in-a-company/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/introduce-agile-in-a-company/</guid>
      <description>First teams have successfully used Scrum to develop applications. The news spread out and everybody wants to apply Scrum. It is time to introduce enterprise-wide Agile with Scrum or Kanban or XP.&#xA;Your Company wants to introduce Enterprise Agility in their product development, quality assurance and sales departments. The company as a whole shall transition to an agile organization and all teams shall adopt Scrum.&#xA;Try the Shu Ha Ri approach for such a change process.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What does an Agile Coach?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/what-does-an-agile-coach/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/what-does-an-agile-coach/</guid>
      <description>An agile coach has three main areas of activity:&#xA;Foster Autonomy Teach and support the team and individuals to be autonomous within the given boundaries of the organization and its processes.&#xA;Create Ground for Motivation Help teams to maximize their autonomy, individual mastery and make sure the team has a purpose.&#xA;Provide Coaching Support teams and individuals to identify potential with their roles and within the agile organization and improve.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Architectural Decision Records ADR</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/architectural-decision-records-adr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/architectural-decision-records-adr/</guid>
      <description>Architecture Decision Record ADR is compact and traceable documents of all important decisions taken during the realization of a product. Use Asciidoc or Markdown and Git to have agile and lean documentation of your major decisions.&#xA;The huge advantage of Architecture Design Record ADR is the timeline of the decisions. It tremendously helps to understand the technical changes during the product lifecycle.&#xA;Please try architecture design records to document your key decisions when developing your software product.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Reach the Software Quality Graal?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/how-to-reach-the-software-quality-graal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/how-to-reach-the-software-quality-graal/</guid>
      <description>Lately I was asked how many bugs and smells detected through SonarQube were acceptable for a software product. And a Scrum master inquired which organizational changes are necessary to empower software developers to write good code. Speechless and dumbfounded, I was unable to answer these questions.&#xA;After some time, I realized these people believe tools can measure the quality of software. But tools can only measure non-quality.&#xA;They tell you when you are doing it wrong, only your heart can tell you when you are doing it right.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Trends Switzerland 2018</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/agile-trends-switzerland-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/agile-trends-switzerland-2018/</guid>
      <description>What are the main hurdles to introducing agile approaches in Swiss companies? The Swiss agile trends report was published for the last ten years and learn us the difficulties and successes of agile transformations.&#xA;SwissQ has published a &amp;#34;SwissQ Software Development Switzerland 2018&amp;#34;, the tenth version of this report.&#xA;Introducing agile company-wide was and is a cultural change process. Such a change takes time and sometimes hurts. Too often, organizations stop the process and revert to all command and control approaches with Waterfall product management.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sonar Lint for the Impatient</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/sonar-lint-for-the-impatient/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/sonar-lint-for-the-impatient/</guid>
      <description>Remove issues before they reach customer sites. No quality problems shall reach your Git master branch.&#xA;SonarQube is a central server that processes full analyses (triggered by the various SonarQube Scanners).&#xA;Its purpose is to give a 360° vision about the quality of your code base. For this, it analyzes all the source lines of your product on a regular basis.&#xA;It should be added that SonarQube also performs scans with well-known third party analyzers (SpotBugs - previously FindBugs -, Checkstyle, PMD) whereas SonarLint does not include those.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Introduction Success Criteria through the LeSS Lens</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/agile-introduction-success-criteria-through-the-less-lens/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/agile-introduction-success-criteria-through-the-less-lens/</guid>
      <description>An agile organization is able to deliver or change her direction at any time without additional cost.&#xA;More companies want to become truly agile and book an expensive journey to the holy land of agility. Often travelers never reach their true destination.&#xA;The LeSS people have a clear set of conditions to increase the odds.&#xA;All my experiences confirm these conditions are essential for success.&#xA;LeSS Criteria Use these criteria as a checklist to evaluate your current agile transformation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pragmatic Craftsmanship - Professional Software Developer</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/pragmatic-craftsmanship-professional-software-developer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/pragmatic-craftsmanship-professional-software-developer/</guid>
      <description>The last months I was often confronted with software products having insufficient quality.&#xA;Insufficient means late delivery, and few new features. The effort to correct errors in the field eats 30% to 50% away from the development budget. How can such a dreadful situation occur?&#xA;One root cause is the low quality of the source code and ignorance of basic coding design approaches.&#xA;We are not talking about complex design activities or complex patterns; we are discussing basic approaches how to write correct and maintainable code.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Do You Need Metrics and KPI in Agile Product Development?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/why-do-you-need-metrics-and-kpi-in-agile-product-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/why-do-you-need-metrics-and-kpi-in-agile-product-development/</guid>
      <description>Why do we define metrics and KPI?&#xA;First, we want to find out how good the build-in quality of our software artifacts is.&#xA;Second, we want to improve the build-in quality through experiments and use the metrics to judge the success of these experiments.&#xA;And the Key Performance Indicators KPI provide plausibility checks by qualifying the intrinsic quality of software artifacts against quantifiable strategic objectives.&#xA;Measurements shall be cheap to gather and as much as possible generated automatically through the tooling landscape.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile GIS Open Data Initiative</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/agile-gis-open-data-initiative/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/agile-gis-open-data-initiative/</guid>
      <description>How can agile approaches be applied to deliver solutions in a government environment?&#xA;Here is an example of a GIS open data portal successfully developed using agile approaches such as Kanban, lean product and technical excellence.&#xA;GIS Open Data Initiative The Swiss government has initiated an open government data strategy to provide data at federal and state level to all citizens and interested parties. The aims are&#xA;Release of official data The Confederation will make data which are suitable for OGD available to the public in machine-readable and open formats to be freely reused.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java 10 aka 18.3 Changes</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/java-10-aka-18.3-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/java-10-aka-18.3-changes/</guid>
      <description>Oracle has decided to release a new JDK two times a year.&#xA;The next release of Java 10 aka 18.3 will be available in March 2018.&#xA;JDK 11 aka 18.9 will be released in September 2018. Java 11 will also be a long-term support LTS release.&#xA;For Java to remain competitive, it must not just continue to move forward — it must move forward faster.&#xA;— Mark Reinhold The Visible Change The visible change is the dawn of the keyword var.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Six Levers for better Agile Product Development</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/six-levers-for-better-agile-product-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/six-levers-for-better-agile-product-development/</guid>
      <description>How can you create better products and services?&#xA;How can you delight your customers, your collaborators, and your stakeholders?&#xA;We identified six levers to multiply the effectivity of your agile development teams and empower them to create great services and products.&#xA;Please add these tools to your toolbox and create great products.&#xA;Design Thinking and Customer Experience You solve customer problems through intuitive services and products. Customer expectations should fit with their experience with your products.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scrum Guide 2017: What changed?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/scrum-guide-2017-what-changed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/scrum-guide-2017-what-changed/</guid>
      <description>The Scrum guide was revised in 2016 and got clarification concerning the core values. I was thrilled. Talking about values and mental models, you must have to successfully introduce and be agile is awesome.&#xA;A new revision was published at the end of year 2017, just a year after the addition of values.&#xA;What has changed?&#xA;What has the community learnt and committed to the new version of the guide?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One Way to Improve Your Scrum Approach</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/one-way-to-improve-your-scrum-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/one-way-to-improve-your-scrum-approach/</guid>
      <description>You work using agile and lean approaches. Your collaborators are trained how to use agile principles.&#xA;Techniques such as test-driven development, continuous integration, DevOps or clean code are regularly practiced.&#xA;Your teams reduce their technical debt and deliver regularly stable product increments.&#xA;Now you are looking for the next improvement. How can your team improve your product and increase customer value?&#xA;It is time for a fresh view.&#xA;Perform an agile assessment with an external expert from another company or department.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why is it so Cool to Develop with Java?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/why-is-it-so-cool-to-develop-with-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/why-is-it-so-cool-to-develop-with-java/</guid>
      <description>Why is it so cool to develop software using Java, a modern IDE and agile tools?&#xA;Because the environment empowers you and incredibly speed-up your development outcomes. In seconds, you know if the next code increment adds value to your product.&#xA;Test driven development and static quality tools are integrated in your IDE. Each time you check some code into your Git repository, all configured checks shall be executed before allowing the commit.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Use Current Software Components?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/why-use-current-software-components/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/why-use-current-software-components/</guid>
      <description>Often, teams discuss if their digital product should upgrade to the current version of open-source or commercial used components.&#xA;The same discussion arises for development tools and programming language versions.&#xA;I have a strong opinion about upgrades. You should always use the current version of all components included in your product. The only discussion is the timely when and never the if.&#xA;Be realist, if your product is successful, you have to upgrade before the components are obsolete.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clean Your Desk and Define New Year Improvements</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/clean-your-desk-and-define-new-year-improvements/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/clean-your-desk-and-define-new-year-improvements/</guid>
      <description>It is Christmastime.&#xA;Clean your desk and the content of your workstation. Upgrade your tools and your development environment to the actual version.&#xA;It is time to add automated build pipelines, TDD, ATDD, and Docker to your toolbox. Embrace agile approaches.&#xA;Work focused and avoid overtime. Prioritize outcomes instead of outputs. Enjoy family life, practice sport, and pursue continuous training.&#xA;Clean Your Desk Digitalize Your Office It is time to sell the last fax device in your office and plan to remove your big printer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impediment List is of Tremendous Importance</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/impediment-list-is-of-tremendous-importance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/impediment-list-is-of-tremendous-importance/</guid>
      <description>An impediment is any aspect hindering the team or a company to deliver value and higher quality to the customers.&#xA;An agile organization continuously removes impediments. It is one of her major activities. This activity is ongoing and can never be completed.&#xA;Impediments resolution is Kaizen 改善, a key technique to lean, agile and Scrum approaches. The translation is change for better.&#xA;Often agile organizations forget to aggressively identify and resolve impediments.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Approaches and Fix Price Contracts</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/agile-approaches-and-fix-price-contracts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/agile-approaches-and-fix-price-contracts/</guid>
      <description>The difficulty with contracts is that it is about trust. Here lays the roots for success or disaster.&#xA;If no trust exists, the henceforth dreaded process is established. After tough negotiations, the development team starts but does not collaborate with the customer. They just build what is written in outdated requirements. A subpar solution is shipped and the relationship with the customer is deeply damaged.&#xA;We can do better. We shall collaborate, trust each other and create an awesome product.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your Management Job in an Agile Environment</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/your-management-job-in-an-agile-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/your-management-job-in-an-agile-environment/</guid>
      <description>You develop your software products using agile approaches. You are doing Scrum, Kanban, Scrumban, Lean Software Development, or LeSS.&#xA;Your collaborators start asking questions about their organization, management roles, and critique the internal processes.&#xA;How employee yearly evaluation, bonus evaluation – work? You hear strange statements such Be agile, do not do agile.&#xA;You as a manager realize you have to describe your role in an agile environment. What does it mean?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scrum Masters are not Administrators</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/scrum-masters-are-not-administrators/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/scrum-masters-are-not-administrators/</guid>
      <description>Readers know I am an early adopter of agile and Scrum approaches.&#xA;I experienced how much more effective and fun it is to work in an agile team developing digital products.&#xA;Lately I was asked if I was interested in working as a Scrum master [1, 2, 3].&#xA;The job description below was handed me over. What an experience it was.&#xA;The text with the regular font is the job description.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What does a Scrum Master?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/what-does-a-scrum-master/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/what-does-a-scrum-master/</guid>
      <description>What does a Scrum master the whole day?&#xA;Are you just a fancy administrator or are you actively removing impediments?&#xA;Do you coach your teams toward mastery?&#xA;Too often, Scrum masters become Scrum administrators.&#xA;They schedule meetings, moderate discussions, write progress reports and draw beautiful slides how to improve the organization.&#xA;Or worst, they collect extensive statistics about velocity, planned versus delivered story points or how precise story estimation was.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>So Called Agile and Scrum Failures</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/so-called-agile-and-scrum-failures/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/so-called-agile-and-scrum-failures/</guid>
      <description>Agile will never guarantee product success.&#xA;All projects, especially application development, entail risk.&#xA;If a product was risk-free, it is unlikely to provide significant benefits or competitive advantages.&#xA;There are a number of ways in which Agile Scrum projects repeatedly fail which are worth examining.&#xA;Agile approaches and Scrum framework can reduce risks in projects and increase the return on investment. Standish Group report is a proof of this statement.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Git Local Repositories for the Impatient</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/git-local-repositories-for-the-impatient/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/git-local-repositories-for-the-impatient/</guid>
      <description>You shall put your source code and text documentation under a version management system.&#xA;The actual industrial standard for version control systems is git, a distributed version control system - DVCS -. It tracks changes in any set of computer files, usually used for coordinating work among programmers who are collaboratively developing source code during software development.&#xA;Subversion was a great tool and should now be retired. Simple refactoring activities with renaming will already corrupt a subversion repository.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is Our Specialty as Agile Coaches at tangly?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/what-is-our-specialty-as-agile-coaches-at-tangly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/what-is-our-specialty-as-agile-coaches-at-tangly/</guid>
      <description>You have more agile coaches on the market than sand-corns on a regular beach.&#xA;They all promise the holly grail of agile product development, highly productive teams and perfect applications for internal and external customers.&#xA;Why should any sane customer hire us to deploy or perfect their agile approach?&#xA;Your overall goal is to continuously improve the products delivered to customers.&#xA;I am convinced to achieve ingrained success an agile coach shall:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Trends Switzerland 2017: We Won</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/agile-trends-switzerland-2017-we-won/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/agile-trends-switzerland-2017-we-won/</guid>
      <description>It is time to throw a big party in Switzerland. More than 60% of all projects are now realized using an agile approach (to see Agile Trends in Switzerland 2017] by SwissQ [1]. Scrum being the most popular one, Kanban as the second one. What a change in just one year. In 2016, we had 40% of projects being agile, one year later we have 60%. Time to adapt and become agile.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fun at Workplace</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/fun-at-workplace/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/fun-at-workplace/</guid>
      <description>It is Spring in Switzerland. We often have time for small talk because it is cold or rainy outside.&#xA;Quite a few of the discussions are about job opportunities, and how interesting and motivating the current activities are.&#xA;I selected two articles to help everybody to decide if your software development job is worth the effort.&#xA;Go through the questions and ask yourself if the current product provides the current settings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>List of Agile and Lean Books for Software Engineers or Students</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/list-of-agile-and-lean-books-for-software-engineers-or-students/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/list-of-agile-and-lean-books-for-software-engineers-or-students/</guid>
      <description>I am regularly asked by practitioners and technical universities, which books I shall recommend learning more about agile developers, agile projects, and agile companies.&#xA;Reading is a great way to learn and to get new ideas.&#xA;Below, a selection of books I read and found fascinating.&#xA;The selection is certainly not exhaustive.&#xA;The criteria are&#xA;I read the book and learnt something.&#xA;I have bought this book to have it as a reference.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Trends Switzerland 2016</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/agile-trends-switzerland-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/agile-trends-switzerland-2016/</guid>
      <description>What are the main hurdles to introducing agile approaches in Swiss companies? The last five years learn us that:&#xA;Introducing agile company-wide is a cultural change process. Such a change takes time and sometimes hurts.&#xA;Without the commitment of senior management, the initiative will fail.&#xA;You must teach, coach, support your collaborators through the transition. You need to believe in them and provide an environment where they can safely learn and experiment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seven Pitfalls with Agile or Scrum Methods</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/seven-pitfalls-with-agile-or-scrum-methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/seven-pitfalls-with-agile-or-scrum-methods/</guid>
      <description>The post describes a presentation I gave at a company internal technical day. It reflects situations we have seen in a lot of agile projects over the last years.&#xA;I assume that the Scrum approach is well introduced in your company.&#xA;You are already proficient with Scrum, eXtreme Programming, Clean Code, Code Refactoring, how to write stories and story maps, and techniques such as TDD, ATDD.&#xA;You are using Scrum well and can laugh about all these posts about Scrum-But(t).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What you do NOT need to do in Scrum!</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/what-you-do-not-need-to-do-in-scrum/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/what-you-do-not-need-to-do-in-scrum/</guid>
      <description>I often hear discussions asking who is performing the traditional product leader tasks in Scrum.&#xA;This is in general an excuse to state that Scrum alone cannot work and classical product leaders are still needed.&#xA;I encourage you to classify these so-called regular product manager activities. Often these jobs are plain reporting progress to various boards and micromanaging the development team.&#xA;I truly acknowledge the importance and value of a line manager caring for his collaborators and nurturing the success of the products they develop.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Found a Limited Liability Company in Switzerland</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/found-a-limited-liability-company-in-switzerland/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/found-a-limited-liability-company-in-switzerland/</guid>
      <description>I left the company I founded 20 years ago and needed a new home to work and have access to social insurance.&#xA;The best legal construct in Switzerland and in Europe is to establish a limited liability company.&#xA;You need such a construct in Switzerland to work as a software specialist. The legal Swiss institutions, such as taxes, social insurances, and accident insurances are challenging and almost unfair with freelancers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is an Agile Company?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/what-is-an-agile-company/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/what-is-an-agile-company/</guid>
      <description>Lately, people often ask me what is an agile company.&#xA;They have an understanding of agile software development techniques such as Scrum, Lean Software Development, Kanban, eXtreme Programming but no clue how a company could be agile.&#xA;What does it mean to be an agile organization?&#xA;One way to approach this theme is to implement concepts of the above-mentioned agile approaches.&#xA;These are the pillars for iterative incremental improvements.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Trends Switzerland 2013</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/agile-trends-switzerland-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/agile-trends-switzerland-2013/</guid>
      <description>What are the main hurdles to introducing agile approaches in Swiss companies?&#xA;Introducing agile company-wide is a cultural change process. Such a change takes time and sometimes hurts.&#xA;Without the commitment of senior management, the initiative will fail.&#xA;Doubt that lean or agile works for big projects, doubt you can convince your collaborators and middle management, doubt your customers agree with lean,&#xA;In the end, what matters are collaborator purpose, customer satisfaction, business value.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Trends Switzerland 2012</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/agile-trends-switzerland-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/agile-trends-switzerland-2012/</guid>
      <description>What are the main hurdles to introducing agile approaches in Swiss companies?&#xA;Introducing agile company-wide is a cultural change process. Such a change takes time and sometimes hurts.&#xA;Without the commitment of senior management, the initiative will fail.&#xA;Doubt that lean or agile works, doubt you can find agile experts, doubt that your projects can be realised with agile approaches.&#xA;In the end, what matters are collaborator purpose, customer satisfaction, business value.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Git Branches for the Impatient</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/git-branches-for-the-impatient/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/git-branches-for-the-impatient/</guid>
      <description>You are working in a small mostly collocated development team. Sometimes a team member works from a remote location.&#xA;You have one git repository accessible to all team members.&#xA;This repository is used to share source code and documentation artifacts.&#xA;You use the actual industrial standard for version control systems is git.&#xA;You decided to use branches to implement new features or fix errors instead of using Trunk-Based Development.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Version of the Scrum Guide 2011</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/the-version-of-the-scrum-guide-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/the-version-of-the-scrum-guide-2011/</guid>
      <description>The new version of the Scrum Guide written by Ken Schwaber and Jeff Sutherland has been available since July 2011.&#xA;You should regularly read the Scrum guide to reflect how your teams are applying agile principles and ideas.&#xA;You should also consult the seminal Agile Manifesto and the 12 Agile Manifesto Principles.&#xA;The older version was published in May 2009.&#xA;I found quite interesting the precision of the Scrum Master’s responsibility.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scrum Master is a full-time Role</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/scrum-master-is-a-full-time-role/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/scrum-master-is-a-full-time-role/</guid>
      <description>I am very happy we discuss in depth the role, responsibilities and activities of a good Scrum Master. I fully agree with Scrum advocates that Scrum Master is a dedicated full-time job.&#xA;I am also convinced a Scrum Master can support multiple experienced Scrum teams. The Large Scale Scrum framework LeSS states a full-time Scrum Master supports 1 to 3 teams.&#xA;I worked with quite a few Scrum Masters, Product Owners, and Scrum teams.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Books for Persons interested in Agile Approaches</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/books-for-persons-interested-in-agile-approaches/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/books-for-persons-interested-in-agile-approaches/</guid>
      <description>I am often told that it is difficult to use Agile/Scrum approaches for brown field projects or for big projects or for distributed projects or for in other situations.&#xA;Interestingly, these people also state that the same problems exist with traditional approaches such as RUP/OpenUP, Waterfall Model, V Model defined as a formal standard in Germany V-Modell Entwicklungsstandard, and the Swiss variant called HERMES.&#xA;Agile approaches are currently the standard for new projects and are thought in technical universities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PMI-ACP Certification</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/pmi-acp-certification/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/pmi-acp-certification/</guid>
      <description>Unknown reference: lean-agile-software-develpment I learnt quite a few new acronyms and techniques when studying for the PMI-ACP certification program. In this post, I collected these acronyms, some definition and the bibliography you should know before attending the examination.&#xA;The main advantage of having it is that you no longer need to argue with PMI certified product managers if agile is applicable to software projects.&#xA;The main interest of PMI-ACP certification is their collection of concepts taken from Agile, eXtreme Programming, Scrum and Lean.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I use a MacBookPro and OS X</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/why-i-use-a-macbookpro-and-os-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/why-i-use-a-macbookpro-and-os-x/</guid>
      <description>I loved Linux as a young developer. I compiled new kernels during evening sessions. I worked hard to install and configure drivers to support the hardware I had bought.&#xA;I explored forums and talked with technical support specialists to activate hardware or support the resolution of my display. I struggled days to have the correct drivers for the graphic card and communication components of my notebook.&#xA;I grew older and decided to enjoy my evenings and weekends with my family and friends.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Agile Methods - Scrum - Motivate your Team?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/do-agile-methods-scrum-motivate-your-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/do-agile-methods-scrum-motivate-your-team/</guid>
      <description>Decision makers and waterfall aficionados loudly ask if agile approaches are worth the hype.&#xA;Does the approach really promote team work?&#xA;Well, my current experience is that the answer is a sounding YES.&#xA;Developers love to develop software products using Scrum. The motivation and positive energy just explode.&#xA;People talk together, build as a team better products and enjoy the daily activities.&#xA;Stakeholders and customers or users embrace the advantages they get.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minimizing Undone Work when Working with Regulatory Departments</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/minimizing-undone-work-when-working-with-regulatory-departments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/minimizing-undone-work-when-working-with-regulatory-departments/</guid>
      <description>The Scrum and agile mantra is to have a ready-to-ship product each time a sprint is completed. You must avoid any incomplete activities at any price.&#xA;Incomplete activities are also called Undone Work. They are technical debts in your software, hindering its delivery to users. They are expended money you cannot invoice to your customers.&#xA;Regulatory and traditional quality insurance departments request all kinds of documents, such as review, test results, risk analysis matrix.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/dev/developmentapproach/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/dev/developmentapproach/</guid>
      <description>Development Approach Introduction Values Architecture Decisions Architecture Decisions shall be documented to provide causality and an audit trade why the current solution was chosen. The evolution of architecture and the history of decisions is of tremendous importance to understand the trade-offs built into the solution.&#xA;Architecture design records ADR is a promising approach to documenting the evolution of a solution architecture.&#xA;Specifications As a user, I want to have all architecture decisions of a component to understand the tradeoffs of the current solution.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/fsm/examples/fsm-bbv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/fsm/examples/fsm-bbv/</guid>
      <description>fsm-bbv States Name Context Description Final Initial Composite Entry Action Exit Action Root&#xA;-&#xA;true&#xA;true&#xA;true&#xA;-&#xA;-&#xA;Off&#xA;Root&#xA;false&#xA;true&#xA;false&#xA;Entry action of Off state&#xA;ExitOffstate&#xA;Maintenance&#xA;Root&#xA;false&#xA;false&#xA;false&#xA;On&#xA;Root&#xA;false&#xA;false&#xA;true&#xA;FM&#xA;On&#xA;false&#xA;false&#xA;true&#xA;entryFM&#xA;exitFM&#xA;DAB&#xA;On&#xA;false&#xA;true&#xA;false&#xA;Play&#xA;FM&#xA;false&#xA;true&#xA;false&#xA;entryPlay&#xA;exitPlay&#xA;AutoTune&#xA;FM&#xA;false&#xA;false&#xA;false&#xA;fsm-bbv Transitions Start State End State Description Local Guard Action Off</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/fsm/examples/fsm-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/fsm/examples/fsm-test/</guid>
      <description>fsm-test States Name Context Description Final Initial Composite Entry Action Exit Action Root&#xA;-&#xA;true&#xA;true&#xA;true&#xA;-&#xA;-&#xA;A&#xA;Root&#xA;State A&#xA;false&#xA;true&#xA;true&#xA;-&#xA;-&#xA;AA&#xA;A&#xA;State AA&#xA;false&#xA;true&#xA;false&#xA;-&#xA;-&#xA;AB&#xA;A&#xA;State AB&#xA;false&#xA;false&#xA;false&#xA;-&#xA;-&#xA;B&#xA;Root&#xA;false&#xA;false&#xA;true&#xA;-&#xA;-&#xA;BA&#xA;B&#xA;State BA&#xA;false&#xA;false&#xA;false&#xA;-&#xA;-&#xA;BB&#xA;B&#xA;State BB&#xA;false&#xA;true&#xA;false</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/fsm/examples/fsm-washer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/fsm/examples/fsm-washer/</guid>
      <description>fsm-washer States Name Context Description Final Initial Composite Entry Action Exit Action Root&#xA;-&#xA;true&#xA;true&#xA;true&#xA;-&#xA;-&#xA;Running&#xA;Root&#xA;Running State&#xA;false&#xA;true&#xA;true&#xA;-&#xA;-&#xA;End&#xA;Root&#xA;State End&#xA;true&#xA;false&#xA;false&#xA;-&#xA;-&#xA;Washing&#xA;Running&#xA;Washing State&#xA;false&#xA;true&#xA;false&#xA;-&#xA;-&#xA;Rinsing&#xA;Running&#xA;Rising State&#xA;false&#xA;false&#xA;false&#xA;-&#xA;-&#xA;Drying&#xA;Running&#xA;Drying State&#xA;true&#xA;false&#xA;false&#xA;-&#xA;-&#xA;PowerOff&#xA;Root&#xA;PowerOff State&#xA;false</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
