<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CRM - CRM Bounded Domain on tangly Components</title>
    <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/crm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CRM - CRM Bounded Domain on tangly Components</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/crm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Readme</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/crm/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/crm/readme/</guid>
      <description>Purpose The tangly erp crm bounded domain component provides regular business model abstractions for business applications written in Java. The component is using records and requires Java 21 LTS or higher.&#xA;Try it out.&#xA;Download and Documentation The library can be included in Maven as&#xA;&amp;lt;dependency&amp;gt; &amp;lt;groupId&amp;gt;net.tangly.erp&amp;lt;/groupId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;artifactId&amp;gt;crm&amp;lt;/artifactId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;version&amp;gt;0.2.8&amp;lt;/version&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/dependency&amp;gt; The library can be included in Gradle as&#xA;implementation &amp;#34;net.tangly.erp:crm:0.2.8&amp;#34; The documentation can be found under Business documentation.&#xA;For any further questions, you can use the forum tangly-Discussions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Release Notes</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/crm/releasesnotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/crm/releasesnotes/</guid>
      <description>ERP CRM Library Change Logs This document provides a high-level view of the changes introduced in the ERP CRM library by release. For a detailed view of what has changed, refer to the repository commits.&#xA;0.2.8 (2024-09-30) 0.2.7 (2024-05-31) Update of library dependencies, update to JDK-21, and modern Gradle approach to build solutions.&#xA;Fix: photo of a natural entity is persisted and displayed without distortions.&#xA;Fix: analytics diagrams display correctly upon initial import of data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bounded Domain CRM Model</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/crm/models/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/domains/crm/models/</guid>
      <description>Bounded Domain CRM Context The bounded domain contextCRM implements&#xA;The core domain Customer Relationship Management&#xA;It uses the shared kernel Core providing core abstractions to modeling&#xA;Bounded Domain Workflow The workflows describe the regular activities a service company has with their contacts and customers.&#xA;Table 1. CRM Workflows ID Description CRM-001&#xA;As a salesperson I want to create and modify a legal entity so that I have a record of every organization my company is working with.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
