<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Agile on tangly Components</title>
    <link>https://blog.tangly.net/tags/agile/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Agile on tangly Components</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.tangly.net/tags/agile/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Document Your Agile Architecture</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/document-your-agile-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/document-your-agile-architecture/</guid>
      <description>The overwhelming success of agile approaches to create digital products has implications on our work techniques.&#xA;Design emerges. The team learns incrementally and refines the solution [1].&#xA;Agile architecture is a collaborative and iterative process.&#xA;Agile methods do not require comprehensive documentation at the beginning. Managers do not need to plan months in advance because things can change as the project evolves.&#xA;The idea is to produce documentation with information that is essential to move forward when it makes the most sense.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daily Scrum Questions</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/daily-scrum-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/daily-scrum-questions/</guid>
      <description>The daily Scrum meeting is a key event for the development team.&#xA;It is a time-boxed event of maximum 15 minutes.&#xA;The developers find out if the Sprint Goal is still achievable and what are the identified impediments to be tackled.&#xA;Often the collaborators use the meeting to synchronize their work and to plan the day.&#xA;It is a great opportunity to ask questions and to learn from each other.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Document Your Software Architecture</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/how-to-document-your-software-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/how-to-document-your-software-architecture/</guid>
      <description>You are creating the next digital software masterpiece.&#xA;How can you document your software architecture in a way that is useful for your team and stakeholders?&#xA;A software architecture document SAD is a document that describes the structure of a software solution.&#xA;It includes the architecture of its components, the relationships between those components, and the principles that guide its design.&#xA;The solution architecture document is typically used as a reference for designing, building, and maintaining a software system.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modern Java Rant</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/modern-java-rant/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/modern-java-rant/</guid>
      <description>The Java community releases a new version every six months. This is a good thing, it means that the language is evolving at a steady pace.&#xA;New language features are added in each release. Much effort is put into improving the performance of the JVM and solving small issues.&#xA;The community provides beta releases for developers to test and provide feedback during the six months before the next release. You have the possibility and time to migrate and test your code before the official release.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How To Improve</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/how-to-improve/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/how-to-improve/</guid>
      <description>You attended a famous or a local technical school. You are the proud owner of a bachelor or a master degree in science.&#xA;You are a certified engineer.&#xA;You are now a full-time software developer. You write daily productive code with your colleagues in your current company.&#xA;Hopefully you studied software engineering at least as a minor.&#xA;How can you continuously improve in your profession?&#xA;How can you become proficient in the new features and possibilities of the technologies you use daily?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Quest for an Agile Company: Eight Years tangly llc</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/the-quest-for-an-agile-company-eight-years-tangly-llc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/the-quest-for-an-agile-company-eight-years-tangly-llc/</guid>
      <description>We are an agile and software technology boutique.&#xA;We often work as Scrum masters, product owners and technical agile coaches. Regularly we are involved in the architecture and development of software products.&#xA;Our collaborators love to coaching, mentoring, and training.&#xA;We regularly work at the customer site. We also more and more often work online with our international customers.&#xA;How do you organize such a company?&#xA;How do collaborators work together?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Commits for the Impatient</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/semantic-commits-for-the-impatient/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/semantic-commits-for-the-impatient/</guid>
      <description>The conventional commits specification is a lightweight convention on top of commit messages. The additional information classifies the type of work performed in the commit.&#xA;A developer infers the importance of the task by looking to the type of the commit. The message communicates the nature of changes to teammates, the public, and other stakeholders.&#xA;Contributors of project repositories know that a well-designed Git commit message is the best way to communicate the context about a change to other developers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gradle Good Practices</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/gradle-good-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/gradle-good-practices/</guid>
      <description>Gradle Build Tool is a fast, dependable, and adaptable open-source build automation tool with an elegant and extensible declarative build language. Java is the primary supported programming language.&#xA;Gradle Build Tool is a popular build system for the JVM and is the default system for Android and Kotlin Multi-Platform projects.&#xA;It has a rich community plugin ecosystem. Groovy, Kotlin, C++, and Swift stacks are well-supported.&#xA;Gradle is fast, scalable, and can build projects of any size and complexity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pragmatic Java Application Design</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/pragmatic-java-application-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/pragmatic-java-application-design/</guid>
      <description>I attended the 20th edition of the Devoxx Belgium conference in Antwerp.&#xA;I heard about beautiful examples of how to design complex software applications written in Java.&#xA;The solutions scale to hundreds of thousands of users, are resilient to network disruption and use fancy libraries and tools.&#xA;The applications are deployed on cloud infrastructure and are available worldwide.&#xA;After the conference, I went to Ibiza for a family holiday. Our family enjoys prolonging the summer on this beautiful balearic island.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>C4 and UML with PlantUML</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/c4-and-uml-with-plantuml/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/c4-and-uml-with-plantuml/</guid>
      <description>You are creating an awesome digital product. The software part shall work flawlessly over the years.&#xA;Technology changes will be added to the product. Legal changes and security improvements are implemented in a timely manner over the years.&#xA;This application will evolve to satisfy new needs and customer segments. The life span of your product is probably more than a decade.&#xA;How can you document critical cross-cutting design decisions and key mechanisms?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java Certification</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/java-certification/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/java-certification/</guid>
      <description>Java expertise is in high demand for all kinds of projects, ranging from big enterprise software implementations down to little web projects. A huge number of enterprise applications are developed in Java.&#xA;But will those employers want you to have related certifications?&#xA;Even if you are not looking to move any time soon, getting certified boosts the value that you can bring to your organization.&#xA;Certifications can be a great bargaining chip when it comes to negotiating a raise or a promotion.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Software Architecture Themes and Questions</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/software-architecture-themes-and-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/software-architecture-themes-and-questions/</guid>
      <description>A software architect works with a development team to define how features shall be realized. The selected approach should support corporate governance and legal constraints.&#xA;A new digital product must fulfill a set of technical aspects to be usable. Technical constraints are the non-functional requirements of the product [1].&#xA;Some of these technical requirements are encountered again and again when developing digital products.&#xA;Any software product must provide solutions to standard problems.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Visual Tools</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/agile-visual-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/agile-visual-tools/</guid>
      <description>Why is visibility so important for any agile or Scrum team?&#xA;When you are running an agile product development initiative, your ultimate goal is customer satisfaction with the delivered solution.&#xA;The project coordination responsibilities are, however, not limited to this single goal.&#xA;The product owner shall nurture the vision, roadmap, the release plan and customer journey. You must coordinate the workflow of your team, refine the product backlog, control identified risks, and track deadlines.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Git Tag for the Impatient</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/git-tag-for-the-impatient/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/git-tag-for-the-impatient/</guid>
      <description>The development software team has reached a milestone.&#xA;A working application with a set of features is available. All tests are green.&#xA;The application can potentially be shipped to internal or external customers.&#xA;How can you mark this event in the git repository of the application?&#xA;Use tags to recognize this state in the list of changes of your shared Git repository.&#xA;Listing Your Tags Listing the existing tags in Git is straightforward.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Git Rebase and Merge for the Impatient</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/git-rebase-and-merge-for-the-impatient/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/git-rebase-and-merge-for-the-impatient/</guid>
      <description>Both the rebase and merge commands provide similar functionalities.&#xA;They combine the work of multiple developers into a single entity, integrating changes between branches.&#xA;That about sums up their similarities.&#xA;The operation git merge is a way of combining changes from one source branch into another target branch. The operation leaves commit messages in the history.&#xA;The operation git rebase is a way of moving the changes from one branch onto another branch.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Certifications Useful?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/are-certifications-useful/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/are-certifications-useful/</guid>
      <description>There are several benefits to getting an IT certification, and several associated costs too.&#xA;Certifications can give you the chance to learn needed skills, and be a quick way to show employers you have those skills.&#xA;On the other hand, certifications can require studying or coursework. You will invest a significant amount of time to master the material. They cost up to several hundred dollars to take.&#xA;So how do you know that the benefits will outweigh the costs for you?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Corporate Governance for Software Products</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/corporate-governance-for-software-products/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/corporate-governance-for-software-products/</guid>
      <description>Since good governance is about the processes for making and implementing decisions, then effective governance and accountability structures are vital.&#xA;Organizations shall successfully use an agile approach to deliver business change through the investment in programs and projects.&#xA;Agile approaches are the most used frameworks to develop successfully digital products.&#xA;Our corporate governance processes shall support agile values and development methods.&#xA;The four guiding principles to enable successful governance of agile delivery are:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Onboarding Software Developers in Your agile Team</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/onboarding-software-developers-in-your-agile-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/onboarding-software-developers-in-your-agile-team/</guid>
      <description>Now that you have gone through the long and tedious process of hiring a talented developer with vetting and interview activities, it is easy to think that the hard part is done [1] [2].&#xA;There is no doubt that hiring good people is challenging and competitive, but it is a mistake to think that the challenge ends when you hired a new collaborator.&#xA;Onboarding software developers is just as important for getting the most out of the hiring process.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scrum Masters and Agile Coaches</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/scrum-masters-and-agile-coaches/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/scrum-masters-and-agile-coaches/</guid>
      <description>Scrum is the most popular agile approach used to develop digital products.&#xA;The Scrum master role is well-documented in the Scrum. There are probably more than one million of certified Scrum masters in the world.&#xA;To differentiate themselves from the numerous Scrum masters, consultants call themselves agile coaches.&#xA;Quite a fancy title.&#xA;Does a difference exist between a Scrum master and an agile coach?&#xA;A Scrum master is a type of Agile coach.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Quest for an Agile Company: Seven Years tangly llc</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/the-quest-for-an-agile-company-seven-years-tangly-llc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/the-quest-for-an-agile-company-seven-years-tangly-llc/</guid>
      <description>We are an agile software coaching and digital product development boutique.&#xA;Since our inception, we have created digital products using agile approaches. Our preferred tools are Scrum, Lean Software Development, DevOps, LeSS.&#xA;The created digital products are successful in the market.&#xA;They exhibit good quality. Sound engineering approaches were used to design and construct them in a timely and economical way.&#xA;Our customers learnt how to deploy updates and new functionalities in a matter of days.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Technical Interviews</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/technical-interviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/technical-interviews/</guid>
      <description>Your sole goal is to hire a qualified collaborator with potential.&#xA;For example, you need a great software engineer with social competence. He is a professional developer and has knowledge of the technology stack [1] your company is using. The candidate naturally understands agile and DevOps approaches.&#xA;How can you convince him to sign the contract and start working on your cool product?&#xA;Hiring is like dating.&#xA;Both parties shall be motivated to deepen their relationship and enter a binding agreement.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SME IT Responsible</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/sme-it-responsible/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/sme-it-responsible/</guid>
      <description>What does a senior manager in charge of information technology?&#xA;An IT director is the information technology right-hand man of the company’s manager. He sometimes has the shiny title of CIO. He proposes and implements the IT strategy of the company.&#xA;He intervenes at different levels in the management and optimization of the company’s information system.&#xA;This encompasses hardware and software infrastructures, information architecture, business tools, dedicated internal or external human resources, and often old technology.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Select An Agile Software Development Partner</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/select-an-agile-software-development-partner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/select-an-agile-software-development-partner/</guid>
      <description>It is not unusual for businesses to turn to third-party companies when they want help to achieve their goals without increasing internal overhead.&#xA;This type of outsourcing is especially common for projects that require tremendous amounts of effort or specific skill sets [1].&#xA;Time constraints are often a supplemental driving factor.&#xA;Partnering up with another business to help meet your needs is a viable and widespread solution [2]. It often makes sense for businesses trying to tackle a massive software development project while focusing on the current needs of their clients.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Steps DevOps</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/first-steps-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/first-steps-devops/</guid>
      <description>The DevOps movement started to gather momentum with the first DevOps conference held in Ghent, Belgium in 2009 [1].&#xA;The approach aims to shorten the system development life-cycle and to provide continuous delivery with high software quality. DevOps is complementary with agile software development approaches.&#xA;Several DevOps aspects came from the Agile method.&#xA;Seminal books [1, 2, 3, 4] and good practices were published around the same time.&#xA;The DevOps approach belongs to the regular instruments of professional software developers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eliminate Your Printer</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/eliminate-your-printer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/eliminate-your-printer/</guid>
      <description>In an increasingly technology-focused world, the demand for businesses to digitize has grown dramatically.&#xA;So, what does it mean to digitize your business?&#xA;Essentially, it means incorporating technology into your business operations to increase efficiency, enhance customer experience, and boost sales.&#xA;This could mean developing a mobile application for your startup, transitioning into ecommerce, offering mobile payment options, and more.&#xA;The goal of digitizing your business is to keep up with the rapidly changing economy by offering your customers more ways to access your business, and streamline daily operations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Experiences</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/expertise/expertise-agile/agile-experiences/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/expertise/expertise-agile/agile-experiences/</guid>
      <description>Agile Experiences Context Scrum is the industrial standard to create and develop awesome digital products.&#xA;Scrum Scrum is a minimalist framework empowering your organization to deliver digital products.&#xA;Scrum is an additive framework. Please be pragmatic and professional.&#xA;Roles: Product Owner, Scrum Master, Team Member&#xA;Events: Sprint, Sprint Planning, Daily Scrum, Review, Retrospective, Backlog Refinement&#xA;Artifacts: Product Increment, Product Backlog, Spring Backlog, Definition of Done&#xA;Technical Agile and Scrum</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ArchUnit</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/archunit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/archunit/</guid>
      <description>How often have you experienced a well-defined and understood software architecture on paper? And it falls apart when developers start implementing it?&#xA;While re-architecting recently legacy components in an application, I experienced the same.&#xA;As more and more developers joined the team, it became a constant routine to make them aware of the design and how to adhere to it.&#xA;I know some of you may say, Why not control the implementation during code-review sessions?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transfer a Software Project</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/transfer-a-software-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/transfer-a-software-project/</guid>
      <description>You developed a new digital product for an internal or external customer. Your solution is awesome.&#xA;The product is released to delighted users. Your users love your solution.&#xA;The project is now winding down and closing activities are initiated. The customer organization shall take ownership of all product related artifacts. The handover is a vital part of closing a project [1].&#xA;Your customer paid for the development and own the produced artifacts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Detect Fake Scrum?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/how-to-detect-fake-scrum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/how-to-detect-fake-scrum/</guid>
      <description>Some organisations are adopting agile and Scrum approaches simply because they see competitors doing it. In these situations, there is rarely a desire to adopt a new mindset and culture, or motivation for true change.&#xA;A common pattern is the adoption of a new nomenclature. Project Managers are renamed as Scrum Masters. Business Analysts become Product Owners.&#xA;Very little actually changes. Few benefits of agility are realised.&#xA;If anything, the situation may become worse as some previous structures are lost, yet the discipline for Agile is just not there.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Would You Enjoy Being a Scrum Master?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/would-you-enjoy-being-a-scrum-master/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/would-you-enjoy-being-a-scrum-master/</guid>
      <description>Scrum is the most popular approach to create awesome new digital products.&#xA;Perhaps you are thinking of pursuing a career as a Scrum master. You read the Agile Manifesto and memorized the 12 Agile Manifesto Principles.&#xA;Perhaps you have recently been moved into that role and are wondering if being a Scrum master is right for you.&#xA;There are plenty of good reasons to become a Scrum master. The job is fascinating, in demand and pays well.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing DevOps Ideas</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/introducing-devops-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/introducing-devops-ideas/</guid>
      <description>Your organization heard of DevOps, and your developers clamor you should adopt the approach.&#xA;Each organization I talk with has some DevOps initiative. Often because they read that DevOps approach puts customers and end-user satisfaction at the center.&#xA;Does DevOps really improve the quality of your digital products and customer satisfaction?&#xA;Or is it only the next silver bullet fad used to increase the bonus of consultants and managers?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digital Product Manager</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/digital-product-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/digital-product-manager/</guid>
      <description>Effective product management is driven by a customer-centric mindset. The customer is placed at the center of every decision.&#xA;Supported by tools and techniques such as design thinking, this mindset focuses the entire organization on creating desirable, viable, feasible, and sustainable solutions.&#xA;Good product managers balance customer needs, adequate technologies, product delivery, and governance or legal constraints.&#xA;They shall master project management approaches, financing mechanisms and collaborator nurturing.&#xA;Responsibilities The primary responsibilities of product management often fall into the following areas.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java, Groovy, Clojure</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/java-groovy-clojure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/java-groovy-clojure/</guid>
      <description>Professional software developers shall master their primary technology stack and programming language.&#xA;I am a proficient and experienced programmer in Java.&#xA;I have written production code in Java for the last twenty years.&#xA;I decided to study the language in depth and acquired various Java developer certifications.&#xA;I truly love the modern Java language and the available development environments.&#xA;I want to understand the strengths and weaknesses of Java.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modernize Your Java Landscape</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/modernize-your-java-landscape/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/modernize-your-java-landscape/</guid>
      <description>The dreaded attack through the log4j logging library was a wake-up call for all companies using obsolete libraries. Many organizations found out the hard way they cannot update the library and deploy the new version in a matter of minutes as professional developers should do. They needed weeks to perform such a simple activity.&#xA;They also found out that they had no process for such regular situations when a critical flaw is detected in some software they are using.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modern Java with Spring</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/modern-java-with-spring/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/modern-java-with-spring/</guid>
      <description>Spring and Spring Boot frameworks are the standard for enterprise Java applications.&#xA;Spring Boot makes it easy to create stand-alone, production-grade Spring-based Applications that you can just run.&#xA;They take an opinionated view of the Spring platform and third-party libraries, so you can get started with minimum fuss.&#xA;Most Spring Boot applications need minimal Spring configuration.&#xA;Minimize Boilerplate Code One of the key reasons for the success of Spring is the approach of convention over configuration.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doing Agile</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/doing-agile/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/doing-agile/</guid>
      <description>In the midst of the agile adoption explosion, many teams are experiencing difficulties.&#xA;Organizations often mix agile with Scrum.&#xA;One of the most common misconceptions about Scrum is that it is synonymous with agile. Agile Manifesto is an umbrella term that refers to a family of approaches that share common values and principles.&#xA;Scrum is a commonly used agile framework that offers suggestions for how work can be organized to maximize the value of the end-user.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile and Nearshore Development</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/agile-and-nearshore-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/agile-and-nearshore-development/</guid>
      <description>The majority of software product development initiatives use an agile approach. The most popular framework is currently Scrum.&#xA;It is natural that organizations would gravitate towards the many benefits agile ideas provide.&#xA;Scarce resources and time-to-market constraints have driven the implementation of shoring development initiatives. Awareness that talent can be found at any location speeds up the trend.&#xA;The outsourcing market is undergoing constant evolution. Traditionally, cost reduction was the key driver for software development outsourcing, but now it doesn’t even make the top five, according to Deloitte’s 2018 Global Outsourcing Survey.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Quest for an Agile Company: Six Years tangly llc</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/the-quest-for-an-agile-company-six-years-tangly-llc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/the-quest-for-an-agile-company-six-years-tangly-llc/</guid>
      <description>Historically, big beats small. Scale was a sufficient advantage to be successful in the market.&#xA;Now, fast and adaptive beats slow and steadfast.&#xA;New technologies, evolving customer preferences and changing employee expectations are fundamentally challenging established ways of working [1].&#xA;It is time to move beyond rigid hierarchies, siloed business units, crippling bureaucracy and an increasingly unwieldy matrix.&#xA;Agile organizations combine the efficiencies of scale with the speed, flexibility and resilience to compete and win in today’s world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluate Technical CVs</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/evaluate-technical-cvs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/evaluate-technical-cvs/</guid>
      <description>The goal of a curriculum vitae is to get an invitation to a job interview. I review hundreds of CVs and must select a few candidates we should invite.&#xA;Each interview will cost hundreds of Euros to the company. I must minimize the number of interviews and increase the probability of a match.&#xA;Over the years, I developed a checklist to select promising candidates.&#xA;The below checklist is biased to the Java technology check.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spotify Cultural Elements</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/spotify-cultural-elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/spotify-cultural-elements/</guid>
      <description>Recently, a client told me that they were adopting the Spotify Model. This statement sounded great for him.&#xA;Spotify has published some great articles and videos about how they have grown and transformed their organization to be agile. Then it occurred to me that what my customer was saying was completely wrong.&#xA;I don’t think you can really understand what it is like to work at Spotify without actually living it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Choice is Good</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/choice-is-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/choice-is-good/</guid>
      <description>First and foremost, our primary goal is to develop successful products and delight users. We are always looking for good practices to improve our odds.&#xA;Product development is a risky business.&#xA;We want to expand our toolbox with proven approaches. We use these tools to experiment when confronted with new problems. There is No Silver Bullet to solve our specific challenges.&#xA;Using a goal-driven approach that guides people through process-related options is one powerful approach.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Design Modeling</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/agile-design-modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/agile-design-modeling/</guid>
      <description>Unknown reference: implementing-domain-driven-desing The line between software development and software architecture is a tricky one.&#xA;Some people will tell you that it does not exist and that architecture is simply an extension of the design process undertaken by developers. Others will make out it is a massive gaping chasm that can only be crossed by lofty developers. They believe you must always abstract your abstractions and not get bogged down by those pesky implementation details.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scrum Developer Formation</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/scrum-developer-formation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/scrum-developer-formation/</guid>
      <description>You are working as a developer in a Scrum team.&#xA;Congratulations, working as a professional Scrum developer is a fulfilling and exciting job.&#xA;You should attend professional training.&#xA;Formal training is often the difference between being a professional instead of just pretending to be one.&#xA;Scrum Developer Role Here the official definition of the developer team member role taken from the Scrum.&#xA;Developers are the people in the Scrum Team that are committed to creating any aspect of a usable Increment each Sprint.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I Learnt Teaching Agile Software Architecture</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/what-i-learnt-teaching-agile-software-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/what-i-learnt-teaching-agile-software-architecture/</guid>
      <description>I am teaching agile software architecture and techniques SWAT as advanced bachelor level lecture weighted with 3 ECTS.&#xA;I gave this training the last three years at Lucerne University of Applied Sciences and Arts HSLU in Switzerland.&#xA;All materials are released under the Creative Commons copyright.&#xA;The course contents are aligned with the big software architecture programs.&#xA;The Open Group organization is the steward of TOGAF standard. TOGAF is the worldwide industrial standard for enterprise software architecture.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scrum Master Formation</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/scrum-master-formation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/scrum-master-formation/</guid>
      <description>You work as a Scrum master.&#xA;Congratulations, working as a professional Scrum master is a fulfilling and exciting job.&#xA;You should attend professional training.&#xA;Not only attend the two-day training to receive a shiny diploma.&#xA;Being a Scrum master and coach is a profession, not a fancy title!&#xA;Please reflect on your goals and ethics.&#xA;Scrum Master Role Here the official definition of the product owner role taken from the Scrum.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DevOps for Small Applications</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/devops-for-small-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/devops-for-small-applications/</guid>
      <description>DevOps is the combination of cultural philosophies, practices and tools that increase an organization’s ability to deliver at high velocity.&#xA;It evolves and improves products at a faster pace than organizations using traditional software development and infrastructure management processes.&#xA;This speed enables organizations to better serve their customers [1, 2].&#xA;A surprising side effect of this speed-up is a documented improvement of the delivered quality.&#xA;How It Works Under a DevOps model, development and operations teams are no longer siloed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Leadership</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/agile-leadership/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/agile-leadership/</guid>
      <description>Everybody is talking about being agile.&#xA;Companies institutionalize agile change programs and send all their collaborators in training to learn the agile way.&#xA;What does that mean?&#xA;How should I as a manager work the agile way?&#xA;Does this agile way exist, or is it simply a fad created by the consulting industry?&#xA;This article provides some pointers and hypotheses what agile leadership could be.&#xA;Feel free to experiment and refine your successful approach to be agile as an organization.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Technical Team Lead</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/technical-team-lead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/technical-team-lead/</guid>
      <description>I lately had to explain to customers what are the responsibilities of a technical team lead. Managers often grasp the people aspects embedded in the words team lead. The understanding of the word technical is strangely often missing.&#xA;A technical team leads coaches and teaches the subtleties of the used technology stack to his team and organization. This person should be able to create or review a software architecture. He has a deep understanding of technological concepts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Enterprise Architecture?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/why-enterprise-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/why-enterprise-architecture/</guid>
      <description>Architecture principles hold true in agile environments. The major difference between older traditional approaches and modern agile ones is the way of performing enterprise architecture.&#xA;The last years have shown a promising evolution of plan-based, centralist enterprise architecture approaches to more agile, decentralized, meritocracy driven processes.&#xA;These new approaches are way more compatible with modern and agile software product development framework such as Scrum, eXtreme Programming, and LeSS&#xA;Traditional processes use dedicated persons or departments to define architecture principles in a top-down approach.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Product Owner Formation</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/product-owner-formation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/product-owner-formation/</guid>
      <description>You are acting as a product owner in your organization.&#xA;Congratulations, working as a professional product owner is a fulfilling and exciting job.&#xA;You should attend professional training.&#xA;Being a product owner and requirements engineer is a profession, not a hobby!&#xA;Formal training is often the difference between being a professional instead of just pretending to be one.&#xA;Product Owner Role Here the official definition of the product owner role taken from the Scrum.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Temporal Aspects of Rolling ERP Planning</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/temporal-aspects-of-rolling-erp-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/temporal-aspects-of-rolling-erp-planning/</guid>
      <description>Agile approaches advocate dynamic planning and adaptation to new inputs and priority changes. The Beyond Budgeting Round Table movement promotes rolling planning, budgeting and reporting.&#xA;The beyond budgeting techniques recommend the complete abolition of traditional budgeting processes. They require the implementation of new techniques that will replace them. The BB framework does not specify the exact techniques that are applicable to all companies.&#xA;However, there are some techniques that have proven to be effective in real cases in the past.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Trends Switzerland 2021</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/agile-trends-switzerland-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/agile-trends-switzerland-2021/</guid>
      <description>As a modern leader, you are aware of the importance of transforming your organization to become more agile. Indeed, you have successfully implemented first steps.&#xA;Trouble is brewing. Things are not moving forward as quickly as they should, especially in the current challenging situation. The leadership behaviour of your colleagues is only changing slowly. Your key developers are grumbling you are faking it.&#xA;Many companies around the world discover their agile transformation is stalling.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on Agile Fluency Model</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/reflections-on-agile-fluency-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/reflections-on-agile-fluency-model/</guid>
      <description>Agile fluency model is a powerful abstraction to better understand your agile transition. It does not matter which flavor of agile you are deploying in your organization; the agile fluency model can be applied in all cases.&#xA;The agile fluency model has a powerful message about agile and technical excellence. The second zone of the model is all about software craftsmanship and eXtreme Programming.&#xA;One key lesson of the fluency model is it takes time until you are professional at your chosen level.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Certified Java Developer</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/certified-java-developer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/certified-java-developer/</guid>
      <description>Java is celebrating 25 years of existence.&#xA;I discovered the anniversary offer to certify for Java SE 11 Developer.&#xA;This special certification has a cool logo with the remainder of the Java 25-year anniversary.&#xA;Oracle offers this certification for only 25 dollars [1] and provides free access to their learning platform.&#xA;The offer and logo availability are time limited.&#xA;The free learning subscription includes:&#xA;The Java Explorer learning path for basic Java skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Trends Switzerland 2020</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/agile-trends-switzerland-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/agile-trends-switzerland-2020/</guid>
      <description>As a modern leader, you are aware of the importance of transforming your organization to become more agile. Indeed, you have successfully implemented first steps.&#xA;Trouble is brewing. Things are not moving forward as quickly as they should, especially in the current challenging situation. The leadership behaviour of your colleagues is only changing slowly. Your key developers are grumbling you are faking it.&#xA;Many companies around the world discover their agile transformation is stalling.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Requirements Engineering</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/agile-requirements-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/agile-requirements-engineering/</guid>
      <description>Lately, I was asked which new approaches should be used for agile requirements engineering. Did we find a new silver bullet to write software specifications the agile way?&#xA;The answer is easy. We do not need new approaches or complicated processes. Start with proven principles and learn.&#xA;Impact Mapping and Story Mapping are successful approaches to identify and prioritize your functions. Specification by Example and User Stories as a discussion allow you to refine your understanding of what your customers need.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective Working in Digital Age</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/effective-working-in-digital-age/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/effective-working-in-digital-age/</guid>
      <description>Home office is the new way of working. A lot of friends and business partners are working from home. Our meetings are mostly online. We share documents and results through digital platforms.&#xA;I truly hope we continue to work online in the future. I would like to mix home office, local coworking space, and regular office attendance. I am convinced less commute time and a greener approach to work are certainly great improvements.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Is Java Path Class Better?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/why-is-java-path-class-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/why-is-java-path-class-better/</guid>
      <description>Java NIO New Input Output is an alternative IO API for Java, meaning alternative to the standard Java IO and Java Networking APIs.&#xA;Java NIO offers a different IO programming model than the traditional IO APIs.&#xA;One major feature of interest is the support of alternate file systems. An in-memory file system is ideal for test file related operations in unit and integration tests.&#xA;Sometimes NIO is claimed to mean Non-blocking IO.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LeSS Lessons Learnt</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/less-lessons-learnt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/less-lessons-learnt/</guid>
      <description>Scaling Agile, Lean and Scrum to the whole product development department is hard work.&#xA;You start a change journey in murky waters. Best to communicate a lot, strengthen your teams and have total support of upper management.&#xA;Technical agile coaching usefully describes the work I do. Agile coaching helps your business to become more successful, often improve the way you plan and deliver software.&#xA;Technical agile coaching focuses on how people design products, write code and deliver high-quality products.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advocate Zero Bug Policy in Your Projects!</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/advocate-zero-bug-policy-in-your-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/advocate-zero-bug-policy-in-your-projects/</guid>
      <description>At many customer sites I visit, I see a lot of effort being put into classifying and managing bugs.&#xA;Their bug list may contain more than a thousand items. All are neatly documented with screenshots, ways to reproduce the problem and a severity and impact classification. In the worst case, a specialist has worked hard and estimated the effort to correct each of these bugs.&#xA;A change management board meets every few weeks to decide which bugs have a higher priority and should urgently be fixed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Quest for an Agile Company: Five Years tangly llc</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/the-quest-for-an-agile-company-five-years-tangly-llc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/the-quest-for-an-agile-company-five-years-tangly-llc/</guid>
      <description>An agile company is a business with the ability to quickly adapt to market changes [1].&#xA;tangly is an agile and digital development boutique. We must swiftly react to market changes to survive.&#xA;Agility is woven into our culture and processes.&#xA;Agile organizations must be fast-moving and flexible, have rapid response to unexpected obstacles, lead change, be in touch with customers.&#xA;They have a continuous competitive advantage, and a flat organizational structure for quick communication [2].</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Component Design</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/agile-component-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/agile-component-design/</guid>
      <description>You are an experienced programmer. You master your primary technology stack and systematically write clean code.&#xA;Your team recognized your merits and asked you to take ownership of whole packages in the application.&#xA;You are now responsible for creating or modifying a software component in your current application.&#xA;This is a design activity.&#xA;How can you create a good, legible, maintainable component architecture?&#xA;How can you validate your functional and non-functional requirements?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Agile Collaborators Learn</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/how-agile-collaborators-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/how-agile-collaborators-learn/</guid>
      <description>Most products are developed by a team, and these achievements are the fruit of teamwork.&#xA;Software product development is now agile, and most often uses the Scrum approach.&#xA;Just putting a bunch of people together in the same open office will not produce a high performance agile team. Quite a few companies find that out the hard way.&#xA;How can you increase the odds to create an environment where agile teams bloom and perform?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Calibrate Your Agile Approach: Bill of Rights</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/calibrate-your-agile-approach-bill-of-rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/calibrate-your-agile-approach-bill-of-rights/</guid>
      <description>When eXtreme Programming first came out, one expectation it worked hard to set is who gets to make what calls on software projects.&#xA;For example, business has the right to know how long something is going to take and when it can expect things to be done.&#xA;Conversely, developers have the right to know what the priorities are, and to be able to do good work.&#xA;To that end, eXtreme Programming created the Customer and Development Team Bill of Rights.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile @ Scale</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/agile-@-scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/agile-@-scale/</guid>
      <description>Your organization has decided to introduce agile at scale in all development departments or better in the whole company.&#xA;Your Chief of Agility COA, Chief of Digitalization COD or Chief of Change COC was in an expensive training. After a few drinks, he has selected the appropriate framework for your company.&#xA;Welcome to the club of companies introducing agile approaches and having no clues why they do it and how they could be successful.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Commons View on Scrum</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/a-commons-view-on-scrum/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/a-commons-view-on-scrum/</guid>
      <description>Agile approaches encourage common ownership of artifacts during product development. Historically, the commons is the term used for shared resources. Can we apply the commons learnings to agile and Scrum approaches?&#xA;Interestingly, economists were kind to state common ownership is doomed to fail through the theory published at the end of the sixties [1].&#xA;Thirty years later, Elinor Ostrom showed that commons can indeed work well if you follow a small set of rules.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Architecture within Scrum</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/agile-architecture-within-scrum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/agile-architecture-within-scrum/</guid>
      <description>You are applying the agile, lean approach to your software product development. Your teams use Scrum or Kanban to deliver running software every two weeks.&#xA;Agile architecture is a key element to improve the quality of your solution and reduce the overall cycle-time of your product delivery.&#xA;Your journey toward greater business agility starts by identifying what outcomes are most important to your company’s success.&#xA;Outcomes are codified in functional and non-functional requirements your product shall fulfill.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Code is Clean Code!</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/agile-code-is-clean-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/agile-code-is-clean-code/</guid>
      <description>You are applying the agile, lean approach to your software product development.&#xA;Congratulations, you are applying state of the industry good practices.&#xA;Your teams use Scrum or Kanban to deliver running software every two weeks.&#xA;To create an agile architecture, you must write agile worthy code. Agile code is always clean code.&#xA;Start early, do it continuously and soon your code will be clean, legible and free of known defects.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Architecture Principles</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/agile-architecture-principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/agile-architecture-principles/</guid>
      <description>You are applying the agile, lean approach to your software product development. Your teams use Scrum or Kanban to deliver running software every two weeks. The product market introduction is a success. You will successfully sell the solution for the next ten years.&#xA;How shall you define the software architecture of your product and ensure a long living and high-quality solution?&#xA;The experts tell you the design is emergent.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You Need an Engineering Culture</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/you-need-an-engineering-culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/you-need-an-engineering-culture/</guid>
      <description>Agile approaches are not enough. You need a strong engineering culture to achieve quality and lasting success.&#xA;Often, coaches and Scrum masters tinker with the processes and invest effort and blood to improve the ceremonies and the company structure.&#xA;But at the end of the day, the success of your application is defined by its adequacy to customer needs and its overall quality. You need a solid and professional engineering culture to produce high-quality products and release them at a high rate.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Healthy is Your Product? - Company Culture Check</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/how-healthy-is-your-product-company-culture-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/how-healthy-is-your-product-company-culture-check/</guid>
      <description>You are developing your application using agile and lean approaches.&#xA;How can you check your approach and distill improvements?&#xA;Health check of your product and your development approach are certainly a good solution.&#xA;This post is the fourth and last of a set of articles identifying health checks with different focus.&#xA;We will identify strengths, potential weaknesses and hopefully find room for improvement.&#xA;What is your company culture?&#xA;How are collaborators focused on delighting your customers?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Detecting Agile Bullshit</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/detecting-agile-bullshit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/detecting-agile-bullshit/</guid>
      <description>The Defense Innovation Board DIB advises the secretary of defense of the United States of America.&#xA;Members of the board are recognizable names like Eric Schmidt who was CEO of Google and Alphabet, or Instagram COO Marne Levine.&#xA;So I was quite surprised that a government committee was so straightforward to publish a document called Detecting Agile Bullshit [1].&#xA;Simple questions are used as a bullshit detector to identify organizations faking agile.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Healthy is Your Product? - Product Strategy Check</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/how-healthy-is-your-product-product-strategy-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/how-healthy-is-your-product-product-strategy-check/</guid>
      <description>You are developing your product using agile and lean approaches.&#xA;How can you check your approach and distill improvements?&#xA;Health check of your product and your development approach are certainly a good solution.&#xA;This post is the third of a set of articles identifying health checks with different focus. We will identify strengths, potential weaknesses and hopefully find room for improvement.&#xA;What is your product strategy? How do you involve your customers and stakeholders?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SAFE 4.6: Improvements Direly Needed</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/safe-4.6-improvements-direly-needed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/safe-4.6-improvements-direly-needed/</guid>
      <description>It is official.&#xA;The power engine of the SAFe 4.6 vehicle is the team and technical agility. View the SAFe for more information [1].&#xA;It is one of their five Lean Enterprise competencies and one of their four core values. SAFe finally recognizes the tremendous importance of technical proficiency and craftsmanship.&#xA;They advocate two findings. First, you need team agility, how you apply Scrum or Kanban.&#xA;In other words, being agile instead of doing agile.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Healthy is Your Product? - Delivery Pipeline Check</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/how-healthy-is-your-product-delivery-pipeline-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/how-healthy-is-your-product-delivery-pipeline-check/</guid>
      <description>You are developing your product using agile and lean approaches.&#xA;How can you check your approach and distill improvements? A health check of your product and your development approach is certainly a good solution.&#xA;This post is the second of a series identifying health checks with different focus. We will identify strengths, potential weaknesses and hopefully find room for improvement.&#xA;How you build and deliver your software product has direct implications on your liquidity and cash flow.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Should You handle Definition of Done?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/how-should-you-handle-definition-of-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/how-should-you-handle-definition-of-done/</guid>
      <description>An agile team is the sole responsible for the internal quality of the product they build and maintain.&#xA;The developers shall be accountable for producing the expected quality and optimizing long term goals of the organization.&#xA;You as a developer have an ethical, professional and legal responsibility to ensure adequate quality for your products.&#xA;Laws protect the confidentiality of their personal and financial data.&#xA;It is a potential crime to leak credit card information, geolocation data or the worst personal documents.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Healthy is Your Product? - Source Code Check</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/how-healthy-is-your-product-source-code-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/how-healthy-is-your-product-source-code-check/</guid>
      <description>You are developing your product using agile and lean approaches.&#xA;How can you check your approach and distill improvements? Health check of your product and your development approach are certainly a good solution.&#xA;This post is the first of a series identifying health checks with different focus. We will identify strengths, potential weaknesses and hopefully find room for improvement.&#xA;The initial examination shall always be the source code. Your code base is a key asset of your company.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduce Agile in A Company</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/introduce-agile-in-a-company/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/introduce-agile-in-a-company/</guid>
      <description>First teams have successfully used Scrum to develop applications. The news spread out and everybody wants to apply Scrum. It is time to introduce enterprise-wide Agile with Scrum or Kanban or XP.&#xA;Your Company wants to introduce Enterprise Agility in their product development, quality assurance and sales departments. The company as a whole shall transition to an agile organization and all teams shall adopt Scrum.&#xA;Try the Shu Ha Ri approach for such a change process.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What does an Agile Coach?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/what-does-an-agile-coach/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/what-does-an-agile-coach/</guid>
      <description>An agile coach has three main areas of activity:&#xA;Foster Autonomy Teach and support the team and individuals to be autonomous within the given boundaries of the organization and its processes.&#xA;Create Ground for Motivation Help teams to maximize their autonomy, individual mastery and make sure the team has a purpose.&#xA;Provide Coaching Support teams and individuals to identify potential with their roles and within the agile organization and improve.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Trends Switzerland 2018</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/agile-trends-switzerland-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/agile-trends-switzerland-2018/</guid>
      <description>What are the main hurdles to introducing agile approaches in Swiss companies? The Swiss agile trends report was published for the last ten years and learn us the difficulties and successes of agile transformations.&#xA;SwissQ has published a &amp;#34;SwissQ Software Development Switzerland 2018&amp;#34;, the tenth version of this report.&#xA;Introducing agile company-wide was and is a cultural change process. Such a change takes time and sometimes hurts. Too often, organizations stop the process and revert to all command and control approaches with Waterfall product management.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Introduction Success Criteria through the LeSS Lens</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/agile-introduction-success-criteria-through-the-less-lens/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/agile-introduction-success-criteria-through-the-less-lens/</guid>
      <description>An agile organization is able to deliver or change her direction at any time without additional cost.&#xA;More companies want to become truly agile and book an expensive journey to the holy land of agility. Often travelers never reach their true destination.&#xA;The LeSS people have a clear set of conditions to increase the odds.&#xA;All my experiences confirm these conditions are essential for success.&#xA;LeSS Criteria Use these criteria as a checklist to evaluate your current agile transformation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pragmatic Craftsmanship - Professional Software Developer</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/pragmatic-craftsmanship-professional-software-developer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/pragmatic-craftsmanship-professional-software-developer/</guid>
      <description>The last months I was often confronted with software products having insufficient quality.&#xA;Insufficient means late delivery, and few new features. The effort to correct errors in the field eats 30% to 50% away from the development budget. How can such a dreadful situation occur?&#xA;One root cause is the low quality of the source code and ignorance of basic coding design approaches.&#xA;We are not talking about complex design activities or complex patterns; we are discussing basic approaches how to write correct and maintainable code.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Do You Need Metrics and KPI in Agile Product Development?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/why-do-you-need-metrics-and-kpi-in-agile-product-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/why-do-you-need-metrics-and-kpi-in-agile-product-development/</guid>
      <description>Why do we define metrics and KPI?&#xA;First, we want to find out how good the build-in quality of our software artifacts is.&#xA;Second, we want to improve the build-in quality through experiments and use the metrics to judge the success of these experiments.&#xA;And the Key Performance Indicators KPI provide plausibility checks by qualifying the intrinsic quality of software artifacts against quantifiable strategic objectives.&#xA;Measurements shall be cheap to gather and as much as possible generated automatically through the tooling landscape.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile GIS Open Data Initiative</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/agile-gis-open-data-initiative/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/agile-gis-open-data-initiative/</guid>
      <description>How can agile approaches be applied to deliver solutions in a government environment?&#xA;Here is an example of a GIS open data portal successfully developed using agile approaches such as Kanban, lean product and technical excellence.&#xA;GIS Open Data Initiative The Swiss government has initiated an open government data strategy to provide data at federal and state level to all citizens and interested parties. The aims are&#xA;Release of official data The Confederation will make data which are suitable for OGD available to the public in machine-readable and open formats to be freely reused.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Six Levers for better Agile Product Development</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/six-levers-for-better-agile-product-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/six-levers-for-better-agile-product-development/</guid>
      <description>Every company is a software company.&#xA;Software is a key to success. This is the new reality in the digital world.&#xA;How can you create better digital products and services?&#xA;How can you delight your customers, your collaborators, and your stakeholders?&#xA;How can you increase the odds of success for your digital products?&#xA;We identified six levers to multiply the effectivity of your agile development teams and empower them to create great services and products.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scrum Guide 2017: What changed?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/scrum-guide-2017-what-changed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/scrum-guide-2017-what-changed/</guid>
      <description>The Scrum guide was revised in 2016 and got clarification concerning the core values. I was thrilled. Talking about values and mental models, you must have to successfully introduce and be agile is awesome.&#xA;A new revision was published at the end of year 2017, just a year after the addition of values.&#xA;What has changed?&#xA;What has the community learnt and committed to the new version of the guide?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One Way to Improve Your Scrum Approach</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/one-way-to-improve-your-scrum-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/one-way-to-improve-your-scrum-approach/</guid>
      <description>You work using agile and lean approaches. Your collaborators are trained how to use agile principles.&#xA;Techniques such as test-driven development, continuous integration, DevOps or clean code are regularly practiced.&#xA;Your teams reduce their technical debt and deliver regularly stable product increments.&#xA;Now you are looking for the next improvement. How can your team improve your product and increase customer value?&#xA;It is time for a fresh view.&#xA;Perform an agile assessment with an external expert from another company or department.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impediment List is of Tremendous Importance</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/impediment-list-is-of-tremendous-importance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/impediment-list-is-of-tremendous-importance/</guid>
      <description>An impediment is any aspect hindering the team or a company to deliver value and higher quality to the customers.&#xA;An agile organization continuously removes impediments. It is one of her major activities. This activity is ongoing and can never be completed.&#xA;Impediments resolution is Kaizen 改善, a key technique to lean, agile and Scrum approaches. The translation is change for better.&#xA;Often agile organizations forget to aggressively identify and resolve impediments.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Approaches and Fix Price Contracts</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/agile-approaches-and-fix-price-contracts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/agile-approaches-and-fix-price-contracts/</guid>
      <description>The difficulty with contracts is that it is about trust. Here lays the roots for success or disaster.&#xA;If no trust exists, the henceforth dreaded process is established. After tough negotiations, the development team starts but does not collaborate with the customer. They just build what is written in outdated requirements. A subpar solution is shipped and the relationship with the customer is deeply damaged.&#xA;We can do better. We shall collaborate, trust each other and create an awesome product.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your Management Job in an Agile Environment</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/your-management-job-in-an-agile-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/your-management-job-in-an-agile-environment/</guid>
      <description>You develop your software products using agile approaches. You are doing Scrum, Kanban, Scrumban, Lean Software Development, or LeSS.&#xA;Your collaborators start asking questions about their organization, management roles, and critique the internal processes.&#xA;How employee yearly evaluation, bonus evaluation – work? You hear strange statements such Be agile, do not do agile.&#xA;You as a manager realize you have to describe your role in an agile environment. What does it mean?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scrum Masters are not Administrators</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/scrum-masters-are-not-administrators/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/scrum-masters-are-not-administrators/</guid>
      <description>Readers know I am an early adopter of agile and Scrum approaches.&#xA;I experienced how much more effective and fun it is to work in an agile team developing digital products.&#xA;Lately I was asked if I was interested in working as a Scrum master [1, 2, 3].&#xA;The job description below was handed me over. What an experience it was.&#xA;The text with the regular font is the job description.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What does a Scrum Master?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/what-does-a-scrum-master/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/what-does-a-scrum-master/</guid>
      <description>What does a Scrum master the whole day?&#xA;Are you just a fancy administrator or are you actively removing impediments?&#xA;Do you coach your teams toward mastery?&#xA;Too often, Scrum masters become Scrum administrators.&#xA;They schedule meetings, moderate discussions, write progress reports and draw beautiful slides how to improve the organization.&#xA;Or worst, they collect extensive statistics about velocity, planned versus delivered story points or how precise story estimation was.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>So Called Agile and Scrum Failures</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/so-called-agile-and-scrum-failures/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/so-called-agile-and-scrum-failures/</guid>
      <description>Agile will never guarantee product success.&#xA;All projects, especially application development, entail risk.&#xA;If a product was risk-free, it is unlikely to provide significant benefits or competitive advantages.&#xA;There are a number of ways in which Agile Scrum projects repeatedly fail which are worth examining.&#xA;Agile approaches and Scrum framework can reduce risks in projects and increase the return on investment. Standish Group report is a proof of this statement.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Git Local Repositories for the Impatient</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/git-local-repositories-for-the-impatient/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/git-local-repositories-for-the-impatient/</guid>
      <description>You shall put your source code and text documentation under a version management system.&#xA;The actual industrial standard for version control systems is git, a distributed version control system - DVCS -. It tracks changes in any set of computer files, usually used for coordinating work among programmers who are collaboratively developing source code during software development.&#xA;Subversion was a great tool and should now be retired. Simple refactoring activities with renaming will already corrupt a subversion repository.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Trends Switzerland 2017: We Won</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/agile-trends-switzerland-2017-we-won/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/agile-trends-switzerland-2017-we-won/</guid>
      <description>It is time to throw a big party in Switzerland. More than 60% of all projects are now realized using an agile approach (to see Agile Trends in Switzerland 2017] by SwissQ [1]. Scrum being the most popular one, Kanban as the second one. What a change in just one year. In 2016, we had 40% of projects being agile, one year later we have 60%. Time to adapt and become agile.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>List of Agile and Lean Books for Software Engineers or Students</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/list-of-agile-and-lean-books-for-software-engineers-or-students/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/list-of-agile-and-lean-books-for-software-engineers-or-students/</guid>
      <description>I am regularly asked by practitioners and technical universities, which books I shall recommend learning more about agile developers, agile projects, and agile companies.&#xA;Reading is a great way to learn and to get new ideas.&#xA;Below, a selection of books I read and found fascinating.&#xA;The selection is certainly not exhaustive.&#xA;The criteria are&#xA;I read the book and learnt something.&#xA;I have bought this book to have it as a reference.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Trends Switzerland 2016</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/agile-trends-switzerland-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/agile-trends-switzerland-2016/</guid>
      <description>What are the main hurdles to introducing agile approaches in Swiss companies? The last five years learn us that:&#xA;Introducing agile company-wide is a cultural change process. Such a change takes time and sometimes hurts.&#xA;Without the commitment of senior management, the initiative will fail.&#xA;You must teach, coach, support your collaborators through the transition. You need to believe in them and provide an environment where they can safely learn and experiment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seven Pitfalls with Agile or Scrum Methods</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/seven-pitfalls-with-agile-or-scrum-methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/seven-pitfalls-with-agile-or-scrum-methods/</guid>
      <description>The post describes a presentation I gave at a company internal technical day. It reflects situations we have seen in a lot of agile projects over the last years.&#xA;I assume that the Scrum approach is well introduced in your company.&#xA;You are already proficient with Scrum, eXtreme Programming, Clean Code, Code Refactoring, how to write stories and story maps, and techniques such as TDD, ATDD.&#xA;You are using Scrum well and can laugh about all these posts about Scrum-But(t).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What you do NOT need to do in Scrum!</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/what-you-do-not-need-to-do-in-scrum/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/what-you-do-not-need-to-do-in-scrum/</guid>
      <description>I often hear discussions asking who is performing the traditional product leader tasks in Scrum.&#xA;This is in general an excuse to state that Scrum alone cannot work and classical product leaders are still needed.&#xA;I encourage you to classify these so-called regular product manager activities. Often these jobs are plain reporting progress to various boards and micromanaging the development team.&#xA;I truly acknowledge the importance and value of a line manager caring for his collaborators and nurturing the success of the products they develop.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is an Agile Company?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/what-is-an-agile-company/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/what-is-an-agile-company/</guid>
      <description>Lately, people often ask me what is an agile company.&#xA;They have an understanding of agile software development techniques such as Scrum, Lean Software Development, Kanban, eXtreme Programming but no clue how a company could be agile.&#xA;What does it mean to be an agile organization?&#xA;One way to approach this theme is to implement concepts of the above-mentioned agile approaches.&#xA;These are the pillars for iterative incremental improvements.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Trends Switzerland 2013</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/agile-trends-switzerland-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/agile-trends-switzerland-2013/</guid>
      <description>What are the main hurdles to introducing agile approaches in Swiss companies?&#xA;Introducing agile company-wide is a cultural change process. Such a change takes time and sometimes hurts.&#xA;Without the commitment of senior management, the initiative will fail.&#xA;Doubt that lean or agile works for big projects, doubt you can convince your collaborators and middle management, doubt your customers agree with lean,&#xA;In the end, what matters are collaborator purpose, customer satisfaction, business value.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Trends Switzerland 2012</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/agile-trends-switzerland-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/agile-trends-switzerland-2012/</guid>
      <description>What are the main hurdles to introducing agile approaches in Swiss companies?&#xA;Introducing agile company-wide is a cultural change process. Such a change takes time and sometimes hurts.&#xA;Without the commitment of senior management, the initiative will fail.&#xA;Doubt that lean or agile works, doubt you can find agile experts, doubt that your projects can be realised with agile approaches.&#xA;In the end, what matters are collaborator purpose, customer satisfaction, business value.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Git Branches for the Impatient</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/git-branches-for-the-impatient/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/git-branches-for-the-impatient/</guid>
      <description>You are working in a small mostly collocated development team. Sometimes a team member works from a remote location.&#xA;You have one git repository accessible to all team members.&#xA;This repository is used to share source code and documentation artifacts.&#xA;You use the actual industrial standard for version control systems is git.&#xA;You decided to use branches to implement new features or fix errors instead of using Trunk-Based Development.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Version of the Scrum Guide 2011</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/the-version-of-the-scrum-guide-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/the-version-of-the-scrum-guide-2011/</guid>
      <description>The new version of the Scrum Guide written by Ken Schwaber and Jeff Sutherland has been available since July 2011.&#xA;You should regularly read the Scrum guide to reflect how your teams are applying agile principles and ideas.&#xA;You should also consult the seminal Agile Manifesto and the 12 Agile Manifesto Principles.&#xA;The older version was published in May 2009.&#xA;I found quite interesting the precision of the Scrum Master’s responsibility.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scrum Master is a full-time Role</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/scrum-master-is-a-full-time-role/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/scrum-master-is-a-full-time-role/</guid>
      <description>I am very happy we discuss in depth the role, responsibilities and activities of a good Scrum Master. I fully agree with Scrum advocates that Scrum Master is a dedicated full-time job.&#xA;I am also convinced a Scrum Master can support multiple experienced Scrum teams. The Large Scale Scrum framework LeSS states a full-time Scrum Master supports 1 to 3 teams.&#xA;I worked with quite a few Scrum Masters, Product Owners, and Scrum teams.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Books for Persons interested in Agile Approaches</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/books-for-persons-interested-in-agile-approaches/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/books-for-persons-interested-in-agile-approaches/</guid>
      <description>I am often told that it is difficult to use Agile/Scrum approaches for brown field projects or for big projects or for distributed projects or for in other situations.&#xA;Interestingly, these people also state that the same problems exist with traditional approaches such as RUP/OpenUP, Waterfall Model, V Model defined as a formal standard in Germany V-Modell Entwicklungsstandard, and the Swiss variant called HERMES.&#xA;Agile approaches are currently the standard for new projects and are thought in technical universities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PMI-ACP Certification</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/pmi-acp-certification/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/pmi-acp-certification/</guid>
      <description>Unknown reference: lean-agile-software-develpment I learnt quite a few new acronyms and techniques when studying for the PMI-ACP certification program. In this post, I collected these acronyms, some definition and the bibliography you should know before attending the examination.&#xA;The main advantage of having it is that you no longer need to argue with PMI certified product managers if agile is applicable to software projects.&#xA;The main interest of PMI-ACP certification is their collection of concepts taken from Agile, eXtreme Programming, Scrum and Lean.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Agile Methods - Scrum - Motivate your Team?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/do-agile-methods-scrum-motivate-your-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/do-agile-methods-scrum-motivate-your-team/</guid>
      <description>Decision makers and waterfall aficionados loudly ask if agile approaches are worth the hype.&#xA;Does the approach really promote team work?&#xA;Well, my current experience is that the answer is a sounding YES.&#xA;Developers love to develop software products using Scrum. The motivation and positive energy just explode.&#xA;People talk together, build as a team better products and enjoy the daily activities.&#xA;Stakeholders and customers or users embrace the advantages they get.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minimizing Undone Work when Working with Regulatory Departments</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/minimizing-undone-work-when-working-with-regulatory-departments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/minimizing-undone-work-when-working-with-regulatory-departments/</guid>
      <description>The Scrum and agile mantra is to have a ready-to-ship product each time a sprint is completed. You must avoid any incomplete activities at any price.&#xA;Incomplete activities are also called Undone Work. They are technical debts in your software, hindering its delivery to users. They are expended money you cannot invoice to your customers.&#xA;Regulatory and traditional quality insurance departments request all kinds of documents, such as review, test results, risk analysis matrix.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
