<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2016 on tangly Components</title>
    <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2016 on tangly Components</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What you do NOT need to do in Scrum!</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/what-you-do-not-need-to-do-in-scrum/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/what-you-do-not-need-to-do-in-scrum/</guid>
      <description>I often hear discussions asking who is performing the traditional product leader tasks in Scrum.&#xA;This is in general an excuse to state that Scrum alone cannot work and classical product leaders are still needed.&#xA;I encourage you to classify these so-called regular product manager activities. Often these jobs are plain reporting progress to various boards and micromanaging the development team.&#xA;I truly acknowledge the importance and value of a line manager caring for his collaborators and nurturing the success of the products they develop.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Found a Limited Liability Company in Switzerland</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/found-a-limited-liability-company-in-switzerland/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/found-a-limited-liability-company-in-switzerland/</guid>
      <description>I left the company I founded 20 years ago and needed a new home to work and have access to social insurance.&#xA;The best legal construct in Switzerland and in Europe is to establish a limited liability company.&#xA;You need such a construct in Switzerland to work as a software specialist. The legal Swiss institutions, such as taxes, social insurances, and accident insurances are challenging and almost unfair with freelancers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is an Agile Company?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/what-is-an-agile-company/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/what-is-an-agile-company/</guid>
      <description>Lately, people often ask me what is an agile company.&#xA;They have an understanding of agile software development techniques such as Scrum, Lean Software Development, Kanban, eXtreme Programming but no clue how a company could be agile.&#xA;What does it mean to be an agile organization?&#xA;One way to approach this theme is to implement concepts of the above-mentioned agile approaches.&#xA;These are the pillars for iterative incremental improvements.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Trends Switzerland 2013</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/agile-trends-switzerland-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/agile-trends-switzerland-2013/</guid>
      <description>What are the main hurdles to introducing agile approaches in Swiss companies?&#xA;Introducing agile company-wide is a cultural change process. Such a change takes time and sometimes hurts.&#xA;Without the commitment of senior management, the initiative will fail.&#xA;Doubt that lean or agile works for big projects, doubt you can convince your collaborators and middle management, doubt your customers agree with lean,&#xA;In the end, what matters are collaborator purpose, customer satisfaction, business value.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Trends Switzerland 2012</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/agile-trends-switzerland-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/agile-trends-switzerland-2012/</guid>
      <description>What are the main hurdles to introducing agile approaches in Swiss companies?&#xA;Introducing agile company-wide is a cultural change process. Such a change takes time and sometimes hurts.&#xA;Without the commitment of senior management, the initiative will fail.&#xA;Doubt that lean or agile works, doubt you can find agile experts, doubt that your projects can be realised with agile approaches.&#xA;In the end, what matters are collaborator purpose, customer satisfaction, business value.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Git Branches for the Impatient</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/git-branches-for-the-impatient/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/git-branches-for-the-impatient/</guid>
      <description>You are working in a small mostly collocated development team. Sometimes a team member works from a remote location.&#xA;You have one git repository accessible to all team members.&#xA;This repository is used to share source code and documentation artifacts.&#xA;You use the actual industrial standard for version control systems is git.&#xA;You decided to use branches to implement new features or fix errors instead of using Trunk-Based Development.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Version of the Scrum Guide 2011</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/the-version-of-the-scrum-guide-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/the-version-of-the-scrum-guide-2011/</guid>
      <description>The new version of the Scrum Guide written by Ken Schwaber and Jeff Sutherland has been available since July 2011.&#xA;You should regularly read the Scrum guide to reflect how your teams are applying agile principles and ideas.&#xA;You should also consult the seminal Agile Manifesto and the 12 Agile Manifesto Principles.&#xA;The older version was published in May 2009.&#xA;I found quite interesting the precision of the Scrum Master’s responsibility.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scrum Master is a full-time Role</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/scrum-master-is-a-full-time-role/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/scrum-master-is-a-full-time-role/</guid>
      <description>I am very happy we discuss in depth the role, responsibilities and activities of a good Scrum Master. I fully agree with Scrum advocates that Scrum Master is a dedicated full-time job.&#xA;I am also convinced a Scrum Master can support multiple experienced Scrum teams. The Large Scale Scrum framework LeSS states a full-time Scrum Master supports 1 to 3 teams.&#xA;I worked with quite a few Scrum Masters, Product Owners, and Scrum teams.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Books for Persons interested in Agile Approaches</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/books-for-persons-interested-in-agile-approaches/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/books-for-persons-interested-in-agile-approaches/</guid>
      <description>I am often told that it is difficult to use Agile/Scrum approaches for brown field projects or for big projects or for distributed projects or for in other situations.&#xA;Interestingly, these people also state that the same problems exist with traditional approaches such as RUP/OpenUP, Waterfall Model, V Model defined as a formal standard in Germany V-Modell Entwicklungsstandard, and the Swiss variant called HERMES.&#xA;Agile approaches are currently the standard for new projects and are thought in technical universities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PMI-ACP Certification</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/pmi-acp-certification/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/pmi-acp-certification/</guid>
      <description>Unknown reference: lean-agile-software-develpment I learnt quite a few new acronyms and techniques when studying for the PMI-ACP certification program. In this post, I collected these acronyms, some definition and the bibliography you should know before attending the examination.&#xA;The main advantage of having it is that you no longer need to argue with PMI certified product managers if agile is applicable to software projects.&#xA;The main interest of PMI-ACP certification is their collection of concepts taken from Agile, eXtreme Programming, Scrum and Lean.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I use a MacBookPro and OS X</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/why-i-use-a-macbookpro-and-os-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/why-i-use-a-macbookpro-and-os-x/</guid>
      <description>I loved Linux as a young developer. I compiled new kernels during evening sessions. I worked hard to install and configure drivers to support the hardware I had bought.&#xA;I explored forums and talked with technical support specialists to activate hardware or support the resolution of my display. I struggled days to have the correct drivers for the graphic card and communication components of my notebook.&#xA;I grew older and decided to enjoy my evenings and weekends with my family and friends.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Agile Methods - Scrum - Motivate your Team?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/do-agile-methods-scrum-motivate-your-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/do-agile-methods-scrum-motivate-your-team/</guid>
      <description>Decision makers and waterfall aficionados loudly ask if agile approaches are worth the hype.&#xA;Does the approach really promote team work?&#xA;Well, my current experience is that the answer is a sounding YES.&#xA;Developers love to develop software products using Scrum. The motivation and positive energy just explode.&#xA;People talk together, build as a team better products and enjoy the daily activities.&#xA;Stakeholders and customers or users embrace the advantages they get.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minimizing Undone Work when Working with Regulatory Departments</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/minimizing-undone-work-when-working-with-regulatory-departments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/minimizing-undone-work-when-working-with-regulatory-departments/</guid>
      <description>The Scrum and agile mantra is to have a ready-to-ship product each time a sprint is completed. You must avoid any incomplete activities at any price.&#xA;Incomplete activities are also called Undone Work. They are technical debts in your software, hindering its delivery to users. They are expended money you cannot invoice to your customers.&#xA;Regulatory and traditional quality insurance departments request all kinds of documents, such as review, test results, risk analysis matrix.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
