<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tangly on tangly Components</title>
    <link>https://blog.tangly.net/tags/tangly/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tangly on tangly Components</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.tangly.net/tags/tangly/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How To Improve</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/how-to-improve/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/how-to-improve/</guid>
      <description>You attended a famous or a local technical school. You are the proud owner of a bachelor or a master degree in science.&#xA;You are a certified engineer.&#xA;You are now a full-time software developer. You write daily productive code with your colleagues in your current company.&#xA;Hopefully you studied software engineering at least as a minor.&#xA;How can you continuously improve in your profession?&#xA;How can you become proficient in the new features and possibilities of the technologies you use daily?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Quest for an Agile Company: Eight Years tangly llc</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/the-quest-for-an-agile-company-eight-years-tangly-llc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/the-quest-for-an-agile-company-eight-years-tangly-llc/</guid>
      <description>We are an agile and software technology boutique.&#xA;We often work as Scrum masters, product owners and technical agile coaches. Regularly we are involved in the architecture and development of software products.&#xA;Our collaborators love to coaching, mentoring, and training.&#xA;We regularly work at the customer site. We also more and more often work online with our international customers.&#xA;How do you organize such a company?&#xA;How do collaborators work together?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Quest for an Agile Company: Seven Years tangly llc</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/the-quest-for-an-agile-company-seven-years-tangly-llc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/the-quest-for-an-agile-company-seven-years-tangly-llc/</guid>
      <description>We are an agile software coaching and digital product development boutique.&#xA;Since our inception, we have created digital products using agile approaches. Our preferred tools are Scrum, Lean Software Development, DevOps, LeSS.&#xA;The created digital products are successful in the market.&#xA;They exhibit good quality. Sound engineering approaches were used to design and construct them in a timely and economical way.&#xA;Our customers learnt how to deploy updates and new functionalities in a matter of days.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Quest for an Agile Company: Six Years tangly llc</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/the-quest-for-an-agile-company-six-years-tangly-llc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/the-quest-for-an-agile-company-six-years-tangly-llc/</guid>
      <description>Historically, big beats small. Scale was a sufficient advantage to be successful in the market.&#xA;Now, fast and adaptive beats slow and steadfast.&#xA;New technologies, evolving customer preferences and changing employee expectations are fundamentally challenging established ways of working [1].&#xA;It is time to move beyond rigid hierarchies, siloed business units, crippling bureaucracy and an increasingly unwieldy matrix.&#xA;Agile organizations combine the efficiencies of scale with the speed, flexibility and resilience to compete and win in today’s world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Quest for an Agile Company: Five Years tangly llc</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/the-quest-for-an-agile-company-five-years-tangly-llc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/the-quest-for-an-agile-company-five-years-tangly-llc/</guid>
      <description>An agile company is a business with the ability to quickly adapt to market changes [1].&#xA;tangly is an agile and digital development boutique. We must swiftly react to market changes to survive.&#xA;Agility is woven into our culture and processes.&#xA;Agile organizations must be fast-moving and flexible, have rapid response to unexpected obstacles, lead change, be in touch with customers.&#xA;They have a continuous competitive advantage, and a flat organizational structure for quick communication [2].</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Journey to be a Digital Company - tangly llc</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/a-journey-to-be-a-digital-company-tangly-llc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/a-journey-to-be-a-digital-company-tangly-llc/</guid>
      <description>I long dreamed of working in a digital environment. I shall no longer print out a form, sign it by hand and use snake mail to deliver it to the receiving party. All company documents are stored electronically. I can search any artifacts by content and get a list of all interesting items in seconds.&#xA;Our software service company is an ideal candidate to validate if this assumption is realistic.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is Our Specialty as Agile Coaches at tangly?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/what-is-our-specialty-as-agile-coaches-at-tangly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/what-is-our-specialty-as-agile-coaches-at-tangly/</guid>
      <description>You have more agile coaches on the market than sand-corns on a regular beach.&#xA;They all promise the holly grail of agile product development, highly productive teams and perfect applications for internal and external customers.&#xA;Why should any sane customer hire us to deploy or perfect their agile approach?&#xA;Your overall goal is to continuously improve the products delivered to customers.&#xA;I am convinced to achieve ingrained success an agile coach shall:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fun at Workplace</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/fun-at-workplace/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/fun-at-workplace/</guid>
      <description>It is Spring in Switzerland. We often have time for small talk because it is cold or rainy outside.&#xA;Quite a few of the discussions are about job opportunities, and how interesting and motivating the current activities are.&#xA;I selected two articles to help everybody to decide if your software development job is worth the effort.&#xA;Go through the questions and ask yourself if the current product provides the current settings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Found a Limited Liability Company in Switzerland</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/found-a-limited-liability-company-in-switzerland/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/found-a-limited-liability-company-in-switzerland/</guid>
      <description>I left the company I founded 20 years ago and needed a new home to work and have access to social insurance.&#xA;The best legal construct in Switzerland and in Europe is to establish a limited liability company.&#xA;You need such a construct in Switzerland to work as a software specialist. The legal Swiss institutions, such as taxes, social insurances, and accident insurances are challenging and almost unfair with freelancers.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
