<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Series-How-Healthy on tangly Components</title>
    <link>https://blog.tangly.net/tags/series-how-healthy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Series-How-Healthy on tangly Components</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.tangly.net/tags/series-how-healthy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Healthy is Your Product? - Company Culture Check</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/how-healthy-is-your-product-company-culture-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/how-healthy-is-your-product-company-culture-check/</guid>
      <description>You are developing your application using agile and lean approaches.&#xA;How can you check your approach and distill improvements?&#xA;Health check of your product and your development approach are certainly a good solution.&#xA;This post is the fourth and last of a set of articles identifying health checks with different focus.&#xA;We will identify strengths, potential weaknesses and hopefully find room for improvement.&#xA;What is your company culture?&#xA;How are collaborators focused on delighting your customers?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Healthy is Your Product? - Product Strategy Check</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/how-healthy-is-your-product-product-strategy-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/how-healthy-is-your-product-product-strategy-check/</guid>
      <description>You are developing your product using agile and lean approaches.&#xA;How can you check your approach and distill improvements?&#xA;Health check of your product and your development approach are certainly a good solution.&#xA;This post is the third of a set of articles identifying health checks with different focus. We will identify strengths, potential weaknesses and hopefully find room for improvement.&#xA;What is your product strategy? How do you involve your customers and stakeholders?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Healthy is Your Product? - Delivery Pipeline Check</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/how-healthy-is-your-product-delivery-pipeline-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/how-healthy-is-your-product-delivery-pipeline-check/</guid>
      <description>You are developing your product using agile and lean approaches.&#xA;How can you check your approach and distill improvements? A health check of your product and your development approach is certainly a good solution.&#xA;This post is the second of a series identifying health checks with different focus. We will identify strengths, potential weaknesses and hopefully find room for improvement.&#xA;How you build and deliver your software product has direct implications on your liquidity and cash flow.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Healthy is Your Product? - Source Code Check</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/how-healthy-is-your-product-source-code-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/how-healthy-is-your-product-source-code-check/</guid>
      <description>You are developing your product using agile and lean approaches.&#xA;How can you check your approach and distill improvements? Health check of your product and your development approach are certainly a good solution.&#xA;This post is the first of a series identifying health checks with different focus. We will identify strengths, potential weaknesses and hopefully find room for improvement.&#xA;The initial examination shall always be the source code. Your code base is a key asset of your company.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
