<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>BDD - Behavior Driven Development on tangly Components</title>
    <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/bdd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in BDD - Behavior Driven Development on tangly Components</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.tangly.net/docs/bdd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Readme</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/bdd/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/bdd/readme/</guid>
      <description>Purpose A behavior-driven development library that provides a custom extension based on the JUnit 5 Jupiter Extension Model. This library can be used to create and run stories and behaviors as BDD specification tests.&#xA;The library is a developer-first approach. Developers write acceptance tests to validate the functions they have implemented. The generated report provides a living documentation of the features and allows customers to validate the acceptance criteria.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Release Notes</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/bdd/releasesnotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/bdd/releasesnotes/</guid>
      <description>BDD Library Change Logs This document provides a high-level view of the changes introduced in the BDD library by release. For a detailed view of what has changed, refer to the repository commits.&#xA;0.2.7 (2024.05.31) Update of library dependencies, update to JDK-21, and modern Gradle approach to build solutions.&#xA;0.2.6 (2021-08-31) Update of the dependencies&#xA;0.2.5 (2020-08-31) Update of the dependencies&#xA;0.2.4 (2020-06-30) BDD library is now a regular Java 9 module (thanks to the new module support in Gradle 6.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>User Guide Behavior Driven Design Library</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/bdd/userguidebdd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/bdd/userguidebdd/</guid>
      <description>Ideas Behavior-driven development BDD is an agile software development process that encourages collaboration among developers, quality assurance experts, and customer representatives in a software project. It encourages teams to use conversation and concrete examples to formalize a shared understanding of how the application should behave. It emerged from test-driven development TDD. Behavior-driven development combines the general techniques and principles of TDD with ideas from domain-driven design and object-oriented analysis and design to provide software development and management teams with shared tools and a shared process to collaborate on software development.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>bdd Report</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/bdd/bdd-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/bdd/bdd-report/</guid>
      <description>Feature: Sell items to customers The customer can buy various items from the store. Upon completion the stock of the store reflects the purchasing action. The store carries black and blue sweaters. The store should refuse to sell more sweaters than it has in stock.&#xA;tags: &amp;#39;Feature Example&amp;#39; &amp;#39;Mandatory&amp;#39;&#xA;Story: Buy Sweater As a store owner I want to update the stock when I am selling sweaters to customers.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
