<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Devops on tangly Components</title>
    <link>https://blog.tangly.net/tags/devops/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Devops on tangly Components</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.tangly.net/tags/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Agile Visual Tools</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/agile-visual-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/agile-visual-tools/</guid>
      <description>Why is visibility so important for any agile or Scrum team?&#xA;When you are running an agile product development initiative, your ultimate goal is customer satisfaction with the delivered solution.&#xA;The project coordination responsibilities are, however, not limited to this single goal.&#xA;The product owner shall nurture the vision, roadmap, the release plan and customer journey. You must coordinate the workflow of your team, refine the product backlog, control identified risks, and track deadlines.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Corporate Governance for Software Products</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/corporate-governance-for-software-products/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/corporate-governance-for-software-products/</guid>
      <description>Since good governance is about the processes for making and implementing decisions, then effective governance and accountability structures are vital.&#xA;Organizations shall successfully use an agile approach to deliver business change through the investment in programs and projects.&#xA;Agile approaches are the most used frameworks to develop successfully digital products.&#xA;Our corporate governance processes shall support agile values and development methods.&#xA;The four guiding principles to enable successful governance of agile delivery are:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SME IT Responsible</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/sme-it-responsible/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/sme-it-responsible/</guid>
      <description>What does a senior manager in charge of information technology?&#xA;An IT director is the information technology right-hand man of the company’s manager. He sometimes has the shiny title of CIO. He proposes and implements the IT strategy of the company.&#xA;He intervenes at different levels in the management and optimization of the company’s information system.&#xA;This encompasses hardware and software infrastructures, information architecture, business tools, dedicated internal or external human resources, and often old technology.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Steps DevOps</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/first-steps-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/first-steps-devops/</guid>
      <description>The DevOps movement started to gather momentum with the first DevOps conference held in Ghent, Belgium in 2009 [1].&#xA;The approach aims to shorten the system development life-cycle and to provide continuous delivery with high software quality. DevOps is complementary with agile software development approaches.&#xA;Several DevOps aspects came from the Agile method.&#xA;Seminal books [1, 2, 3, 4] and good practices were published around the same time.&#xA;The DevOps approach belongs to the regular instruments of professional software developers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transfer a Software Project</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/transfer-a-software-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/transfer-a-software-project/</guid>
      <description>You developed a new digital product for an internal or external customer. Your solution is awesome.&#xA;The product is released to delighted users. Your users love your solution.&#xA;The project is now winding down and closing activities are initiated. The customer organization shall take ownership of all product related artifacts. The handover is a vital part of closing a project [1].&#xA;Your customer paid for the development and own the produced artifacts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing DevOps Ideas</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/introducing-devops-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/introducing-devops-ideas/</guid>
      <description>Your organization heard of DevOps, and your developers clamor you should adopt the approach.&#xA;Each organization I talk with has some DevOps initiative. Often because they read that DevOps approach puts customers and end-user satisfaction at the center.&#xA;Does DevOps really improve the quality of your digital products and customer satisfaction?&#xA;Or is it only the next silver bullet fad used to increase the bonus of consultants and managers?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DevOps for Small Applications</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/devops-for-small-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/devops-for-small-applications/</guid>
      <description>DevOps is the combination of cultural philosophies, practices and tools that increase an organization’s ability to deliver at high velocity.&#xA;It evolves and improves products at a faster pace than organizations using traditional software development and infrastructure management processes.&#xA;This speed enables organizations to better serve their customers [1, 2].&#xA;A surprising side effect of this speed-up is a documented improvement of the delivered quality.&#xA;How It Works Under a DevOps model, development and operations teams are no longer siloed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gitlab for Bachelor Students</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/gitlab-for-bachelor-students/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/gitlab-for-bachelor-students/</guid>
      <description>Computer science students shall be proficient with a basic set of software development techniques.&#xA;Technical excellence is a mandatory skill for all software developers.&#xA;Agile development approaches are state of the industry and used in almost all software development initiatives.&#xA;DevOps approaches are used in modern organizations. They predate agile development approaches.&#xA;Technical schools should provide an in-depth experience in these areas to prepare their students for their future activities after completing their bachelor.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
