<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Embedded on tangly Components</title>
    <link>https://blog.tangly.net/tags/embedded/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Embedded on tangly Components</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.tangly.net/tags/embedded/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Domain-Driven Design with ROS-2</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/domain-driven-design-with-ros-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/domain-driven-design-with-ros-2/</guid>
      <description>At its core, Robot Operation System provides a message-passing system, often called middleware.&#xA;Communication is one of the first needs to arise when implementing a new robot application, or really any software system that will interact with hardware. ROS’s built-in and well-tested messaging system saves you time by managing the details of communication between distributed nodes via an anonymous Publish and Subscribe Pattern.&#xA;This approach encourages good practices in your software development, including fault isolation, Seperation of Concerns, and clear interfaces.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Actors with CMSIS OS in Cpp</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/actors-with-cmsis-os-in-cpp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/actors-with-cmsis-os-in-cpp/</guid>
      <description>The actor library defines the actor abstraction with mailboxes and concrete implementation for various target platforms.&#xA;The CMSIS-RTOS v2 platform provides an actor implementation for all realtime kernels supporting the CMSIS API. The API is under the stewardship of ARM company.&#xA;Any kernel with a CMSIS-RTOS v2 compatible layer is eligible.&#xA;STM provides the CMSIS integration with freeRTOS for all STM32 microcontrollers.&#xA;Library The library defines key abstractions as abstract classes [1] [2].</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bus Sensors and Actuators</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/bus-sensors-and-actuators/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/bus-sensors-and-actuators/</guid>
      <description>Your embedded system has a set of sensors and actors.&#xA;Some sensors and actors are connected to a bus. Typical buses are CAN bus, Serial Peripherical Interface, Ethernet, Bluetooth, or I2C standards.&#xA;The bus is a shared medium used to communicate with a set of external active or passive components.&#xA;Which design rules shall you follow when designing sensors and actors using a bus architecture?&#xA;Do you need to consider threading design?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sensors and Actuators</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/sensors-and-actuators/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/sensors-and-actuators/</guid>
      <description>Embedded design maps domain abstractions to the underlying hardware.&#xA;A temperature sensor is a domain abstraction of a physical hardware temperature sensor.&#xA;A valve is a domain abstraction of a physical hardware valve. A physical valve can be a simple opened-closed device, or a proportional device.&#xA;The microcontroller board reads the temperature sensor through an I2C or SPI bus. It controls the valve through a GPIO, a PWM or a CAN bus controller.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
