<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Java on tangly Components</title>
    <link>https://blog.tangly.net/tags/java/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Java on tangly Components</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.tangly.net/tags/java/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>I Love My Nerdy Job</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/i-love-my-nerdy-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/i-love-my-nerdy-job/</guid>
      <description>I am a computer science engineer. I love to solve problems and provide cool solutions to users [1].&#xA;I love my software development job. I am already sixty years old. I started programming before I was 20.&#xA;And I still tremendously love developing digital products and writing software applications.&#xA;My passion is tinkering with source code to have a maintainable and efficient solution. I love to work with other developers and to coach them to become better software engineers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Actor Model</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/actor-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/actor-model/</guid>
      <description>Concurrent programming has always been tricky. Accessing a shared state from multiple threads is a central problem, where hard-to-catch errors may easily appear.&#xA;Protected access to identified shared variables is easy to realize. Mechanisms to avoid deadlocks or starvation are cumbersome to implement and almost impossible to validate.&#xA;The need for concurrent programming has increased tremendously with the fact that all modern processors and many microcontrollers have multiple cores.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Document Your Software Architecture</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/how-to-document-your-software-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/how-to-document-your-software-architecture/</guid>
      <description>You are creating the next digital software masterpiece.&#xA;How can you document your software architecture in a way that is useful for your team and stakeholders?&#xA;A software architecture document SAD is a document that describes the structure of a software solution.&#xA;It includes the architecture of its components, the relationships between those components, and the principles that guide its design.&#xA;The solution architecture document is typically used as a reference for designing, building, and maintaining a software system.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modern Java Rant</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/modern-java-rant/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/modern-java-rant/</guid>
      <description>The Java community releases a new version every six months. This is a good thing, it means that the language is evolving at a steady pace.&#xA;New language features are added in each release. Much effort is put into improving the performance of the JVM and solving small issues.&#xA;The community provides beta releases for developers to test and provide feedback during the six months before the next release. You have the possibility and time to migrate and test your code before the official release.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure Your Concurrency</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/structure-your-concurrency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/structure-your-concurrency/</guid>
      <description>Writing concurrent software is one of the greatest challenges for software developers [1, 2].&#xA;A professional software developer must understand the principles of concurrent programming and the tools available to write concurrent software.&#xA;Only concurrent applications can access all cores of modern multicore processors and provide the best performance.&#xA;Java thread model makes it a strong contender among concurrent languages, but multithreading has always been inherently tricky.&#xA;The introduction of virtual threads empowered Java to provide a unique and highly-optimized threading system that is also easy to understand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java Modules</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/java-modules/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/java-modules/</guid>
      <description>Java 9 introduces a new level of abstraction above packages, known as the Java Platform Module System JPMS, or Modules for short [1].&#xA;Modules emphasize at compilation time modern software engineering principles such as encapsulation, and modularity [2, 3, 4].&#xA;Java 9 was released in September 2017.&#xA;Most Java developers are still not using this powerful and elegant construct to modularize their applications.&#xA;Modules A module is a group of closely related Java packages and resources along with a new module descriptor file.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Streams</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/advanced-streams/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/advanced-streams/</guid>
      <description>The Java Stream API is a powerful and simple to understand set of tools for processing sequences of elements. The standard collections were retrofitted with the stream() method, which allows us to convert any collection to a stream.&#xA;Modern Java code has almost no loops and conditional statements. It relies on the Stream API and the functional programming style to implement algorithms.&#xA;When used properly, it allows us to reduce a huge amount of boilerplate code, create more readable programs, and improve productivity [1, 2].</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EclipseStore</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/eclipsestore/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/eclipsestore/</guid>
      <description>Eclipse Store [1] is a Java-native persistence layer built for cloud-native microservices and serverless systems. EclipseStore is the only data storage solution that uses the native Java object model instead of database-specific structure or format.&#xA;It enables storing any Java object graph of any size and complexity transaction-safe into any binary data storage such as plain files, persistent volumes, or cloud object storage.&#xA;Snapshots of the object graph differences are regularly saved to the storage.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Classes, Sealed Types and Pattern Matching</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/data-classes-sealed-types-and-pattern-matching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/data-classes-sealed-types-and-pattern-matching/</guid>
      <description>Records, sealed types, enumerations are the key language features for Algebraic Data Types.&#xA;The features have been available since Java 17.&#xA;Latter JDK releases provide additional capabilities and syntactic sugar.&#xA;Based on the features of JDK 22, we are still missing with constructors for records and primitive support for pattern matching [1].&#xA;Pattern matching capabilities empower the developer to implement complex algorithms in a compact and legible way.&#xA;Patterns such as visitor pattern are obsolete.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Command Interpreter</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/command-interpreter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/command-interpreter/</guid>
      <description>Most digital products have a command interpreter.&#xA;External systems send requests to the system and often await an answer. A command interpreter can model this behavior.&#xA;The channels used to transmit requests and return answers are variable. Messages can be transmitted other various buses and protocols.&#xA;An operator can send a command over a CAN bus, Serial Peripherical Interface, Ethernet or Bluetooth connection.&#xA;A regular command line interpreter inputs commands as a string containing a request and associated parameters.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gradle Good Practices</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/gradle-good-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/gradle-good-practices/</guid>
      <description>Gradle Build Tool is a fast, dependable, and adaptable open-source build automation tool with an elegant and extensible declarative build language. Java is the primary supported programming language.&#xA;Gradle Build Tool is a popular build system for the JVM and is the default system for Android and Kotlin Multi-Platform projects.&#xA;It has a rich community plugin ecosystem. Groovy, Kotlin, C++, and Swift stacks are well-supported.&#xA;Gradle is fast, scalable, and can build projects of any size and complexity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java Certification</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/java-certification/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/java-certification/</guid>
      <description>Java expertise is in high demand for all kinds of projects, ranging from big enterprise software implementations down to little web projects. A huge number of enterprise applications are developed in Java.&#xA;But will those employers want you to have related certifications?&#xA;Even if you are not looking to move any time soon, getting certified boosts the value that you can bring to your organization.&#xA;Certifications can be a great bargaining chip when it comes to negotiating a raise or a promotion.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20th Devoxx Belgium Conference 2023</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/20th-devoxx-belgium-conference-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/20th-devoxx-belgium-conference-2023/</guid>
      <description>I attended the highly anticipated 20th edition of Devoxx Belgium 2023.&#xA;Building on the success of the previous year, which attracted over 3,200 attendees, this five-day technology conference is set to exceed expectations.&#xA;The fresh release of Java 21 is a hot topic. Renowned speakers share their knowledge and discuss the enhancements that this new version brings, providing a valuable learning opportunity.&#xA;Attending Devoxx Belgium presents a remarkable opportunity to broaden your knowledge, refine your skills, and gain firsthand experience with the most recent technologies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java 21</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/java-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/java-21/</guid>
      <description>Java 21 LTS was released on time to the public. The release has been available for download since 21st September 2023.&#xA;Pattern matching is maturing nicely. The hope is that more solutions will more advanced data stream manipulation and functional programming algorithms. Complex inheritance structure are no more considered as good practices in regular application. The pattern matching extensions nicely provide idioms to solve similar design problems.&#xA;The support for virtual threads is reaching full integration in the official Java distribution.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Onboarding Software Developers in Your agile Team</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/onboarding-software-developers-in-your-agile-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/onboarding-software-developers-in-your-agile-team/</guid>
      <description>Now that you have gone through the long and tedious process of hiring a talented developer with vetting and interview activities, it is easy to think that the hard part is done [1] [2].&#xA;There is no doubt that hiring good people is challenging and competitive, but it is a mistake to think that the challenge ends when you hired a new collaborator.&#xA;Onboarding software developers is just as important for getting the most out of the hiring process.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java 20</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/java-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/java-20/</guid>
      <description>Java 20 was released on time to the public. The release has been available for download since 21st March 2023.&#xA;Interestingly, the new Java release contains only incubating or preview JEP proposals. No final improvements are part of this version.&#xA;You are a Java developer, you should always install the latest JDK and try it out. Most of the time, all your products will compile and run on the new release without any changes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Software Developer Assumptions</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/software-developer-assumptions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/software-developer-assumptions/</guid>
      <description>Here are some software development topics I have learnt to like after 40 years in the industry.&#xA;I worked at quite a few industrial and commercial digital product development initiatives. I truly enjoyed creating successful solutions.&#xA;Over the years, I encountered similar architecture and design patterns when creating source code for these applications.&#xA;I started programming with languages such as Ada, Portal, and C. I embraced object-oriented languages with first C++ and later Java.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Module Test Reporting with Gradle 7.x</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/multi-module-test-reporting-with-gradle-7.x/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/multi-module-test-reporting-with-gradle-7.x/</guid>
      <description>I love Gradle as the building tool for all my Java projects.&#xA;But sometimes I was discouraged about how spotty or cumbersome the support for multi-module project is.&#xA;I struggled for years to generate test and code overage reports over modules included in a Gradle Build Tool project.&#xA;Gradle finally provides a better approach to generate aggregated test and code coverage reports over multiple modules belonging to the same project.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Behavior Driven Design</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/behavior-driven-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/behavior-driven-design/</guid>
      <description>Domain-Driven Design DDD has been around since Eric Evans published his book about the subject in 2003 [1].&#xA;Vernon Vaugh published powerful approaches how to implement DDD concepts into a software solution [2, 3].&#xA;How do you validate and test your DDD digital solutions?&#xA;Behavior Driven Development BDD is an inversion how systems are often developed. In some ways, it is an extension of Test Driven Development TDD approach to the whole application.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modern Java Constructs</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/modern-java-constructs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/modern-java-constructs/</guid>
      <description>Modern Java is quite a departure from the traditional Java available at the beginning of the millennium.&#xA;The most visible change is certainly lambda expressions and stream, enabling a more functional programming approach in Java.&#xA;Functional programming is a paradigm that supports developers to think in terms of functions instead of classes. Functions are stateless and without side effects. Avoiding state can lead to better software, especially in high-performance, concurrent applications [1].</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vaadin</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/vaadin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/vaadin/</guid>
      <description>Vaadin is an ideal solution if you are a Java developer and wants to provide a user interface for your product. Vaadin is a framework to create graphical user interfaces using plain Java, or any JVM-based language for that matter.&#xA;You develop in Java, and the framework takes care of all the rest. It generates the client-side code, and the communication between the client-side code in the browser and the backend code on the server.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modular Monoliths are the new Graal</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/modular-monoliths-are-the-new-graal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/modular-monoliths-are-the-new-graal/</guid>
      <description>A modular monolith is a software design approach in which a monolith is designed with an emphasis on interchangeable and potentially reusable modules.&#xA;A modular monolith can be split in the future into a set of microservices.&#xA;Delay the split as long as you can. Microservices have a steep price tag during operations.&#xA;A modular monolith provides:&#xA;Independent and parallel development approach.&#xA;Diminish coupling and improve cohesion. The interfaces are better documented and thinner.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Software Structure with DDD</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/software-structure-with-ddd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/software-structure-with-ddd/</guid>
      <description>Domain Driven Development DDD is the preferred software architecture approach for designing digital products. The method nicely matches with the operational concepts of microservices.&#xA;Domain-driven design is a holistic approach to understanding, designing and building software applications.&#xA;Seminal books [1, 2, 3] describes the approach and key concepts defining the development method.&#xA;Concrete recipes and examples of code structure are still sparse.&#xA;How should you structure your namespaces and modules?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Measurements and Units</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/measurements-and-units/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/measurements-and-units/</guid>
      <description>JSR-385 could have saved Mars Climate Orbiter[2] in year 1999.&#xA;Accidents in computer applications happen again and again due to calculation errors.&#xA;The International System of Units SI, commonly known as the metric system, is the international standard for measurement.&#xA;The International Treaty of the Mete was signed in Paris on May 20, 1875, by seventeen countries, including the United States.&#xA;In May 2019, the system of units was updated.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yet Another Hybrid Method</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/yet-another-hybrid-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/yet-another-hybrid-method/</guid>
      <description>SoDa Software Development Agile is a homebrew project development method created at the technical university of Lucerne. It is a mixture of Waterfall, RUP and Scrum approaches. It uses a distorted Scrum for the concept and implementation phase[2].&#xA;The documentation was not updated the last ten years. The approach is clinically dead and should not be promoted for active software development efforts.&#xA;A similar approach exists with the official governmental Swiss project method HERMES.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modern Java with Spring</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/modern-java-with-spring/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/modern-java-with-spring/</guid>
      <description>Spring and Spring Boot frameworks are the standard for enterprise Java applications.&#xA;Spring Boot makes it easy to create stand-alone, production-grade Spring-based Applications that you can just run.&#xA;They take an opinionated view of the Spring platform and third-party libraries, so you can get started with minimum fuss.&#xA;Most Spring Boot applications need minimal Spring configuration.&#xA;Minimize Boilerplate Code One of the key reasons for the success of Spring is the approach of convention over configuration.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Immutability in Java</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/immutability-in-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/immutability-in-java/</guid>
      <description>Immutability is a powerful and simple concept in programming theory that is strangely underused.&#xA;An immutable object is simply a class whose instances cannot be modified. This is in contrast to a mutable object or changeable object, which can be modified after it is created.&#xA;Immutable objects are also useful because they are inherently thread-safe. Other benefits are that they are simpler to understand and reason about and offer higher security than mutable objects</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Technical Debt</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/technical-debt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/technical-debt/</guid>
      <description>The technical debt or code debt is a concept in software development that reflects the implied cost of additional rework. The rework is caused by choosing an easy limited solution now instead of using a better approach that would take longer to realize.&#xA;Another source of technical debt is natural technical obsolescence.&#xA;As with monetary debt, if technical debt is not repaid, it accumulates interest, making it harder and harder to implement changes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gradle 7</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/gradle-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/gradle-7/</guid>
      <description>Gradle Build Tool is my preferred build tool for all Java applications I am developing.&#xA;Google chose Gradle as the official build tool for Android.&#xA;Not only because build scripts are code, but because Gradle is modeled in a way that is extensible in the most fundamental ways.&#xA;Gradle’s model also allows it to be used for native development with C/C++ and can be expanded to cover any ecosystem.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JDk 17</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/jdk-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/jdk-17/</guid>
      <description>I truly love the new release rhythm of the Java ecosystem. Every six months a new JDK is delivered. Being able to use new features every six months is awesome.&#xA;The new release JDK 17 [3] is the next long term support LTS release. The migration overhead is held to a minimum thanks to the incredible backward compatibility. The early-access builds give you more than enough opportunities and time to migrate all your applications on time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Technical Team Lead</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/technical-team-lead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/technical-team-lead/</guid>
      <description>I lately had to explain to customers what are the responsibilities of a technical team lead. Managers often grasp the people aspects embedded in the words team lead. The understanding of the word technical is strangely often missing.&#xA;A technical team leads coaches and teaches the subtleties of the used technology stack to his team and organization. This person should be able to create or review a software architecture. He has a deep understanding of technological concepts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Certified Java Developer</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/certified-java-developer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/certified-java-developer/</guid>
      <description>Java is celebrating 25 years of existence.&#xA;I discovered the anniversary offer to certify for Java SE 11 Developer.&#xA;This special certification has a cool logo with the remainder of the Java 25-year anniversary.&#xA;Oracle offers this certification for only 25 dollars [1] and provides free access to their learning platform.&#xA;The offer and logo availability are time limited.&#xA;The free learning subscription includes:&#xA;The Java Explorer learning path for basic Java skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Service for Developer Game Changer</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/self-service-for-developer-game-changer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/self-service-for-developer-game-changer/</guid>
      <description>Often, I hear complain that the IT department is not reacting to developer’s needs. They are slow, clumsy and too administrative. Harsher words state they are incompetent.&#xA;I have observed a clear trend in Switzerland since around 2015 to solve these tensions.&#xA;Standard IT services such as docker images, database instances or internal domain names are provided through self-service kiosks.&#xA;What are the advantages of this approach?&#xA;Advantages The advantages to providing a self-service kiosk for users in an academical or industrial environment are:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JDk 16</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/jdk-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/jdk-16/</guid>
      <description>I truly love the new release rhythm of the Java ecosystem. It is awesome to be able to use new features every six months.&#xA;The migration overhead is held to a minimum thanks to incredible backward compatibility.&#xA;The new features greatly simplify the existing code and tremendously increase legibility.&#xA;Features like records, sealed types, or switch expressions are wonderful. The promise of advanced pattern matching constructs is sweet.&#xA;Polishing of functional programming approach improved my source code quite stupendously.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Software Architecture is Mainstream</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/agile-software-architecture-is-mainstream/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/agile-software-architecture-is-mainstream/</guid>
      <description>Slowly, slowly major actors in the software architecture landscape acknowledge agile development is state of the industry approach to building software products.&#xA;They are still struggling to integrate their older views in a faster, iterative, incremental development approach. The duration of a regular Scrum sprint is usually two weeks.&#xA;More important, they have discovered we build products because no customers buy projects. They buy solutions and products.&#xA;I am relieved I need less fight to convince enterprise architects that agile is the way.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MicroStream 4.x</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/microstream-4.x/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/microstream-4.x/</guid>
      <description>MicroStream approach empowers Java developers. The library provides a cool and compact approach to persist complex data models. You can persist your whole data model with less than a hundred lines of code. The library is efficient and works reliably.&#xA;Modern architectures based on bounded domains and Domain Driven Design are supported.&#xA;The company behind the product has promised to open source their product beginning of 2021.&#xA;I use the library to prototype bounded domain implementations requiring persistent data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modern Java Development</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/modern-java-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/modern-java-development/</guid>
      <description>Java development activities have won traction since the decision to release a new version to the community every six months. Preview and incubator features promote feedback from the community and users.&#xA;Some tool builders, such as JetBrains are working proactively and provide support for JDK in developments.&#xA;Other tool maintainers such as JaCoCo are dreadfully behind the release cycle.&#xA;We learnt to deal with the new speed and how to tackle the laggards.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Is Java Path Class Better?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/why-is-java-path-class-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/why-is-java-path-class-better/</guid>
      <description>Java NIO New Input Output is an alternative IO API for Java, meaning alternative to the standard Java IO and Java Networking APIs.&#xA;Java NIO offers a different IO programming model than the traditional IO APIs.&#xA;One major feature of interest is the support of alternate file systems. An in-memory file system is ideal for test file related operations in unit and integration tests.&#xA;Sometimes NIO is claimed to mean Non-blocking IO.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Software Development for Students</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/software-development-for-students/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/software-development-for-students/</guid>
      <description>Computer science students shall achieve technical excellence when reaching bachelor level. They should be proficient with industry good practices.&#xA;Students understand the theory and principles behind these practices. Experience with one of the best of breed tools enforces learning and automatism.&#xA;The focus of a technical university is to teach the concepts and methods. The tools are used to practice and to increase student learning.&#xA;Source Code Version Management with Git Git is the standard tool for the distributed source code management system.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gitlab for Bachelor Students</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/gitlab-for-bachelor-students/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/gitlab-for-bachelor-students/</guid>
      <description>Computer science students shall be proficient with a basic set of software development techniques.&#xA;Technical excellence is a mandatory skill for all software developers.&#xA;Agile development approaches are state of the industry and used in almost all software development initiatives.&#xA;DevOps approaches are used in modern organizations. They predate agile development approaches.&#xA;Technical schools should provide an in-depth experience in these areas to prepare their students for their future activities after completing their bachelor.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reference Codes</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/reference-codes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/reference-codes/</guid>
      <description>Reference codes are an old concept. They are often used in the relational database schema definition as enumeration values. The database specialists often call them lookup tables.&#xA;Reference codes are dynamic enumeration values. By dynamic, we mean you can add values without recompiling the source code.&#xA;In modern DevOps environments where deployment of a new version is performed in minutes, this advantage is somewhat shallow. We view reference codes more as strongly typed and efficient tags.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The power of Tags and Comments</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/the-power-of-tags-and-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/the-power-of-tags-and-comments/</guid>
      <description>A software architect models customer domains and maps them to excellent software constructs. The solution shall support future customer groups and expand to store additional information.&#xA;Tags, also called labels, provide an informal ontology to classify customer data.&#xA;Tags are extensible and are machine-readable.&#xA;Comments empower users to store relevant unstructured information.&#xA;Comments are only for human beings.&#xA;What are good approaches to provide searchable tags and labels and avoid wild growth of useless records?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Entities, Identifiers, External identifiers and Names</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/entities-identifiers-external-identifiers-and-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/entities-identifiers-external-identifiers-and-names/</guid>
      <description>A software architect models customer domains and maps them to powerful software abstractions [1]. Soon you correlate internal efficient identifiers, meaningful external identifiers, and domain entities.&#xA;You enjoy long conversations with the enterprise data architect and identify the system owning a specific external identifier.&#xA;How do you relate to external systems and communicate with other companies?&#xA;How do you define internal identifiers, which grow with application success?&#xA;How can you bridge the customer world with your software solution?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Journey Implementing Digital Invoices</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/a-journey-implementing-digital-invoices/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/a-journey-implementing-digital-invoices/</guid>
      <description>Our company has the ambition to digitize all our workflows since our inception. We proudly state we never bought a printer or a fax machine. Analog machines should become obsolete in the digital age.&#xA;Companies should be more environment-aware and save some trees. See our blog on A Journey to Be a Digital Company.&#xA;Switzerland finally introduced a digital payment slip. It uses a QR code and still assumes you need to print it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gradle 6.4 Finally Supports Java Modules</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/gradle-6.4-finally-supports-java-modules/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/gradle-6.4-finally-supports-java-modules/</guid>
      <description>Java 9 release introduced the concept of modules within the Java language. Java 9 was released in September 2017.&#xA;Until now, creating Java modules was quite cumbersome and Gradle did only offer limited support through external plugins.&#xA;With the release of Gradle 6.4 in May 2020, software developers can finally easily generate well-behaved Java modules. We had to wait almost three years for native support!&#xA;Support for modules is native in the Java plugin.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Component Design</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/agile-component-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/agile-component-design/</guid>
      <description>You are an experienced programmer. You master your primary technology stack and systematically write clean code.&#xA;Your team recognized your merits and asked you to take ownership of whole packages in the application.&#xA;You are now responsible for creating or modifying a software component in your current application.&#xA;This is a design activity.&#xA;How can you create a good, legible, maintainable component architecture?&#xA;How can you validate your functional and non-functional requirements?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java Records Are Here - Available in JDK 14</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/java-records-are-here-available-in-jdk-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/java-records-are-here-available-in-jdk-14/</guid>
      <description>We need justification not to use immutable objects in our solutions, rather than an affirmative reason to use them. Records provide a first-class means for modeling data-only aggregates. They have been available in Java since the release of JDK 14.&#xA;Records are often seen as syntactic sugar to easily create immutable objects without having to write too much boilerplate code. Records as a clean definition of immutable objects can have a tremendous impact on your component design.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Time to Migrate to a Modern JDK, Laggards!</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/time-to-migrate-to-a-modern-jdk-laggards/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/time-to-migrate-to-a-modern-jdk-laggards/</guid>
      <description>Are you still using Java 8 to run your mission-critical systems?&#xA;Are you truly using daily a six years old technology stack?&#xA;Are you already applying for a Java laggard club membership?&#xA;If you are still using Java 8, you are using technologies released in Spring 2014. You are missing all the improvements in the garbage collector, runtime engine, and various APIs.&#xA;Java 11 LTS was released in September 2018.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sonar Lint for the Impatient</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/sonar-lint-for-the-impatient/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/sonar-lint-for-the-impatient/</guid>
      <description>Remove issues before they reach customer sites. No quality problems shall reach your Git master branch.&#xA;SonarQube is a central server that processes full analyses (triggered by the various SonarQube Scanners).&#xA;Its purpose is to give a 360° vision about the quality of your code base. For this, it analyzes all the source lines of your product on a regular basis.&#xA;It should be added that SonarQube also performs scans with well-known third party analyzers (SpotBugs - previously FindBugs -, Checkstyle, PMD) whereas SonarLint does not include those.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java 10 aka 18.3 Changes</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/java-10-aka-18.3-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/java-10-aka-18.3-changes/</guid>
      <description>Oracle has decided to release a new JDK two times a year.&#xA;The next release of Java 10 aka 18.3 will be available in March 2018.&#xA;JDK 11 aka 18.9 will be released in September 2018. Java 11 will also be a long-term support LTS release.&#xA;For Java to remain competitive, it must not just continue to move forward — it must move forward faster.&#xA;— Mark Reinhold The Visible Change The visible change is the dawn of the keyword var.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why is it so Cool to Develop with Java?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/why-is-it-so-cool-to-develop-with-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/why-is-it-so-cool-to-develop-with-java/</guid>
      <description>Why is it so cool to develop software using Java, a modern IDE and agile tools?&#xA;Because the environment empowers you and incredibly speed-up your development outcomes. In seconds, you know if the next code increment adds value to your product.&#xA;Test driven development and static quality tools are integrated in your IDE. Each time you check some code into your Git repository, all configured checks shall be executed before allowing the commit.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
