<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Agile Expertise on tangly Components</title>
    <link>https://blog.tangly.net/expertise/expertise-agile/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Agile Expertise on tangly Components</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.tangly.net/expertise/expertise-agile/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Agile Organizations</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/expertise/expertise-agile/agile-organizations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/expertise/expertise-agile/agile-organizations/</guid>
      <description>Digital Delivery Our Scrum Masters and agile coaches help organizations develop a foundation of Scrum good practices and grow the internal expertise needed to become a true learning organization.&#xA;Teach Scrum, Kanban on the job Formulate a vision, a roadmap, a release plan and act on Create a team contract and definition of done DoD Continuously improve team effectiveness Growth your Scrum masters and product owners to high performers Agile Techniques Expertly trained agile and Scrum teams are critical to your company’s business agility.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Products</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/expertise/expertise-agile/agile-products/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/expertise/expertise-agile/agile-products/</guid>
      <description>Effective Product Strategy Developing a successful product is not down to luck or trying hard. Product success starts with making the right strategic decisions.&#xA;Validate product strategy with design thinking Review product performance with lean budgets Set the right priorities and establish a growth mindset Implement your digital transformation with your product portfolio Product Leadership with Scrum The product owner is a product management role. Product management is a complex, multi-faceted discipline that takes time and effort to master.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Experiences</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/expertise/expertise-agile/agile-experiences/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/expertise/expertise-agile/agile-experiences/</guid>
      <description>Agile Experiences Context Scrum is the industrial standard to create and develop awesome digital products.&#xA;Scrum Scrum is a minimalist framework empowering your organization to deliver digital products.&#xA;Scrum is an additive framework. Please be pragmatic and professional.&#xA;Roles: Product Owner, Scrum Master, Team Member&#xA;Events: Sprint, Sprint Planning, Daily Scrum, Review, Retrospective, Backlog Refinement&#xA;Artifacts: Product Increment, Product Backlog, Spring Backlog, Definition of Done&#xA;Technical Agile and Scrum</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
