<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2019 on tangly Components</title>
    <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2019 on tangly Components</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Journey to be a Digital Company - tangly llc</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/a-journey-to-be-a-digital-company-tangly-llc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/a-journey-to-be-a-digital-company-tangly-llc/</guid>
      <description>I long dreamed of working in a digital environment. I shall no longer print out a form, sign it by hand and use snake mail to deliver it to the receiving party. All company documents are stored electronically. I can search any artifacts by content and get a list of all interesting items in seconds.&#xA;Our software service company is an ideal candidate to validate if this assumption is realistic.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile @ Scale</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/agile-@-scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/agile-@-scale/</guid>
      <description>Your organization has decided to introduce agile at scale in all development departments or better in the whole company.&#xA;Your Chief of Agility COA, Chief of Digitalization COD or Chief of Change COC was in an expensive training. After a few drinks, he has selected the appropriate framework for your company.&#xA;Welcome to the club of companies introducing agile approaches and having no clues why they do it and how they could be successful.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Time to Migrate to a Modern JDK, Laggards!</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/time-to-migrate-to-a-modern-jdk-laggards/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/time-to-migrate-to-a-modern-jdk-laggards/</guid>
      <description>Are you still using Java 8 to run your mission-critical systems?&#xA;Are you truly using daily a six years old technology stack?&#xA;Are you already applying for a Java laggard club membership?&#xA;If you are still using Java 8, you are using technologies released in Spring 2014. You are missing all the improvements in the garbage collector, runtime engine, and various APIs.&#xA;Java 11 LTS was released in September 2018.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Commons View on Scrum</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/a-commons-view-on-scrum/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/a-commons-view-on-scrum/</guid>
      <description>Agile approaches encourage common ownership of artifacts during product development. Historically, the commons is the term used for shared resources. Can we apply the commons learnings to agile and Scrum approaches?&#xA;Interestingly, economists were kind to state common ownership is doomed to fail through the theory published at the end of the sixties [1].&#xA;Thirty years later, Elinor Ostrom showed that commons can indeed work well if you follow a small set of rules.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Architecture within Scrum</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/agile-architecture-within-scrum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/agile-architecture-within-scrum/</guid>
      <description>You are applying the agile, lean approach to your software product development. Your teams use Scrum or Kanban to deliver running software every two weeks.&#xA;Agile architecture is a key element to improve the quality of your solution and reduce the overall cycle-time of your product delivery.&#xA;Your journey toward greater business agility starts by identifying what outcomes are most important to your company’s success.&#xA;Outcomes are codified in functional and non-functional requirements your product shall fulfill.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The World is a Better Place and We Must Tackle Climate Change</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/the-world-is-a-better-place-and-we-must-tackle-climate-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/the-world-is-a-better-place-and-we-must-tackle-climate-change/</guid>
      <description>The world has really improved in a lot of areas.&#xA;_Stop whining we are doomed.&#xA;And yes, we must act strong and fast to tackle the climate change disaster._&#xA;Remember how much the world bettered the last centuries.&#xA;We are not doomed, we must solve the next challenges instead of just complaining and doing nothing.&#xA;Ask yourself if you need a car.&#xA;Travel by train instead of flying.&#xA;Schedule a video conference instead of a business trip.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Code is Clean Code!</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/agile-code-is-clean-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/agile-code-is-clean-code/</guid>
      <description>You are applying the agile, lean approach to your software product development.&#xA;Congratulations, you are applying state of the industry good practices.&#xA;Your teams use Scrum or Kanban to deliver running software every two weeks.&#xA;To create an agile architecture, you must write agile worthy code. Agile code is always clean code.&#xA;Start early, do it continuously and soon your code will be clean, legible and free of known defects.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Architecture Principles</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/agile-architecture-principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/agile-architecture-principles/</guid>
      <description>You are applying the agile, lean approach to your software product development. Your teams use Scrum or Kanban to deliver running software every two weeks. The product market introduction is a success. You will successfully sell the solution for the next ten years.&#xA;How shall you define the software architecture of your product and ensure a long living and high-quality solution?&#xA;The experts tell you the design is emergent.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I still love to use a MacBookPro and MacOS in 2019</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/why-i-still-love-to-use-a-macbookpro-and-macos-in-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/why-i-still-love-to-use-a-macbookpro-and-macos-in-2019/</guid>
      <description>As a young developer, I loved Linux, compiled new kernels during evening sessions and struggled days to have the correct drivers for the graphic card and communication components of my notebook.&#xA;I grew older and decided to enjoy my weekends, family and outdoor activities.&#xA;And surely I shall have no virus, trojan and other evils in my workstation. So I went to macOS and Apple notebooks without regrets.&#xA;Gains The major gains using macOS are</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Code Scene as Crime Scene</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/code-scene-as-crime-scene/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/code-scene-as-crime-scene/</guid>
      <description>You have a successful product and happy users. Slowly, the cost of adding new features is creeping up and product margins are shrinking. Which crimes did put us in this dreaded situation?&#xA;How can you analyze the history of your product’s source code?&#xA;How can you explore the social dimension of your product development? How can you find good approaches to increase time to market and improve development costs?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You Need an Engineering Culture</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/you-need-an-engineering-culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/you-need-an-engineering-culture/</guid>
      <description>Agile approaches are not enough. You need a strong engineering culture to achieve quality and lasting success.&#xA;Often, coaches and Scrum masters tinker with the processes and invest effort and blood to improve the ceremonies and the company structure.&#xA;But at the end of the day, the success of your application is defined by its adequacy to customer needs and its overall quality. You need a solid and professional engineering culture to produce high-quality products and release them at a high rate.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Healthy is Your Product? - Company Culture Check</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/how-healthy-is-your-product-company-culture-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/how-healthy-is-your-product-company-culture-check/</guid>
      <description>You are developing your application using agile and lean approaches.&#xA;How can you check your approach and distill improvements?&#xA;Health check of your product and your development approach are certainly a good solution.&#xA;This post is the fourth and last of a set of articles identifying health checks with different focus.&#xA;We will identify strengths, potential weaknesses and hopefully find room for improvement.&#xA;What is your company culture?&#xA;How are collaborators focused on delighting your customers?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Detecting Agile Bullshit</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/detecting-agile-bullshit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/detecting-agile-bullshit/</guid>
      <description>The Defense Innovation Board DIB advises the secretary of defense of the United States of America.&#xA;Members of the board are recognizable names like Eric Schmidt who was CEO of Google and Alphabet, or Instagram COO Marne Levine.&#xA;So I was quite surprised that a government committee was so straightforward to publish a document called Detecting Agile Bullshit [1].&#xA;Simple questions are used as a bullshit detector to identify organizations faking agile.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
