<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2018 on tangly Components</title>
    <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2018 on tangly Components</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Healthy is Your Product? - Product Strategy Check</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/how-healthy-is-your-product-product-strategy-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/how-healthy-is-your-product-product-strategy-check/</guid>
      <description>You are developing your product using agile and lean approaches.&#xA;How can you check your approach and distill improvements?&#xA;Health check of your product and your development approach are certainly a good solution.&#xA;This post is the third of a set of articles identifying health checks with different focus. We will identify strengths, potential weaknesses and hopefully find room for improvement.&#xA;What is your product strategy? How do you involve your customers and stakeholders?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SAFE 4.6: Improvements Direly Needed</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/safe-4.6-improvements-direly-needed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/safe-4.6-improvements-direly-needed/</guid>
      <description>It is official.&#xA;The power engine of the SAFe 4.6 vehicle is the team and technical agility. View the SAFe for more information [1].&#xA;It is one of their five Lean Enterprise competencies and one of their four core values. SAFe finally recognizes the tremendous importance of technical proficiency and craftsmanship.&#xA;They advocate two findings. First, you need team agility, how you apply Scrum or Kanban.&#xA;In other words, being agile instead of doing agile.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Healthy is Your Product? - Delivery Pipeline Check</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/how-healthy-is-your-product-delivery-pipeline-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/how-healthy-is-your-product-delivery-pipeline-check/</guid>
      <description>You are developing your product using agile and lean approaches.&#xA;How can you check your approach and distill improvements? A health check of your product and your development approach is certainly a good solution.&#xA;This post is the second of a series identifying health checks with different focus. We will identify strengths, potential weaknesses and hopefully find room for improvement.&#xA;How you build and deliver your software product has direct implications on your liquidity and cash flow.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Should You handle Definition of Done?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/how-should-you-handle-definition-of-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/how-should-you-handle-definition-of-done/</guid>
      <description>An agile team is the sole responsible for the internal quality of the product they build and maintain.&#xA;The developers shall be accountable for producing the expected quality and optimizing long term goals of the organization.&#xA;You as a developer have an ethical, professional and legal responsibility to ensure adequate quality for your products.&#xA;Laws protect the confidentiality of their personal and financial data.&#xA;It is a potential crime to leak credit card information, geolocation data or the worst personal documents.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Healthy is Your Product? - Source Code Check</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/how-healthy-is-your-product-source-code-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/how-healthy-is-your-product-source-code-check/</guid>
      <description>You are developing your product using agile and lean approaches.&#xA;How can you check your approach and distill improvements? Health check of your product and your development approach are certainly a good solution.&#xA;This post is the first of a series identifying health checks with different focus. We will identify strengths, potential weaknesses and hopefully find room for improvement.&#xA;The initial examination shall always be the source code. Your code base is a key asset of your company.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduce Agile in A Company</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/introduce-agile-in-a-company/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/introduce-agile-in-a-company/</guid>
      <description>First teams have successfully used Scrum to develop applications. The news spread out and everybody wants to apply Scrum. It is time to introduce enterprise-wide Agile with Scrum or Kanban or XP.&#xA;Your Company wants to introduce Enterprise Agility in their product development, quality assurance and sales departments. The company as a whole shall transition to an agile organization and all teams shall adopt Scrum.&#xA;Try the Shu Ha Ri approach for such a change process.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What does an Agile Coach?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/what-does-an-agile-coach/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/what-does-an-agile-coach/</guid>
      <description>An agile coach has three main areas of activity:&#xA;Foster Autonomy Teach and support the team and individuals to be autonomous within the given boundaries of the organization and its processes.&#xA;Create Ground for Motivation Help teams to maximize their autonomy, individual mastery and make sure the team has a purpose.&#xA;Provide Coaching Support teams and individuals to identify potential with their roles and within the agile organization and improve.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Architectural Decision Records ADR</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/architectural-decision-records-adr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/architectural-decision-records-adr/</guid>
      <description>Architecture Decision Record ADR is compact and traceable documents of all important decisions taken during the realization of a product. Use Asciidoc or Markdown and Git to have agile and lean documentation of your major decisions.&#xA;The huge advantage of Architecture Design Record ADR is the timeline of the decisions. It tremendously helps to understand the technical changes during the product lifecycle.&#xA;Please try architecture design records to document your key decisions when developing your software product.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Reach the Software Quality Graal?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/how-to-reach-the-software-quality-graal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/how-to-reach-the-software-quality-graal/</guid>
      <description>Lately I was asked how many bugs and smells detected through SonarQube were acceptable for a software product. And a Scrum master inquired which organizational changes are necessary to empower software developers to write good code. Speechless and dumbfounded, I was unable to answer these questions.&#xA;After some time, I realized these people believe tools can measure the quality of software. But tools can only measure non-quality.&#xA;They tell you when you are doing it wrong, only your heart can tell you when you are doing it right.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Trends Switzerland 2018</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/agile-trends-switzerland-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/agile-trends-switzerland-2018/</guid>
      <description>What are the main hurdles to introducing agile approaches in Swiss companies? The Swiss agile trends report was published for the last ten years and learn us the difficulties and successes of agile transformations.&#xA;SwissQ has published a &amp;#34;SwissQ Software Development Switzerland 2018&amp;#34;, the tenth version of this report.&#xA;Introducing agile company-wide was and is a cultural change process. Such a change takes time and sometimes hurts. Too often, organizations stop the process and revert to all command and control approaches with Waterfall product management.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sonar Lint for the Impatient</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/sonar-lint-for-the-impatient/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/sonar-lint-for-the-impatient/</guid>
      <description>Remove issues before they reach customer sites. No quality problems shall reach your Git master branch.&#xA;SonarQube is a central server that processes full analyses (triggered by the various SonarQube Scanners).&#xA;Its purpose is to give a 360° vision about the quality of your code base. For this, it analyzes all the source lines of your product on a regular basis.&#xA;It should be added that SonarQube also performs scans with well-known third party analyzers (SpotBugs - previously FindBugs -, Checkstyle, PMD) whereas SonarLint does not include those.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Introduction Success Criteria through the LeSS Lens</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/agile-introduction-success-criteria-through-the-less-lens/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/agile-introduction-success-criteria-through-the-less-lens/</guid>
      <description>An agile organization is able to deliver or change her direction at any time without additional cost.&#xA;More companies want to become truly agile and book an expensive journey to the holy land of agility. Often travelers never reach their true destination.&#xA;The LeSS people have a clear set of conditions to increase the odds.&#xA;All my experiences confirm these conditions are essential for success.&#xA;LeSS Criteria Use these criteria as a checklist to evaluate your current agile transformation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pragmatic Craftsmanship - Professional Software Developer</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/pragmatic-craftsmanship-professional-software-developer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/pragmatic-craftsmanship-professional-software-developer/</guid>
      <description>The last months I was often confronted with software products having insufficient quality.&#xA;Insufficient means late delivery, and few new features. The effort to correct errors in the field eats 30% to 50% away from the development budget. How can such a dreadful situation occur?&#xA;One root cause is the low quality of the source code and ignorance of basic coding design approaches.&#xA;We are not talking about complex design activities or complex patterns; we are discussing basic approaches how to write correct and maintainable code.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Do You Need Metrics and KPI in Agile Product Development?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/why-do-you-need-metrics-and-kpi-in-agile-product-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/why-do-you-need-metrics-and-kpi-in-agile-product-development/</guid>
      <description>Why do we define metrics and KPI?&#xA;First, we want to find out how good the build-in quality of our software artifacts is.&#xA;Second, we want to improve the build-in quality through experiments and use the metrics to judge the success of these experiments.&#xA;And the Key Performance Indicators KPI provide plausibility checks by qualifying the intrinsic quality of software artifacts against quantifiable strategic objectives.&#xA;Measurements shall be cheap to gather and as much as possible generated automatically through the tooling landscape.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile GIS Open Data Initiative</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/agile-gis-open-data-initiative/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/agile-gis-open-data-initiative/</guid>
      <description>How can agile approaches be applied to deliver solutions in a government environment?&#xA;Here is an example of a GIS open data portal successfully developed using agile approaches such as Kanban, lean product and technical excellence.&#xA;GIS Open Data Initiative The Swiss government has initiated an open government data strategy to provide data at federal and state level to all citizens and interested parties. The aims are&#xA;Release of official data The Confederation will make data which are suitable for OGD available to the public in machine-readable and open formats to be freely reused.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java 10 aka 18.3 Changes</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/java-10-aka-18.3-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/java-10-aka-18.3-changes/</guid>
      <description>Oracle has decided to release a new JDK two times a year.&#xA;The next release of Java 10 aka 18.3 will be available in March 2018.&#xA;JDK 11 aka 18.9 will be released in September 2018. Java 11 will also be a long-term support LTS release.&#xA;For Java to remain competitive, it must not just continue to move forward — it must move forward faster.&#xA;— Mark Reinhold The Visible Change The visible change is the dawn of the keyword var.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Six Levers for better Agile Product Development</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/six-levers-for-better-agile-product-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/six-levers-for-better-agile-product-development/</guid>
      <description>Every company is a software company.&#xA;Software is a key to success. This is the new reality in the digital world.&#xA;How can you create better digital products and services?&#xA;How can you delight your customers, your collaborators, and your stakeholders?&#xA;How can you increase the odds of success for your digital products?&#xA;We identified six levers to multiply the effectivity of your agile development teams and empower them to create great services and products.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scrum Guide 2017: What changed?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/scrum-guide-2017-what-changed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/scrum-guide-2017-what-changed/</guid>
      <description>The Scrum guide was revised in 2016 and got clarification concerning the core values. I was thrilled. Talking about values and mental models, you must have to successfully introduce and be agile is awesome.&#xA;A new revision was published at the end of year 2017, just a year after the addition of values.&#xA;What has changed?&#xA;What has the community learnt and committed to the new version of the guide?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One Way to Improve Your Scrum Approach</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/one-way-to-improve-your-scrum-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/one-way-to-improve-your-scrum-approach/</guid>
      <description>You work using agile and lean approaches. Your collaborators are trained how to use agile principles.&#xA;Techniques such as test-driven development, continuous integration, DevOps or clean code are regularly practiced.&#xA;Your teams reduce their technical debt and deliver regularly stable product increments.&#xA;Now you are looking for the next improvement. How can your team improve your product and increase customer value?&#xA;It is time for a fresh view.&#xA;Perform an agile assessment with an external expert from another company or department.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why is it so Cool to Develop with Java?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/why-is-it-so-cool-to-develop-with-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2018/why-is-it-so-cool-to-develop-with-java/</guid>
      <description>Why is it so cool to develop software using Java, a modern IDE and agile tools?&#xA;Because the environment empowers you and incredibly speeds up your development outcomes. In seconds, you know if the next code increment adds value to your product.&#xA;Test driven development and static quality tools are integrated in your IDE. Each time you check some code into your Git repository, all configured checks shall be executed before allowing the commit.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
