<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2021 on tangly Components</title>
    <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2021 on tangly Components</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Spotify Cultural Elements</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/spotify-cultural-elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/spotify-cultural-elements/</guid>
      <description>Recently, a client told me that they were adopting the Spotify Model. This statement sounded great for him.&#xA;Spotify has published some great articles and videos about how they have grown and transformed their organization to be agile. Then it occurred to me that what my customer was saying was completely wrong.&#xA;I don’t think you can really understand what it is like to work at Spotify without actually living it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gradle 7</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/gradle-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/gradle-7/</guid>
      <description>Gradle Build Tool is my preferred build tool for all Java applications I am developing.&#xA;Google chose Gradle as the official build tool for Android.&#xA;Not only because build scripts are code, but because Gradle is modeled in a way that is extensible in the most fundamental ways.&#xA;Gradle’s model also allows it to be used for native development with C/C++ and can be expanded to cover any ecosystem.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Choice is Good</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/choice-is-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/choice-is-good/</guid>
      <description>First and foremost, our primary goal is to develop successful products and delight users. We are always looking for good practices to improve our odds.&#xA;Product development is a risky business.&#xA;We want to expand our toolbox with proven approaches. We use these tools to experiment when confronted with new problems. There is No Silver Bullet to solve our specific challenges.&#xA;Using a goal-driven approach that guides people through process-related options is one powerful approach.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JDk 17</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/jdk-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/jdk-17/</guid>
      <description>I truly love the new release rhythm of the Java ecosystem. Every six months a new JDK is delivered. Being able to use new features every six months is awesome.&#xA;The new release JDK 17 [3] is the next long term support LTS release. The migration overhead is held to a minimum thanks to the incredible backward compatibility. The early-access builds give you more than enough opportunities and time to migrate all your applications on time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Design Modeling</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/agile-design-modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/agile-design-modeling/</guid>
      <description>Unknown reference: implementing-domain-driven-desing The line between software development and software architecture is a tricky one.&#xA;Some people will tell you that it does not exist and that architecture is simply an extension of the design process undertaken by developers. Others will make out it is a massive gaping chasm that can only be crossed by lofty developers. They believe you must always abstract your abstractions and not get bogged down by those pesky implementation details.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scrum Developer Formation</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/scrum-developer-formation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/scrum-developer-formation/</guid>
      <description>You are working as a developer in a Scrum team.&#xA;Congratulations, working as a professional Scrum developer is a fulfilling and exciting job.&#xA;You should attend professional training.&#xA;Formal training is often the difference between being a professional instead of just pretending to be one.&#xA;Scrum Developer Role Here the official definition of the developer team member role taken from the Scrum.&#xA;Developers are the people in the Scrum Team that are committed to creating any aspect of a usable Increment each Sprint.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I Learnt Teaching Agile Software Architecture</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/what-i-learnt-teaching-agile-software-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/what-i-learnt-teaching-agile-software-architecture/</guid>
      <description>I am teaching agile software architecture and techniques SWAT as advanced bachelor level lecture weighted with 3 ECTS.&#xA;I gave this training the last three years at Lucerne University of Applied Sciences and Arts HSLU in Switzerland.&#xA;All materials are released under the Creative Commons copyright.&#xA;The course contents are aligned with the big software architecture programs.&#xA;The Open Group organization is the steward of TOGAF standard. TOGAF is the worldwide industrial standard for enterprise software architecture.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving a Static Web Site Build With Hugo and Docsy</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/improving-a-static-web-site-build-with-hugo-and-docsy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/improving-a-static-web-site-build-with-hugo-and-docsy/</guid>
      <description>The static website build tool Hugo is awesome. With the extensive built-in feature set of Hugo and the feature-rich text formatting options that Asciidoc offers, it creates a blogging experience composed of easy content management and fun writing experience.&#xA;In most static site generators including Hugo, Markdown is the one and only first-class citizen when it comes to creating posts.&#xA;However, in recent Hugo versions, external helpers are an official feature.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scrum Master Formation</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/scrum-master-formation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/scrum-master-formation/</guid>
      <description>You work as a Scrum master.&#xA;Congratulations, working as a professional Scrum master is a fulfilling and exciting job.&#xA;You should attend professional training.&#xA;Not only attend the two-day training to receive a shiny diploma.&#xA;Being a Scrum master and coach is a profession, not a fancy title!&#xA;Please reflect on your goals and ethics.&#xA;Scrum Master Role Here the official definition of the product owner role taken from the Scrum.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DevOps for Small Applications</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/devops-for-small-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/devops-for-small-applications/</guid>
      <description>DevOps is the combination of cultural philosophies, practices and tools that increase an organization’s ability to deliver at high velocity.&#xA;It evolves and improves products at a faster pace than organizations using traditional software development and infrastructure management processes.&#xA;This speed enables organizations to better serve their customers [1, 2].&#xA;A surprising side effect of this speed-up is a documented improvement of the delivered quality.&#xA;How It Works Under a DevOps model, development and operations teams are no longer siloed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Leadership</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/agile-leadership/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/agile-leadership/</guid>
      <description>Everybody is talking about being agile.&#xA;Companies institutionalize agile change programs and send all their collaborators in training to learn the agile way.&#xA;What does that mean?&#xA;How should I as a manager work the agile way?&#xA;Does this agile way exist, or is it simply a fad created by the consulting industry?&#xA;This article provides some pointers and hypotheses what agile leadership could be.&#xA;Feel free to experiment and refine your successful approach to be agile as an organization.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Technical Team Lead</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/technical-team-lead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/technical-team-lead/</guid>
      <description>I lately had to explain to customers what are the responsibilities of a technical team lead. Managers often grasp the people aspects embedded in the words team lead. The understanding of the word technical is strangely often missing.&#xA;A technical team leads coaches and teaches the subtleties of the used technology stack to his team and organization. This person should be able to create or review a software architecture. He has a deep understanding of technological concepts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Enterprise Architecture?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/why-enterprise-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/why-enterprise-architecture/</guid>
      <description>Architecture principles hold true in agile environments. The major difference between older traditional approaches and modern agile ones is the way of performing enterprise architecture.&#xA;The last years have shown a promising evolution of plan-based, centralist enterprise architecture approaches to more agile, decentralized, meritocracy driven processes.&#xA;These new approaches are way more compatible with modern and agile software product development framework such as Scrum, eXtreme Programming, and LeSS&#xA;Traditional processes use dedicated persons or departments to define architecture principles in a top-down approach.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Product Owner Formation</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/product-owner-formation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/product-owner-formation/</guid>
      <description>You are acting as a product owner in your organization.&#xA;Congratulations, working as a professional product owner is a fulfilling and exciting job.&#xA;You should attend professional training.&#xA;Being a product owner and requirements engineer is a profession, not a hobby!&#xA;Formal training is often the difference between being a professional instead of just pretending to be one.&#xA;Product Owner Role Here the official definition of the product owner role taken from the Scrum.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Temporal Aspects of Rolling ERP Planning</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/temporal-aspects-of-rolling-erp-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/temporal-aspects-of-rolling-erp-planning/</guid>
      <description>Agile approaches advocate dynamic planning and adaptation to new inputs and priority changes. The Beyond Budgeting Round Table movement promotes rolling planning, budgeting and reporting.&#xA;The beyond budgeting techniques recommend the complete abolition of traditional budgeting processes. They require the implementation of new techniques that will replace them. The BB framework does not specify the exact techniques that are applicable to all companies.&#xA;However, there are some techniques that have proven to be effective in real cases in the past.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Trends Switzerland 2021</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/agile-trends-switzerland-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/agile-trends-switzerland-2021/</guid>
      <description>As a modern leader, you are aware of the importance of transforming your organization to become more agile. Indeed, you have successfully implemented first steps.&#xA;Trouble is brewing. Things are not moving forward as quickly as they should, especially in the current challenging situation. The leadership behaviour of your colleagues is only changing slowly. Your key developers are grumbling you are faking it.&#xA;Many companies around the world discover their agile transformation is stalling.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on Agile Fluency Model</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/reflections-on-agile-fluency-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/reflections-on-agile-fluency-model/</guid>
      <description>Agile fluency model is a powerful abstraction to better understand your agile transition. It does not matter which flavor of agile you are deploying in your organization; the agile fluency model can be applied in all cases.&#xA;The agile fluency model has a powerful message about agile and technical excellence. The second zone of the model is all about software craftsmanship and eXtreme Programming.&#xA;One key lesson of the fluency model is it takes time until you are professional at your chosen level.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Certified Java Developer</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/certified-java-developer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/certified-java-developer/</guid>
      <description>Java is celebrating 25 years of existence.&#xA;I discovered the anniversary offer to certify for Java SE 11 Developer.&#xA;This special certification has a cool logo with the remainder of the Java 25-year anniversary.&#xA;Oracle offers this certification for only 25 dollars [1] and provides free access to their learning platform.&#xA;The offer and logo availability are time limited.&#xA;The free learning subscription includes:&#xA;The Java Explorer learning path for basic Java skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Trends Switzerland 2020</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/agile-trends-switzerland-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/agile-trends-switzerland-2020/</guid>
      <description>As a modern leader, you are aware of the importance of transforming your organization to become more agile. Indeed, you have successfully implemented first steps.&#xA;Trouble is brewing. Things are not moving forward as quickly as they should, especially in the current challenging situation. The leadership behaviour of your colleagues is only changing slowly. Your key developers are grumbling you are faking it.&#xA;Many companies around the world discover their agile transformation is stalling.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Requirements Engineering</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/agile-requirements-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/agile-requirements-engineering/</guid>
      <description>Lately, I was asked which new approaches should be used for agile requirements engineering. Did we find a new silver bullet to write software specifications the agile way?&#xA;The answer is easy. We do not need new approaches or complicated processes. Start with proven principles and learn.&#xA;Impact Mapping and Story Mapping are successful approaches to identify and prioritize your functions. Specification by Example and User Stories as a discussion allow you to refine your understanding of what your customers need.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Service for Developer Game Changer</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/self-service-for-developer-game-changer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/self-service-for-developer-game-changer/</guid>
      <description>Often, I hear complain that the IT department is not reacting to developer’s needs. They are slow, clumsy and too administrative. Harsher words state they are incompetent.&#xA;I have observed a clear trend in Switzerland since around 2015 to solve these tensions.&#xA;Standard IT services such as docker images, database instances or internal domain names are provided through self-service kiosks.&#xA;What are the advantages of this approach?&#xA;Advantages The advantages to providing a self-service kiosk for users in an academical or industrial environment are:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JDk 16</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/jdk-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/jdk-16/</guid>
      <description>I truly love the new release rhythm of the Java ecosystem. It is awesome to be able to use new features every six months.&#xA;The migration overhead is held to a minimum thanks to incredible backward compatibility.&#xA;The new features greatly simplify the existing code and tremendously increase legibility.&#xA;Features like records, sealed types, or switch expressions are wonderful. The promise of advanced pattern matching constructs is sweet.&#xA;Polishing of functional programming approach improved my source code quite stupendously.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Software Architecture is Mainstream</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/agile-software-architecture-is-mainstream/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/agile-software-architecture-is-mainstream/</guid>
      <description>Slowly, slowly major actors in the software architecture landscape acknowledge agile development is state of the industry approach to building software products.&#xA;They are still struggling to integrate their older views in a faster, iterative, incremental development approach. The duration of a regular Scrum sprint is usually two weeks.&#xA;More important, they have discovered we build products because no customers buy projects. They buy solutions and products.&#xA;I am relieved I need less fight to convince enterprise architects that agile is the way.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MicroStream 4.x</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/microstream-4.x/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/microstream-4.x/</guid>
      <description>MicroStream approach empowers Java developers. The library provides a cool and compact approach to persist complex data models. You can persist your whole data model with less than a hundred lines of code. The library is efficient and works reliably.&#xA;Modern architectures based on bounded domains and Domain Driven Design are supported.&#xA;The company behind the product has promised to open source their product beginning of 2021.&#xA;I use the library to prototype bounded domain implementations requiring persistent data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modern Java Development</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/modern-java-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/modern-java-development/</guid>
      <description>Java development activities have won traction since the decision to release a new version to the community every six months. Preview and incubator features promote feedback from the community and users.&#xA;Some tool builders, such as JetBrains are working proactively and provide support for JDK in developments.&#xA;Other tool maintainers such as JaCoCo are dreadfully behind the release cycle.&#xA;We learnt to deal with the new speed and how to tackle the laggards.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective Working in Digital Age</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/effective-working-in-digital-age/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/effective-working-in-digital-age/</guid>
      <description>Home office is the new way of working. A lot of friends and business partners are working from home. Our meetings are mostly online. We share documents and results through digital platforms.&#xA;I truly hope we continue to work online in the future. I would like to mix home office, local coworking space, and regular office attendance. I am convinced less commute time and a greener approach to work are certainly great improvements.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Is Java Path Class Better?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/why-is-java-path-class-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/why-is-java-path-class-better/</guid>
      <description>Java NIO New Input Output is an alternative IO API for Java, meaning alternative to the standard Java IO and Java Networking APIs.&#xA;Java NIO offers a different IO programming model than the traditional IO APIs.&#xA;One major feature of interest is the support of alternate file systems. An in-memory file system is ideal for test file related operations in unit and integration tests.&#xA;Sometimes NIO is claimed to mean Non-blocking IO.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LeSS Lessons Learnt</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/less-lessons-learnt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/less-lessons-learnt/</guid>
      <description>Scaling Agile, Lean and Scrum to the whole product development department is hard work.&#xA;You start a change journey in murky waters. Best to communicate a lot, strengthen your teams and have total support of upper management.&#xA;Technical agile coaching usefully describes the work I do. Agile coaching helps your business to become more successful, often improve the way you plan and deliver software.&#xA;Technical agile coaching focuses on how people design products, write code and deliver high-quality products.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Software Development for Students</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/software-development-for-students/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/software-development-for-students/</guid>
      <description>Computer science students shall achieve technical excellence when reaching bachelor level. They should be proficient with industry good practices.&#xA;Students understand the theory and principles behind these practices. Experience with one of the best of breed tools enforces learning and automatism.&#xA;The focus of a technical university is to teach the concepts and methods. The tools are used to practice and to increase student learning.&#xA;Source Code Version Management with Git Git is the standard tool for the distributed source code management system.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gitlab for Bachelor Students</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/gitlab-for-bachelor-students/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/gitlab-for-bachelor-students/</guid>
      <description>Computer science students shall be proficient with a basic set of software development techniques.&#xA;Technical excellence is a mandatory skill for all software developers.&#xA;Agile development approaches are state of the industry and used in almost all software development initiatives.&#xA;DevOps approaches are used in modern organizations. They predate agile development approaches.&#xA;Technical schools should provide an in-depth experience in these areas to prepare their students for their future activities after completing their bachelor.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meaningful Identifiers</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/meaningful-identifiers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/meaningful-identifiers/</guid>
      <description>Identifiers are a key concept to successfully model complex business domains. They permeate how our modern civilization functions.&#xA;Could you imagine a country without a car registration number of vehicles, internet addresses, postal addresses or social security numbers?&#xA;Identifiers are identifiers.&#xA;Identifiers cannot be changed at any time.&#xA;Updating identifiers means introducing mapping relations between the old and the new values.&#xA;In computer science, identifiers IDs are lexical tokens that name entities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Value Objects as Embedded Entities</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/value-objects-as-embedded-entities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/value-objects-as-embedded-entities/</guid>
      <description>This post discusses the value object pattern, and the factory pattern, which are tactical patterns in the domain-driven design Domain-Driven Design approach.&#xA;Value objects represent typed values that have no conceptual identity in your domain. They can help you write better codes that are less error-prone, more performant and more expressive.&#xA;Value objects define the second kind of domain objects besides entities. Their main characteristic is immutability:&#xA;Attributes of a value object never change.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
