<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2022 on tangly Components</title>
    <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2022 on tangly Components</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>First Steps DevOps</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/first-steps-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/first-steps-devops/</guid>
      <description>The DevOps movement started to gather momentum with the first DevOps conference held in Ghent, Belgium in 2009 [1].&#xA;The approach aims to shorten the system development life-cycle and to provide continuous delivery with high software quality. DevOps is complementary with agile software development approaches.&#xA;Several DevOps aspects came from the Agile method.&#xA;Seminal books [1, 2, 3, 4] and good practices were published around the same time.&#xA;The DevOps approach belongs to the regular instruments of professional software developers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Module Test Reporting with Gradle 7.x</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/multi-module-test-reporting-with-gradle-7.x/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/multi-module-test-reporting-with-gradle-7.x/</guid>
      <description>I love Gradle as the building tool for all my Java projects.&#xA;But sometimes I was discouraged about how spotty or cumbersome the support for multi-module project is.&#xA;I struggled for years to generate test and code overage reports over modules included in a Gradle Build Tool project.&#xA;Gradle finally provides a better approach to generate aggregated test and code coverage reports over multiple modules belonging to the same project.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Behavior Driven Design</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/behavior-driven-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/behavior-driven-design/</guid>
      <description>Domain-Driven Design DDD has been around since Eric Evans published his book about the subject in 2003 [1].&#xA;Vernon Vaugh published powerful approaches how to implement DDD concepts into a software solution [2, 3].&#xA;How do you validate and test your DDD digital solutions?&#xA;Behavior Driven Development BDD is an inversion how systems are often developed. In some ways, it is an extension of Test Driven Development TDD approach to the whole application.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modern Java Constructs</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/modern-java-constructs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/modern-java-constructs/</guid>
      <description>Modern Java is quite a departure from the traditional Java available at the beginning of the millennium.&#xA;The most visible change is certainly lambda expressions and stream, enabling a more functional programming approach in Java.&#xA;Functional programming is a paradigm that supports developers to think in terms of functions instead of classes. Functions are stateless and without side effects. Avoiding state can lead to better software, especially in high-performance, concurrent applications [1].</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vaadin</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/vaadin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/vaadin/</guid>
      <description>Vaadin is an ideal solution if you are a Java developer and wants to provide a user interface for your product. Vaadin is a framework to create graphical user interfaces using plain Java, or any JVM-based language for that matter.&#xA;You develop in Java, and the framework takes care of all the rest. It generates the client-side code, and the communication between the client-side code in the browser and the backend code on the server.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eliminate Your Printer</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/eliminate-your-printer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/eliminate-your-printer/</guid>
      <description>In an increasingly technology-focused world, the demand for businesses to digitize has grown dramatically.&#xA;So, what does it mean to digitize your business?&#xA;Essentially, it means incorporating technology into your business operations to increase efficiency, enhance customer experience, and boost sales.&#xA;This could mean developing a mobile application for your startup, transitioning into ecommerce, offering mobile payment options, and more.&#xA;The goal of digitizing your business is to keep up with the rapidly changing economy by offering your customers more ways to access your business, and streamline daily operations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ArchUnit</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/archunit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/archunit/</guid>
      <description>How often have you experienced a well-defined and understood software architecture on paper? And it falls apart when developers start implementing it?&#xA;While re-architecting recently legacy components in an application, I experienced the same.&#xA;As more and more developers joined the team, it became a constant routine to make them aware of the design and how to adhere to it.&#xA;I know some of you may say, Why not control the implementation during code-review sessions?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transfer a Software Project</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/transfer-a-software-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/transfer-a-software-project/</guid>
      <description>You developed a new digital product for an internal or external customer. Your solution is awesome.&#xA;The product is released to delighted users. Your users love your solution.&#xA;The project is now winding down and closing activities are initiated. The customer organization shall take ownership of all product related artifacts. The handover is a vital part of closing a project [1].&#xA;Your customer paid for the development and own the produced artifacts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Detect Fake Scrum?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/how-to-detect-fake-scrum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/how-to-detect-fake-scrum/</guid>
      <description>Some organisations are adopting agile and Scrum approaches simply because they see competitors doing it. In these situations, there is rarely a desire to adopt a new mindset and culture, or motivation for true change.&#xA;A common pattern is the adoption of a new nomenclature. Project Managers are renamed as Scrum Masters. Business Analysts become Product Owners.&#xA;Very little actually changes. Few benefits of agility are realised.&#xA;If anything, the situation may become worse as some previous structures are lost, yet the discipline for Agile is just not there.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Would You Enjoy Being a Scrum Master?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/would-you-enjoy-being-a-scrum-master/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/would-you-enjoy-being-a-scrum-master/</guid>
      <description>Scrum is the most popular approach to create awesome new digital products.&#xA;Perhaps you are thinking of pursuing a career as a Scrum master. You read the Agile Manifesto and memorized the 12 Agile Manifesto Principles.&#xA;Perhaps you have recently been moved into that role and are wondering if being a Scrum master is right for you.&#xA;There are plenty of good reasons to become a Scrum master. The job is fascinating, in demand and pays well.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modular Monoliths are the new Graal</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/modular-monoliths-are-the-new-graal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/modular-monoliths-are-the-new-graal/</guid>
      <description>A modular monolith is a software design approach in which a monolith is designed with an emphasis on interchangeable and potentially reusable modules.&#xA;A modular monolith can be split in the future into a set of microservices.&#xA;Delay the split as long as you can. Microservices have a steep price tag during operations.&#xA;A modular monolith provides:&#xA;Independent and parallel development approach.&#xA;Diminish coupling and improve cohesion. The interfaces are better documented and thinner.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Software Structure with DDD</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/software-structure-with-ddd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/software-structure-with-ddd/</guid>
      <description>Domain Driven Development DDD is the preferred software architecture approach for designing digital products. The method nicely matches with the operational concepts of microservices.&#xA;Domain-driven design is a holistic approach to understanding, designing and building software applications.&#xA;Seminal books [1, 2, 3] describes the approach and key concepts defining the development method.&#xA;Concrete recipes and examples of code structure are still sparse.&#xA;How should you structure your namespaces and modules?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Measurements and Units</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/measurements-and-units/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/measurements-and-units/</guid>
      <description>JSR-385 could have saved Mars Climate Orbiter[2] in year 1999.&#xA;Accidents in computer applications happen again and again due to calculation errors.&#xA;The International System of Units SI, commonly known as the metric system, is the international standard for measurement.&#xA;The International Treaty of the Mete was signed in Paris on May 20, 1875, by seventeen countries, including the United States.&#xA;In May 2019, the system of units was updated.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing DevOps Ideas</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/introducing-devops-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/introducing-devops-ideas/</guid>
      <description>Your organization heard of DevOps, and your developers clamor you should adopt the approach.&#xA;Each organization I talk with has some DevOps initiative. Often because they read that DevOps approach puts customers and end-user satisfaction at the center.&#xA;Does DevOps really improve the quality of your digital products and customer satisfaction?&#xA;Or is it only the next silver bullet fad used to increase the bonus of consultants and managers?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digital Product Manager</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/digital-product-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/digital-product-manager/</guid>
      <description>Effective product management is driven by a customer-centric mindset. The customer is placed at the center of every decision.&#xA;Supported by tools and techniques such as design thinking, this mindset focuses the entire organization on creating desirable, viable, feasible, and sustainable solutions.&#xA;Good product managers balance customer needs, adequate technologies, product delivery, and governance or legal constraints.&#xA;They shall master project management approaches, financing mechanisms and collaborator nurturing.&#xA;Responsibilities The primary responsibilities of product management often fall into the following areas.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yet Another Hybrid Method</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/yet-another-hybrid-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/yet-another-hybrid-method/</guid>
      <description>SoDa Software Development Agile is a homebrew project development method created at the technical university of Lucerne. It is a mixture of Waterfall, RUP and Scrum approaches. It uses a distorted Scrum for the concept and implementation phase[2].&#xA;The documentation was not updated the last ten years. The approach is clinically dead and should not be promoted for active software development efforts.&#xA;A similar approach exists with the official governmental Swiss project method HERMES.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java, Groovy, Clojure</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/java-groovy-clojure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/java-groovy-clojure/</guid>
      <description>Professional software developers shall master their primary technology stack and programming language.&#xA;I am a proficient and experienced programmer in Java.&#xA;I have written production code in Java for the last twenty years.&#xA;I decided to study the language in depth and acquired various Java developer certifications.&#xA;I truly love the modern Java language and the available development environments.&#xA;I want to understand the strengths and weaknesses of Java.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modernize Your Java Landscape</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/modernize-your-java-landscape/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/modernize-your-java-landscape/</guid>
      <description>The dreaded attack through the log4j logging library was a wake-up call for all companies using obsolete libraries. Many organizations found out the hard way they cannot update the library and deploy the new version in a matter of minutes as professional developers should do. They needed weeks to perform such a simple activity.&#xA;They also found out that they had no process for such regular situations when a critical flaw is detected in some software they are using.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modern Java with Spring</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/modern-java-with-spring/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/modern-java-with-spring/</guid>
      <description>Spring and Spring Boot frameworks are the standard for enterprise Java applications.&#xA;Spring Boot makes it easy to create stand-alone, production-grade Spring-based Applications that you can just run.&#xA;They take an opinionated view of the Spring platform and third-party libraries, so you can get started with minimum fuss.&#xA;Most Spring Boot applications need minimal Spring configuration.&#xA;Minimize Boilerplate Code One of the key reasons for the success of Spring is the approach of convention over configuration.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doing Agile</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/doing-agile/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/doing-agile/</guid>
      <description>In the midst of the agile adoption explosion, many teams are experiencing difficulties.&#xA;Organizations often mix agile with Scrum.&#xA;One of the most common misconceptions about Scrum is that it is synonymous with agile. Agile Manifesto is an umbrella term that refers to a family of approaches that share common values and principles.&#xA;Scrum is a commonly used agile framework that offers suggestions for how work can be organized to maximize the value of the end-user.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile and Nearshore Development</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/agile-and-nearshore-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/agile-and-nearshore-development/</guid>
      <description>The majority of software product development initiatives use an agile approach. The most popular framework is currently Scrum.&#xA;It is natural that organizations would gravitate towards the many benefits agile ideas provide.&#xA;Scarce resources and time-to-market constraints have driven the implementation of shoring development initiatives. Awareness that talent can be found at any location speeds up the trend.&#xA;The outsourcing market is undergoing constant evolution. Traditionally, cost reduction was the key driver for software development outsourcing, but now it doesn’t even make the top five, according to Deloitte’s 2018 Global Outsourcing Survey.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Quest for an Agile Company: Six Years tangly llc</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/the-quest-for-an-agile-company-six-years-tangly-llc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/the-quest-for-an-agile-company-six-years-tangly-llc/</guid>
      <description>Historically, big beats small. Scale was a sufficient advantage to be successful in the market.&#xA;Now, fast and adaptive beats slow and steadfast.&#xA;New technologies, evolving customer preferences and changing employee expectations are fundamentally challenging established ways of working [1].&#xA;It is time to move beyond rigid hierarchies, siloed business units, crippling bureaucracy and an increasingly unwieldy matrix.&#xA;Agile organizations combine the efficiencies of scale with the speed, flexibility and resilience to compete and win in today’s world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluate Technical CVs</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/evaluate-technical-cvs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/evaluate-technical-cvs/</guid>
      <description>The goal of a curriculum vitae is to get an invitation to a job interview. I review hundreds of CVs and must select a few candidates we should invite.&#xA;Each interview will cost hundreds of Euros to the company. I must minimize the number of interviews and increase the probability of a match.&#xA;Over the years, I developed a checklist to select promising candidates.&#xA;The below checklist is biased to the Java technology check.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Immutability in Java</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/immutability-in-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/immutability-in-java/</guid>
      <description>Immutability is a powerful and simple concept in programming theory that is strangely underused.&#xA;An immutable object is simply a class whose instances cannot be modified. This is in contrast to a mutable object or changeable object, which can be modified after it is created.&#xA;Immutable objects are also useful because they are inherently thread-safe. Other benefits are that they are simpler to understand and reason about and offer higher security than mutable objects</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Technical Debt</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/technical-debt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/technical-debt/</guid>
      <description>The technical debt or code debt is a concept in software development that reflects the implied cost of additional rework. The rework is caused by choosing an easy limited solution now instead of using a better approach that would take longer to realize.&#xA;Another source of technical debt is natural technical obsolescence.&#xA;As with monetary debt, if technical debt is not repaid, it accumulates interest, making it harder and harder to implement changes.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
