<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Series-Students on tangly Components</title>
    <link>https://blog.tangly.net/tags/series-students/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Series-Students on tangly Components</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.tangly.net/tags/series-students/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Commits for the Impatient</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/semantic-commits-for-the-impatient/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/semantic-commits-for-the-impatient/</guid>
      <description>The conventional commits specification is a lightweight convention on top of commit messages. The additional information classifies the type of work performed in the commit.&#xA;A developer infers the importance of the task by looking to the type of the commit. The message communicates the nature of changes to teammates, the public, and other stakeholders.&#xA;Contributors of project repositories know that a well-designed Git commit message is the best way to communicate the context about a change to other developers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gradle Good Practices</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/gradle-good-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/gradle-good-practices/</guid>
      <description>Gradle Build Tool is a fast, dependable, and adaptable open-source build automation tool with an elegant and extensible declarative build language. Java is the primary supported programming language.&#xA;Gradle Build Tool is a popular build system for the JVM and is the default system for Android and Kotlin Multi-Platform projects.&#xA;It has a rich community plugin ecosystem. Groovy, Kotlin, C++, and Swift stacks are well-supported.&#xA;Gradle is fast, scalable, and can build projects of any size and complexity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>C4 and UML with PlantUML</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/c4-and-uml-with-plantuml/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/c4-and-uml-with-plantuml/</guid>
      <description>You are creating an awesome digital product. The software part shall work flawlessly over the years.&#xA;Technology changes will be added to the product. Legal changes and security improvements are implemented in a timely manner over the years.&#xA;This application will evolve to satisfy new needs and customer segments. The life span of your product is probably more than a decade.&#xA;How can you document critical cross-cutting design decisions and key mechanisms?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java Certification</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/java-certification/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/java-certification/</guid>
      <description>Java expertise is in high demand for all kinds of projects, ranging from big enterprise software implementations down to little web projects. A huge number of enterprise applications are developed in Java.&#xA;But will those employers want you to have related certifications?&#xA;Even if you are not looking to move any time soon, getting certified boosts the value that you can bring to your organization.&#xA;Certifications can be a great bargaining chip when it comes to negotiating a raise or a promotion.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Visual Tools</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/agile-visual-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/agile-visual-tools/</guid>
      <description>Why is visibility so important for any agile or Scrum team?&#xA;When you are running an agile product development initiative, your ultimate goal is customer satisfaction with the delivered solution.&#xA;The project coordination responsibilities are, however, not limited to this single goal.&#xA;The product owner shall nurture the vision, roadmap, the release plan and customer journey. You must coordinate the workflow of your team, refine the product backlog, control identified risks, and track deadlines.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Git Tag for the Impatient</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/git-tag-for-the-impatient/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/git-tag-for-the-impatient/</guid>
      <description>The development software team has reached a milestone.&#xA;A working application with a set of features is available. All tests are green.&#xA;The application can potentially be shipped to internal or external customers.&#xA;How can you mark this event in the git repository of the application?&#xA;Use tags to recognize this state in the list of changes of your shared Git repository.&#xA;Listing Your Tags Listing the existing tags in Git is straightforward.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Git Rebase and Merge for the Impatient</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/git-rebase-and-merge-for-the-impatient/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/git-rebase-and-merge-for-the-impatient/</guid>
      <description>Both the rebase and merge commands provide similar functionalities.&#xA;They combine the work of multiple developers into a single entity, integrating changes between branches.&#xA;That about sums up their similarities.&#xA;The operation git merge is a way of combining changes from one source branch into another target branch. The operation leaves commit messages in the history.&#xA;The operation git rebase is a way of moving the changes from one branch onto another branch.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Certifications Useful?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/are-certifications-useful/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/are-certifications-useful/</guid>
      <description>There are several benefits to getting an IT certification, and several associated costs too.&#xA;Certifications can give you the chance to learn needed skills, and be a quick way to show employers you have those skills.&#xA;On the other hand, certifications can require studying or coursework. You will invest a significant amount of time to master the material. They cost up to several hundred dollars to take.&#xA;So how do you know that the benefits will outweigh the costs for you?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Onboarding Software Developers in Your agile Team</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/onboarding-software-developers-in-your-agile-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/onboarding-software-developers-in-your-agile-team/</guid>
      <description>Now that you have gone through the long and tedious process of hiring a talented developer with vetting and interview activities, it is easy to think that the hard part is done [1] [2].&#xA;There is no doubt that hiring good people is challenging and competitive, but it is a mistake to think that the challenge ends when you hired a new collaborator.&#xA;Onboarding software developers is just as important for getting the most out of the hiring process.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Clojure II</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/teaching-clojure-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/teaching-clojure-ii/</guid>
      <description>Functional programming is hype for the last ten years.&#xA;All popular programming languages have added support to functional concepts for years.&#xA;Not all developers are embracing the new approach and using the provided constructs.&#xA;I often have to read source code which uses only idioms defined in the last millennium. I cringed and asked myself why developers are writing such awkward code?&#xA;What does it mean to code with functional paradigms?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Clojure I</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/teaching-clojure-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/teaching-clojure-i/</guid>
      <description>Functional programming is hype for the last ten years. You find a lot of blogs and videos stating object-oriented languages are doomed.&#xA;Almost all most popular languages have added some support to functional concepts in the last years.&#xA;Java introduced lambda expressions and single abstract method interfaces SAM with Java 8 in March 2014. Java developers are empowered to write functional code for almost ten years.&#xA;Other languages such as Python, C++ or C# added their own functional extensions in newer revisions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java 20</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/java-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/java-20/</guid>
      <description>Java 20 was released on time to the public. The release has been available for download since 21st March 2023.&#xA;Interestingly, the new Java release contains only incubating or preview JEP proposals. No final improvements are part of this version.&#xA;You are a Java developer, you should always install the latest JDK and try it out. Most of the time, all your products will compile and run on the new release without any changes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Software Developer Assumptions</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/software-developer-assumptions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/software-developer-assumptions/</guid>
      <description>Here are some software development topics I have learnt to like after 40 years in the industry.&#xA;I worked at quite a few industrial and commercial digital product development initiatives. I truly enjoyed creating successful solutions.&#xA;Over the years, I encountered similar architecture and design patterns when creating source code for these applications.&#xA;I started programming with languages such as Ada, Portal, and C. I embraced object-oriented languages with first C++ and later Java.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Measurements and Units</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/measurements-and-units/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/measurements-and-units/</guid>
      <description>JSR-385 could have saved Mars Climate Orbiter[2] in year 1999.&#xA;Accidents in computer applications happen again and again due to calculation errors.&#xA;The International System of Units SI, commonly known as the metric system, is the international standard for measurement.&#xA;The International Treaty of the Mete was signed in Paris on May 20, 1875, by seventeen countries, including the United States.&#xA;In May 2019, the system of units was updated.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java, Groovy, Clojure</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/java-groovy-clojure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/java-groovy-clojure/</guid>
      <description>Professional software developers shall master their primary technology stack and programming language.&#xA;I am a proficient and experienced programmer in Java.&#xA;I have written production code in Java for the last twenty years.&#xA;I decided to study the language in depth and acquired various Java developer certifications.&#xA;I truly love the modern Java language and the available development environments.&#xA;I want to understand the strengths and weaknesses of Java.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doing Agile</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/doing-agile/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2022/doing-agile/</guid>
      <description>In the midst of the agile adoption explosion, many teams are experiencing difficulties.&#xA;Organizations often mix agile with Scrum.&#xA;One of the most common misconceptions about Scrum is that it is synonymous with agile. Agile Manifesto is an umbrella term that refers to a family of approaches that share common values and principles.&#xA;Scrum is a commonly used agile framework that offers suggestions for how work can be organized to maximize the value of the end-user.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Design Modeling</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/agile-design-modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/agile-design-modeling/</guid>
      <description>Unknown reference: implementing-domain-driven-desing The line between software development and software architecture is a tricky one.&#xA;Some people will tell you that it does not exist and that architecture is simply an extension of the design process undertaken by developers. Others will make out it is a massive gaping chasm that can only be crossed by lofty developers. They believe you must always abstract your abstractions and not get bogged down by those pesky implementation details.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I Learnt Teaching Agile Software Architecture</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/what-i-learnt-teaching-agile-software-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/what-i-learnt-teaching-agile-software-architecture/</guid>
      <description>I am teaching agile software architecture and techniques SWAT as advanced bachelor level lecture weighted with 3 ECTS.&#xA;I gave this training the last three years at Lucerne University of Applied Sciences and Arts HSLU in Switzerland.&#xA;All materials are released under the Creative Commons copyright.&#xA;The course contents are aligned with the big software architecture programs.&#xA;The Open Group organization is the steward of TOGAF standard. TOGAF is the worldwide industrial standard for enterprise software architecture.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving a Static Web Site Build With Hugo and Docsy</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/improving-a-static-web-site-build-with-hugo-and-docsy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/improving-a-static-web-site-build-with-hugo-and-docsy/</guid>
      <description>The static website build tool Hugo is awesome. With the extensive built-in feature set of Hugo and the feature-rich text formatting options that Asciidoc offers, it creates a blogging experience composed of easy content management and fun writing experience.&#xA;In most static site generators including Hugo, Markdown is the one and only first-class citizen when it comes to creating posts.&#xA;However, in recent Hugo versions, external helpers are an official feature.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Requirements Engineering</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/agile-requirements-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/agile-requirements-engineering/</guid>
      <description>Lately, I was asked which new approaches should be used for agile requirements engineering. Did we find a new silver bullet to write software specifications the agile way?&#xA;The answer is easy. We do not need new approaches or complicated processes. Start with proven principles and learn.&#xA;Impact Mapping and Story Mapping are successful approaches to identify and prioritize your functions. Specification by Example and User Stories as a discussion allow you to refine your understanding of what your customers need.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Service for Developer Game Changer</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/self-service-for-developer-game-changer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/self-service-for-developer-game-changer/</guid>
      <description>Often, I hear complain that the IT department is not reacting to developer’s needs. They are slow, clumsy and too administrative. Harsher words state they are incompetent.&#xA;I have observed a clear trend in Switzerland since around 2015 to solve these tensions.&#xA;Standard IT services such as docker images, database instances or internal domain names are provided through self-service kiosks.&#xA;What are the advantages of this approach?&#xA;Advantages The advantages to providing a self-service kiosk for users in an academical or industrial environment are:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Software Architecture is Mainstream</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/agile-software-architecture-is-mainstream/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/agile-software-architecture-is-mainstream/</guid>
      <description>Slowly, slowly major actors in the software architecture landscape acknowledge agile development is state of the industry approach to building software products.&#xA;They are still struggling to integrate their older views in a faster, iterative, incremental development approach. The duration of a regular Scrum sprint is usually two weeks.&#xA;More important, they have discovered we build products because no customers buy projects. They buy solutions and products.&#xA;I am relieved I need less fight to convince enterprise architects that agile is the way.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Software Development for Students</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/software-development-for-students/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/software-development-for-students/</guid>
      <description>Computer science students shall achieve technical excellence when reaching bachelor level. They should be proficient with industry good practices.&#xA;Students understand the theory and principles behind these practices. Experience with one of the best of breed tools enforces learning and automatism.&#xA;The focus of a technical university is to teach the concepts and methods. The tools are used to practice and to increase student learning.&#xA;Source Code Version Management with Git Git is the standard tool for the distributed source code management system.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gitlab for Bachelor Students</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/gitlab-for-bachelor-students/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/gitlab-for-bachelor-students/</guid>
      <description>Computer science students shall be proficient with a basic set of software development techniques.&#xA;Technical excellence is a mandatory skill for all software developers.&#xA;Agile development approaches are state of the industry and used in almost all software development initiatives.&#xA;DevOps approaches are used in modern organizations. They predate agile development approaches.&#xA;Technical schools should provide an in-depth experience in these areas to prepare their students for their future activities after completing their bachelor.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Support Comments for Static Hugo Website</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/support-comments-for-static-hugo-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/support-comments-for-static-hugo-website/</guid>
      <description>There are times in software when you are facing a problem, you find an off-the-shelf solution, and a few lines of code later it just works.&#xA;Today I lived one of those moments.&#xA;The whole configuration of comments and modification of the Docsy theme took around one hour.&#xA;Motivation I wanted to add a comment section to this blog for a while. I was reluctant to implement one myself the classical way, using an external service such as disqus.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating a technical Website with Hugo and Asciidoc</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/creating-a-technical-website-with-hugo-and-asciidoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/creating-a-technical-website-with-hugo-and-asciidoc/</guid>
      <description>I hosted my technical blogs on blogger for years.&#xA;If I correctly remember, I started to use blogger ten years ago. It was a good choice at that time.&#xA;I could easily write blogs and publish them.&#xA;It is a great tool with some drawbacks. Over the years, the deficiencies sting more and more&#xA;The major drawbacks are:&#xA;Their editor is brittle, with limited functionality and unreliable. The generated HTML is not legible and does not support concepts such as micro fragments, meta information or simple functions such as source code highlighting.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Git Local Repositories for the Impatient</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/git-local-repositories-for-the-impatient/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/git-local-repositories-for-the-impatient/</guid>
      <description>You shall put your source code and text documentation under a version management system.&#xA;The actual industrial standard for version control systems is git, a distributed version control system - DVCS -. It tracks changes in any set of computer files, usually used for coordinating work among programmers who are collaboratively developing source code during software development.&#xA;Subversion was a great tool and should now be retired. Simple refactoring activities with renaming will already corrupt a subversion repository.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Git Branches for the Impatient</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/git-branches-for-the-impatient/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/git-branches-for-the-impatient/</guid>
      <description>You are working in a small mostly collocated development team. Sometimes a team member works from a remote location.&#xA;You have one git repository accessible to all team members.&#xA;This repository is used to share source code and documentation artifacts.&#xA;You use the actual industrial standard for version control systems is git.&#xA;You decided to use branches to implement new features or fix errors instead of using Trunk-Based Development.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
