<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ideas on tangly Components</title>
    <link>https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ideas on tangly Components</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Agile Product Management</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/agile-product-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/agile-product-management/</guid>
      <description>Small and medium-sized enterprises often struggle with the implementation of digital product management.&#xA;They have a heterogeneous portfolio of products targeting their customer segments. The development capacities are limited and shared between the products. Often a team is responsible for the development and support of multiple product lines.&#xA;The digital products have different life cycles and customer segments. They are often implemented with different technologies and stacks [1]. Life cycles are strongly influenced by the customer segments, the technology stack, and the architecture [2].</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Architecture</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/agile-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/agile-architecture/</guid>
      <description>Agile Architecture Principles You are applying the agile and lean approach to your software products development. Your teams use Scrum or Kanban to deliver running software at least every two weeks. The product launch is a tremendous success. You will likely sell the solution for the next ten years.&#xA;How shall you define and nurture the software architecture of your product and insure a long living and high-quality solution? The experts tell you the design is emergent.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Transformations</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/agile-transformations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/agile-transformations/</guid>
      <description>Agile Transformations Agile transformation is as an act of transforming an organization’s form or nature gradually. The new form is able to thrive in a flexible, collaborative, self-organizing, fast changing environment.&#xA;The Agile Manifesto values and principles can be taught and exercised throughout any type of organization as it is not limited to development teams.&#xA;The entire organization needs to understand the values and principles of an agile transformation to benefit from the rewards of achieving healthy agility.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design Conventions</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/design-conventions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/design-conventions/</guid>
      <description>Design Conventions Audit Event Conventions The event field is one of the following values&#xA;import Any entity imported from an external source is audited.&#xA;export Any entity exported to an external source is audited.&#xA;create Each time a file is generated and exported shall be audited. For example, the creation of an invoice document is audited.&#xA;login Login of a user.&#xA;logout Logout of a user.&#xA;The component field has the structure net.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Good Practices for Enterprise Java Solutions</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/development-good-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/development-good-practices/</guid>
      <description>Good Practices for Enterprise Java Solutions Bounded Domain Development Knowledge Database Todo&#xA;Write FAQ in Asciidoc</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extendable Models</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/extendable-domain-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/extendable-domain-models/</guid>
      <description>Extendable Domain Models - === Introduction&#xA;Identifiers Names Codes Tags Comments Lessons Learnt Future Research Themes To be written&#xA;Links [1] The power of Tags and Comments. Marcel Baumann. 2020&#xA;[1] Reference Codes. Marcel Baumann. 2020&#xA;[1] Meaningful Identifiers. Marcel Baumann. 2021&#xA;[1] Identifiers and Names. Marcel Baumann. 2020</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Architecture Code Scene</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/architecture-code-scene/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/architecture-code-scene/</guid>
      <description>Architecture Code Scene Purpose Agile development teams shall manage and diminish their technical debt. We provide instruments to increase the pay-off of refactoring measures. The most relevant source code parts should be refactored first. But how can we identify them?&#xA;Git is the de facto standard for version management systems. Git contains the whole evolution story of our source code. We use these data to identify areas under repetitive change or often needing fixing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Components Publication</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/components-publication/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/components-publication/</guid>
      <description>Components Publication Regular Git Repository Update Push the changes to the GitHub repository Open Source Components.&#xA;Verify that the build job in the CI pipeline was successful.&#xA;Push the changes to the GitHub repository. The statistics for developer activities will be automatically updated.&#xA;Continuous Delivery Pipelines See Readme.&#xA;Maven Central Publication The following process is used to publish tangly open source component on Maven Central.&#xA;Publish artifacts of a component with the script uploadToMavenCentral.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Functional Programming</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/functional-programming-in-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/ideas/functional-programming-in-java/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Functional Object-Oriented Order of execution is not always important. It can be asynchronous.&#xA;A specific execution sequence of statements is crucial&#xA;Functions are basic building elements to work with data structures.&#xA;Objects are the main abstractions for data&#xA;Follows the declarative paradigm.&#xA;Follows the imperative paradigm.&#xA;Focuses on the result desired and its final conditions.&#xA;Focuses on how the desired result can be achieved.&#xA;Ensure immutability; programs should be stateless.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
