<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Git on tangly Components</title>
    <link>https://blog.tangly.net/tags/git/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Git on tangly Components</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.tangly.net/tags/git/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Commits for the Impatient</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/semantic-commits-for-the-impatient/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/semantic-commits-for-the-impatient/</guid>
      <description>The conventional commits specification is a lightweight convention on top of commit messages. The additional information classifies the type of work performed in the commit.&#xA;A developer infers the importance of the task by looking to the type of the commit. The message communicates the nature of changes to teammates, the public, and other stakeholders.&#xA;Contributors of project repositories know that a well-designed Git commit message is the best way to communicate the context about a change to other developers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Git Tag for the Impatient</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/git-tag-for-the-impatient/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/git-tag-for-the-impatient/</guid>
      <description>The development software team has reached a milestone.&#xA;A working application with a set of features is available. All tests are green.&#xA;The application can potentially be shipped to internal or external customers.&#xA;How can you mark this event in the git repository of the application?&#xA;Use tags to recognize this state in the list of changes of your shared Git repository.&#xA;Listing Your Tags Listing the existing tags in Git is straightforward.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Git Rebase and Merge for the Impatient</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/git-rebase-and-merge-for-the-impatient/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/git-rebase-and-merge-for-the-impatient/</guid>
      <description>Both the rebase and merge commands provide similar functionalities.&#xA;They combine the work of multiple developers into a single entity, integrating changes between branches.&#xA;That about sums up their similarities.&#xA;The operation git merge is a way of combining changes from one source branch into another target branch. The operation leaves commit messages in the history.&#xA;The operation git rebase is a way of moving the changes from one branch onto another branch.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Software Development for Students</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/software-development-for-students/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/software-development-for-students/</guid>
      <description>Computer science students shall achieve technical excellence when reaching bachelor level. They should be proficient with industry good practices.&#xA;Students understand the theory and principles behind these practices. Experience with one of the best of breed tools enforces learning and automatism.&#xA;The focus of a technical university is to teach the concepts and methods. The tools are used to practice and to increase student learning.&#xA;Source Code Version Management with Git Git is the standard tool for the distributed source code management system.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gitlab for Bachelor Students</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/gitlab-for-bachelor-students/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/gitlab-for-bachelor-students/</guid>
      <description>Computer science students shall be proficient with a basic set of software development techniques.&#xA;Technical excellence is a mandatory skill for all software developers.&#xA;Agile development approaches are state of the industry and used in almost all software development initiatives.&#xA;DevOps approaches are used in modern organizations. They predate agile development approaches.&#xA;Technical schools should provide an in-depth experience in these areas to prepare their students for their future activities after completing their bachelor.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Git Local Repositories for the Impatient</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/git-local-repositories-for-the-impatient/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/git-local-repositories-for-the-impatient/</guid>
      <description>You shall put your source code and text documentation under a version management system.&#xA;The actual industrial standard for version control systems is git, a distributed version control system - DVCS -. It tracks changes in any set of computer files, usually used for coordinating work among programmers who are collaboratively developing source code during software development.&#xA;Subversion was a great tool and should now be retired. Simple refactoring activities with renaming will already corrupt a subversion repository.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Git Branches for the Impatient</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/git-branches-for-the-impatient/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/git-branches-for-the-impatient/</guid>
      <description>You are working in a small mostly collocated development team. Sometimes a team member works from a remote location.&#xA;You have one git repository accessible to all team members.&#xA;This repository is used to share source code and documentation artifacts.&#xA;You use the actual industrial standard for version control systems is git.&#xA;You decided to use branches to implement new features or fix errors instead of using Trunk-Based Development.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
