<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Organization on tangly Components</title>
    <link>https://blog.tangly.net/tags/organization/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Organization on tangly Components</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.tangly.net/tags/organization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How To Improve</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/how-to-improve/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/how-to-improve/</guid>
      <description>You attended a famous or a local technical school. You are the proud owner of a bachelor or a master degree in science.&#xA;You are a certified engineer.&#xA;You are now a full-time software developer. You write daily productive code with your colleagues in your current company.&#xA;Hopefully you studied software engineering at least as a minor.&#xA;How can you continuously improve in your profession?&#xA;How can you become proficient in the new features and possibilities of the technologies you use daily?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Quest for an Agile Company: Eight Years tangly llc</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/the-quest-for-an-agile-company-eight-years-tangly-llc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2024/the-quest-for-an-agile-company-eight-years-tangly-llc/</guid>
      <description>We are an agile and software technology boutique.&#xA;We often work as Scrum masters, product owners and technical agile coaches. Regularly we are involved in the architecture and development of software products.&#xA;Our collaborators love to coaching, mentoring, and training.&#xA;We regularly work at the customer site. We also more and more often work online with our international customers.&#xA;How do you organize such a company?&#xA;How do collaborators work together?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20th Devoxx Belgium Conference 2023</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/20th-devoxx-belgium-conference-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/20th-devoxx-belgium-conference-2023/</guid>
      <description>I attended the highly anticipated 20th edition of Devoxx Belgium 2023.&#xA;Building on the success of the previous year, which attracted over 3,200 attendees, this five-day technology conference is set to exceed expectations.&#xA;The fresh release of Java 21 is a hot topic. Renowned speakers share their knowledge and discuss the enhancements that this new version brings, providing a valuable learning opportunity.&#xA;Attending Devoxx Belgium presents a remarkable opportunity to broaden your knowledge, refine your skills, and gain firsthand experience with the most recent technologies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My New MacBookPro</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/my-new-macbookpro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/my-new-macbookpro/</guid>
      <description>I just received my new MacBookPro M2 Max with 32 GB of RAM and 1 TB SSD [1].&#xA;I know. I am a geek who loves his technical gadgets. I convinced my wife these gadgets are way cheaper than a sports car.&#xA;More seriously, I easily use my workstation forty hours a week. I really appreciate a stable and fast machine. My eyes are thankful if the display has a high resolution and the refresh rate fulfills ergonomic criteria [2].</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Quest for an Agile Company: Seven Years tangly llc</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/the-quest-for-an-agile-company-seven-years-tangly-llc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/the-quest-for-an-agile-company-seven-years-tangly-llc/</guid>
      <description>We are an agile software coaching and digital product development boutique.&#xA;Since our inception, we have created digital products using agile approaches. Our preferred tools are Scrum, Lean Software Development, DevOps, LeSS.&#xA;The created digital products are successful in the market.&#xA;They exhibit good quality. Sound engineering approaches were used to design and construct them in a timely and economical way.&#xA;Our customers learnt how to deploy updates and new functionalities in a matter of days.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Technical Interviews</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/technical-interviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/technical-interviews/</guid>
      <description>Your sole goal is to hire a qualified collaborator with potential.&#xA;For example, you need a great software engineer with social competence. He is a professional developer and has knowledge of the technology stack [1] your company is using. The candidate naturally understands agile and DevOps approaches.&#xA;How can you convince him to sign the contract and start working on your cool product?&#xA;Hiring is like dating.&#xA;Both parties shall be motivated to deepen their relationship and enter a binding agreement.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SME IT Responsible</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/sme-it-responsible/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/sme-it-responsible/</guid>
      <description>What does a senior manager in charge of information technology?&#xA;An IT director is the information technology right-hand man of the company’s manager. He sometimes has the shiny title of CIO. He proposes and implements the IT strategy of the company.&#xA;He intervenes at different levels in the management and optimization of the company’s information system.&#xA;This encompasses hardware and software infrastructures, information architecture, business tools, dedicated internal or external human resources, and often old technology.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Select An Agile Software Development Partner</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/select-an-agile-software-development-partner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2023/select-an-agile-software-development-partner/</guid>
      <description>It is not unusual for businesses to turn to third-party companies when they want help to achieve their goals without increasing internal overhead.&#xA;This type of outsourcing is especially common for projects that require tremendous amounts of effort or specific skill sets [1].&#xA;Time constraints are often a supplemental driving factor.&#xA;Partnering up with another business to help meet your needs is a viable and widespread solution [2]. It often makes sense for businesses trying to tackle a massive software development project while focusing on the current needs of their clients.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Technical Team Lead</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/technical-team-lead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/technical-team-lead/</guid>
      <description>I lately had to explain to customers what are the responsibilities of a technical team lead. Managers often grasp the people aspects embedded in the words team lead. The understanding of the word technical is strangely often missing.&#xA;A technical team leads coaches and teaches the subtleties of the used technology stack to his team and organization. This person should be able to create or review a software architecture. He has a deep understanding of technological concepts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Journey to be a Digital Company - tangly llc</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/a-journey-to-be-a-digital-company-tangly-llc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/a-journey-to-be-a-digital-company-tangly-llc/</guid>
      <description>I long dreamed of working in a digital environment. I shall no longer print out a form, sign it by hand and use snake mail to deliver it to the receiving party. All company documents are stored electronically. I can search any artifacts by content and get a list of all interesting items in seconds.&#xA;Our software service company is an ideal candidate to validate if this assumption is realistic.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The World is a Better Place and We Must Tackle Climate Change</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/the-world-is-a-better-place-and-we-must-tackle-climate-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/the-world-is-a-better-place-and-we-must-tackle-climate-change/</guid>
      <description>The world has really improved in a lot of areas.&#xA;_Stop whining we are doomed.&#xA;And yes, we must act strong and fast to tackle the climate change disaster._&#xA;Remember how much the world bettered the last centuries.&#xA;We are not doomed, we must solve the next challenges instead of just complaining and doing nothing.&#xA;Ask yourself if you need a car.&#xA;Travel by train instead of flying.&#xA;Schedule a video conference instead of a business trip.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I still love to use a MacBookPro and MacOS in 2019</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/why-i-still-love-to-use-a-macbookpro-and-macos-in-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/why-i-still-love-to-use-a-macbookpro-and-macos-in-2019/</guid>
      <description>As a young developer, I loved Linux, compiled new kernels during evening sessions and struggled days to have the correct drivers for the graphic card and communication components of my notebook.&#xA;I grew older and decided to enjoy my weekends, family and outdoor activities.&#xA;And surely I shall have no virus, trojan and other evils in my workstation. So I went to macOS and Apple notebooks without regrets.&#xA;Gains The major gains using macOS are</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clean Your Desk and Define New Year Improvements</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/clean-your-desk-and-define-new-year-improvements/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/clean-your-desk-and-define-new-year-improvements/</guid>
      <description>It is Christmastime.&#xA;Clean your desk and the content of your workstation. Upgrade your tools and your development environment to the actual version.&#xA;It is time to add automated build pipelines, TDD, ATDD, and Docker to your toolbox. Embrace agile approaches.&#xA;Work focused and avoid overtime. Prioritize outcomes instead of outputs. Enjoy family life, practice sport, and pursue continuous training.&#xA;Clean Your Desk Digitalize Your Office It is time to sell the last fax device in your office and plan to remove your big printer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is Our Specialty as Agile Coaches at tangly?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/what-is-our-specialty-as-agile-coaches-at-tangly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/what-is-our-specialty-as-agile-coaches-at-tangly/</guid>
      <description>You have more agile coaches on the market than sand-corns on a regular beach.&#xA;They all promise the holly grail of agile product development, highly productive teams and perfect applications for internal and external customers.&#xA;Why should any sane customer hire us to deploy or perfect their agile approach?&#xA;Your overall goal is to continuously improve the products delivered to customers.&#xA;I am convinced to achieve ingrained success an agile coach shall:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fun at Workplace</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/fun-at-workplace/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/fun-at-workplace/</guid>
      <description>It is Spring in Switzerland. We often have time for small talk because it is cold or rainy outside.&#xA;Quite a few of the discussions are about job opportunities, and how interesting and motivating the current activities are.&#xA;I selected two articles to help everybody to decide if your software development job is worth the effort.&#xA;Go through the questions and ask yourself if the current product provides the current settings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Found a Limited Liability Company in Switzerland</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/found-a-limited-liability-company-in-switzerland/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/found-a-limited-liability-company-in-switzerland/</guid>
      <description>I left the company I founded 20 years ago and needed a new home to work and have access to social insurance.&#xA;The best legal construct in Switzerland and in Europe is to establish a limited liability company.&#xA;You need such a construct in Switzerland to work as a software specialist. The legal Swiss institutions, such as taxes, social insurances, and accident insurances are challenging and almost unfair with freelancers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is an Agile Company?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/what-is-an-agile-company/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/what-is-an-agile-company/</guid>
      <description>Lately, people often ask me what is an agile company.&#xA;They have an understanding of agile software development techniques such as Scrum, Lean Software Development, Kanban, eXtreme Programming but no clue how a company could be agile.&#xA;What does it mean to be an agile organization?&#xA;One way to approach this theme is to implement concepts of the above-mentioned agile approaches.&#xA;These are the pillars for iterative incremental improvements.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I use a MacBookPro and OS X</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/why-i-use-a-macbookpro-and-os-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/why-i-use-a-macbookpro-and-os-x/</guid>
      <description>I loved Linux as a young developer. I compiled new kernels during evening sessions. I worked hard to install and configure drivers to support the hardware I had bought.&#xA;I explored forums and talked with technical support specialists to activate hardware or support the resolution of my display. I struggled days to have the correct drivers for the graphic card and communication components of my notebook.&#xA;I grew older and decided to enjoy my evenings and weekends with my family and friends.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
