<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tangly Components – organization</title>
    <link>https://blog.tangly.net/tags/organization/</link>
    <description>Recent content in organization on tangly Components</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://blog.tangly.net/tags/organization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Technical Team Lead</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/technical-team-lead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/technical-team-lead/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;div class=&#34;sect1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;_technical_team_lead&#34;&gt;Technical Team Lead&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sectionbody&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;imageblock left&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;../pics/2021-07-03-head.png&#34; alt=&#34;2021 07 03 head&#34; width=&#34;420&#34; height=&#34;360&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I lately had to explain customers what are the responsibilities of a technical team lead.
Managers often grasp the people aspects embedded in the words &lt;strong&gt;team lead&lt;/strong&gt;.
The understanding of the word &lt;strong&gt;technical&lt;/strong&gt; is strangely often missing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A technical team lead coaches and teaches the subtleties of the used technology stack to his team and organization.
This person should be able to create or review a software architecture.
He has a deep understanding of technological concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More importantly he can write productive source code.
Ideally she should &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pair_programming&#34;&gt;Pair Program&lt;/a&gt; with team members or
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mob_programming&#34;&gt;Mob Program&lt;/a&gt; with her whole team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph text-center&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A technical team lead must be technically savvy&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_job_description&#34;&gt;Job Description&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here a standard &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Job_description&#34;&gt;Job Description&lt;/a&gt; for a Java technical team lead as often published on job platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are looking for an experienced Java technical lead to be responsible for providing solutions for technical issues which may affect product delivery.
The Java technical lead will facilitate requirement analyses, conduct peer reviews and provide feedback, and enhance frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be successful as a Java technical lead, you should demonstrate sound knowledge of industry best practices, good organizational and leadership skills, and proficiency in Java technologies.
A top-notch Java technical lead should have good analytical skills, the ability to anticipate issues and frame remedial actions, and excellent teamwork skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;_java_technical_lead_responsibilities&#34;&gt;Java Technical Lead Responsibilities&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;ulist&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Performing requirement analyses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developing high-quality and detailed designs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conducting unit testing using automated unit test frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identifying risk and conducting mitigation action planning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conducting configuration of your own work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reviewing the work of other developers and providing feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using coding standards and best practices ensuring quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;_java_technical_lead_requirements&#34;&gt;Java Technical Lead Requirements&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The candidate has a bachelor or master degree in engineering, information systems or related.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;ulist&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extensive experience in the IT industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sound knowledge of estimation techniques.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excellent knowledge of Java and web services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sound knowledge of Java technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good understanding of unit testing methodologies and agile approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excellent analytical skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exceptional communication skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an Internet example please see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.betterteam.com/java-technical-lead-job-description&#34;&gt;Java Technical Lead Job Description&lt;/a&gt;.
You can also find job descriptions under &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.indeed.com&#34;&gt;Indeed&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.glassdoor.com&#34;&gt;Glassdoor&lt;/a&gt;.
Similar examples can also be found under &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com&#34;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_responsibilities&#34;&gt;Responsibilities&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below a description of the responsibilities of a technical lead.
A technical lead is responsible for the following tasks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;ulist&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hiring and training technical personnel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delegating work to team members&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collaborating with their team to identify and fix technical problems&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Analyzing users&amp;#39; needs and then finding applications to serve them&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating end goals for their team&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Checking that software and applications are updated&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supervising system modifications&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conducting security and governance audits to identify areas of improvement&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guiding their team through technical issues and challenges&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A technical lead is responsible for helping their team members with the technical aspects of their jobs, such as coding and programming.
They may also explain new projects to their team and troubleshoot any problems that occur.
In comparison, an engineering manager is more focused on managing their employees.
They are responsible for business growth and team deadlines, and they typically serve as their team’s representative to the rest of the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an engineering manager, you need to have excellent people management skills and be able to assess your team’s long-term goals.
While you are more likely to work hands-on and focus on day-to-day tasks as a technical lead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: A Journey to be a Digital Company - tangly llc</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/a-journey-to-be-a-digital-company-tangly-llc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/a-journey-to-be-a-digital-company-tangly-llc/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;div class=&#34;sect1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;_a_journey_to_be_a_digital_company_tangly_llc&#34;&gt;A Journey to be a Digital Company - tangly llc&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sectionbody&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;imageblock left&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;../pics/2019-12-01-head.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;2019 12 01 head&#34; width=&#34;420&#34; height=&#34;360&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I long dreamed to work in a digital environment.
I shall no longer print out a form, sign it by hand and use snake mail to deliver it to the receiving party.
All company documents are stored electronically.
I can search any artifacts by content and get a list of its in seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our software service company is an ideal candidate to validate if this assumption is realistic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;quoteblock&#34;&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Profit is like the air we breathe. We need air to live, but we don’t live to breathe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;attribution&#34;&gt;
— Frederic Laloux
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_what_is_digital_working&#34;&gt;What is Digital Working?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You shall use digital tools and workflows to perform all your work related tasks.
We want to increase interactions with our coworkers and remove any tedious activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;ulist&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fax is dead. You do not need faxes in Europe - no more waiting at the fax machine,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You send your contracts electronically. You can sign them electronically - no more printing or paper archiving,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You send invoices electronically - no more printing,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You perform your accounting electronically and avoid any paper archive,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You coordinate with your team members with chat tools; not over the phone or with emails.
N o more answering long emails with huge cc list and less business travel,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any document can collaboratively be edited online by multiple collaborators working distributively.
No more calls to find the latest version of a document or to remind somebody to unlock the document.
Or worse finding out why your changes just disappeared,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any collaborator has access to all our assets.
You monitor all software continuous integration and delivery pipelines from anywhere if authorized.
The information is available with a regular notebook or on any mobile device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you have a positive impact on the environment.
Less traveling, less paper and less shipping.
Embrace the digital age and be environment aware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_all_activities_and_processes_are_digitized&#34;&gt;All Activities and Processes are Digitized&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;_internal_tools&#34;&gt;Internal Tools&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tangly.net&#34;&gt;tangly&lt;/a&gt; we use internally&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;ulist&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Business Apps and LibreOffice for office work, email, calendar, video conference and document sharing.
All documents are stored in our product or company online drives,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Business Apps administration console to manage our technical infrastructure such as workstations, mobile devices, DNS record,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bitbucket and continuous integration, delivery and deployment pipelines for software development,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trello for activities management and our electronic Scrum or Kanban board.
We use analog boards if the team members are collocated - we are trying to avoid JIRA. It would be just overkill for us -,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slack is our preferred chat platform,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.banana.ch/&#34;&gt;Banana&lt;/a&gt; is our accounting solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We never had to bought or rent a printer, a landline or a fax machine since founding the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_external_tools&#34;&gt;External Tools&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use an impressive set of tools to collaborate with our customers and partners&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;ulist&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google email, calendar and meetup for communication,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bitbucket.org/&#34;&gt;Bitbucket&lt;/a&gt; and continuous integration, delivery and deployment pipelines for software development,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maven Central to distribute public binary software artifacts,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slack is our preferred chat platform,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Groups for technical discussion,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blogger to publish articles to our community,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LinkedIn for marketing,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GPG and S/MIME to securely exchange confidential documentation or protect sensitive emails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An impressive set of processes with governmental organizations can now be performed electronically in Switzerland&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;ulist&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VAT authority support declaration and payment electronically,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zefix.ch/en/search/entity/welcome&#34;&gt;Company register&lt;/a&gt; in Switzerland give access to all registered companies,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Salary declarations and forms are generated electronically through government &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.elohnausweis-ssk.ch/de/&#34;&gt;online tools&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Swiss post office support package tracking and delivery rescheduling online,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Swiss social insurances - pension fund, children allowance, military service, unemployment insurance - declaration and mutation are available online,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taxes declaration can be performed with a downloadable government application,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Public transportation company tickets can be bought online and delivered electronically on collaborator’s mobile device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_what_is_working&#34;&gt;What is Working?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;ulist&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We perform marketing and sales through online platforms and avoid any physical ads platform,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We communicate through our company online platform. We never use physical documents and minimize email usage,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We deliver all contractual documents electronically,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We deliver all invoices electronically,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have our library and technical documentation as static websites, wikis, and electronic documents.
We do not possess any paper books,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our archive is online. We do not possess a physical archive of documents or contractual documents and never bought or rented physical space for this purpose,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We never did own or rent any printer, land phone line or fax machine. The quality and speed of our Internet connect improve yearly.
It is already above our keenest expectations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_what_is_not_working&#34;&gt;What is NOT Working?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly most of the processes with private companies providing mandatory services cannot be done electronically due to obsolete information systems and cumbersome processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;ulist&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accident insurance (BU and NBU) still request declaration of incidents and communication over paper mail,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pension fund insurance company provides a web portal but still send some forms over paper mail,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tax declaration must still be printed out and sent to the tax office of the state government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of the government solutions provide modern API.
We still must manually input our data in their portals.
The old interfaces they provide are only partially available through expensive commercial solutions.
By old interfaces we mean proprietary formats and proprietary file transfer solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_findings&#34;&gt;Findings&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last four years were a game changer.
A lot of manual activities are now fully digitized and often automatized.
We never had to buy a printer.
The last year we seldom had to scan a paper document.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The partners still requesting paper interactions are some government agencies and some insurances.
We observe a decrease of such physical interactions. Our partners are steadily - if sometimes slowly - digitizing their workflows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slowly digital versions for invoices are emerging.
This approach should allow automated payment workflows.
Interestingly private customers already have billing and e-payment solutions.
Similar solutions for corporate customers are either not available or incredibly limited, cumbersome and expensive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next big step will be the emergence of API to integrate the steps in a workflow specific to the involved companies.
For example the technical part of the onboarding process for a new employee could be fully automated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: The World is a Better Place and We Must Tackle Climate Change</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/the-world-is-a-better-place-and-we-must-tackle-climate-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/the-world-is-a-better-place-and-we-must-tackle-climate-change/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;div class=&#34;sect1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;_the_world_is_a_better_place_and_we_must_tackle_climate_change&#34;&gt;The World is a Better Place and We Must Tackle Climate Change&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sectionbody&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;imageblock left&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;../pics/2019-07-01-head.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;2019 07 01 head&#34; width=&#34;420&#34; height=&#34;360&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world has really improved in a lot of areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stop whining we are doomed.
And yes we must act strong and fast to tackle the climate change disaster.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not forget how much the world &lt;strong&gt;bettered&lt;/strong&gt; the last centuries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are not doomed, we must solve the next challenges instead of just complaining and doing nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;ulist&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask yourself if you need a car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Travel by train instead of flying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schedule a video conference instead of a business trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reduce your plastic and paper usage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each step reduces your carbon footprint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Millions of persons taking similar steps will be a huge improvement. &lt;strong&gt;Just do it!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The late Swedish academic &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hans_Rosling&#34;&gt;Hans Rosling&lt;/a&gt; has identified a worrying trend.
Not only do many people across advanced economies have no idea that the world is becoming a much better place, but they actually even think the opposite.
This is no wonder, when the news focuses on reporting catastrophes, terrorist attacks, wars and famines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who wants to hear about the fact that every day some &lt;strong&gt;200&amp;#39;000&lt;/strong&gt; people around the world are lifted above the $2-a-day poverty line?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or that more than &lt;strong&gt;300&amp;#39;000&lt;/strong&gt; people a day get access to electricity and clean water for the first time every day?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These stories of people in low-income countries simply does not make for exciting news coverage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;admonitionblock caution&#34;&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;
&lt;i class=&#34;fa icon-caution&#34; title=&#34;Caution&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am proud to be an engineer.
Engineering is about models how objects and energy is acting in the universe.
Engineers are well-aware tht facts and empirism validate our assumptions about the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is strange and disturbing to meet people who have opinions and do not want to talk about facts.
Often they grind out sentences to avoid talking about facts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples are flat-earthers believers, vaccination opponents, or wireless opponents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the way do you know that Edward Jenner is considered the founder of vaccinology in the West in 1796.
After he inoculated a 13 year-old-boy with vaccinia virus &lt;em&gt;cowpox&lt;/em&gt;, and demonstrated immunity to smallpox.
In 1798, the first smallpox vaccine was developed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_what_is_better&#34;&gt;What is better?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;_extreme_poverty_is_plumping_down&#34;&gt;Extreme poverty is plumping down&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;imageblock center&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;../pics/2019-07-01-world-poverty.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;2019 07 01 world poverty&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ourworldindata.org/extreme-poverty&#34; class=&#34;bare&#34;&gt;https://ourworldindata.org/extreme-poverty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;_literacy_and_education_is_exploding&#34;&gt;Literacy and education is exploding&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;imageblock center&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;../pics/2019-07-01-world-literacy.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;2019 07 01 world literacy&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ourworldindata.org/literacy&#34; class=&#34;bare&#34;&gt;https://ourworldindata.org/literacy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;_health_is_improving_and_child_mortality_is_crashing&#34;&gt;Health is improving and child mortality is crashing&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;imageblock center&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;../pics/2019-07-01-world-life-expectancy.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;2019 07 01 world life expectancy&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ourworldindata.org/life-expectancy&#34; class=&#34;bare&#34;&gt;https://ourworldindata.org/life-expectancy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please stop the doomsday trashing and start to act to improve your social environment and diminish your solution footprint.
I am tired hearing we cannot improve our world.
Stop lying and simply look at the facts.
Feel free to argument based on facts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recognize that we have difficult problems to solve and success is not guaranteed.
I am just tired of negative thinking and persons claiming we cannot improve our world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start learning and explore the data&lt;/strong&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;https://ourworldindata.org/&#34;&gt;Our World In Data&lt;/a&gt;.
They have a lot of interactive charts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_links&#34;&gt;Links&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;ulist&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.forbes.com/sites/stevedenning/2017/11/30/why-the-world-is-getting-better-why-hardly-anyone-knows-it/#2ab7ae478268&#34;&gt;Why the World Is Getting Better And Why Hardly Anyone Knows It&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbc.com/future/story/20190111-seven-reasons-why-the-world-is-improving&#34;&gt;Seven Reasons the World is Improving&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vox.com/2014/11/24/7272929/global-poverty-health-crime-literacy-good-news&#34;&gt;23 charts and maps that show the world is getting much, much better&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ourworldindata.org/&#34;&gt;Research and interactive data visualizations to understand the world’s largest problems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bbc.com/news/health-47371078&#34;&gt;What do the people of the world die from?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The beautiful book from Hans Rosling is worth studying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Factfulness-Reasons-World-Things-Better-ebook/dp/B0756J1LLV/&#34;&gt;Factfulness: Ten Reasons We are Wrong about the World - and Why Things Are Better Than You Think, Hans Rosling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Why I still love to use a MacBookPro and MacOS in 2019</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/why-i-still-love-to-use-a-macbookpro-and-macos-in-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2019/why-i-still-love-to-use-a-macbookpro-and-macos-in-2019/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;div class=&#34;sect1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;_why_i_still_love_to_use_a_macbookpro_and_macos_in_2019&#34;&gt;Why I still love to use a MacBookPro and macOS in 2019&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sectionbody&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;imageblock left&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;../pics/2019-04-02-head.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;2019 04 02 head&#34; width=&#34;420&#34; height=&#34;360&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a young developer, I loved Linux, compiled new kernels during evening sessions and struggled days to have the correct drivers for the graphic card and communication components of my notebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I grew older and decided to enjoy my weekends, family and outdoor activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And surely I shall have no virus, trojan and other evils on my workstation.
So I went to macOS and Apple notebooks without regrets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_gains&#34;&gt;Gains&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The major gains using macOS are * Still no virus scanner is necessary, the speed-up during complex programming and development activities is tremendous, * No trouble when updating OS, updates are automatic and often no new start is required, Unix command line and tools are available in the console.
Homebrew provides all known and less-known utilities and programs available under Linux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;ulist&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My previous MacBook is now six years old and still used as a development backup platform.
The performance is still very good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My preferred IDE Intellij IDEA works flawlessly on macOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My new MacBookPro is perfect for Java development, database integration and running multiple Docker images locally.
The 32 GB RAM goes a long way to run multiple docker images and databases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No virus scanner is still important.
I was lately at a customer site.
The whole deployment just crashed because IT department decided to update the virus scanner and associated options.
Suddenly, the generated artifacts were considered harmful.
This decision just broke the CI/CD pipeline for hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://brew.sh/&#34;&gt;Homebrew&lt;/a&gt; easily downloads and installs newer versions of favorite applications and utilities.
It solved the dread of macOS slow or missing application updates.
Pre-installed Unix utilities are seldom kept up to date by Apple.
Just use Homebrew and forget about Apple slow updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_daily_development&#34;&gt;Daily Development&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tools I really enjoy and use on a daily basis for software development - mainly Java - are&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;ulist&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jetbrains.com/idea/&#34;&gt;IntelliJ IDEA&lt;/a&gt; IDE is still a dream.
It could sometimes be slightly snappier but still the best Java IDE under the sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;ulist&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UML diagrams are created with &lt;a href=&#34;https://plantuml.com/&#34;&gt;plantUML&lt;/a&gt; and the provided plugin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documents are written in &lt;a href=&#34;https://asciidoc.org/&#34;&gt;Asciidoc&lt;/a&gt; with the existing plugin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/&#34;&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt; is kept up to date with homebrew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gradle.org/&#34;&gt;Gradle Build Tool&lt;/a&gt; is kept up to date either with homebrew or gradlew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Atlassian Cloud applications - &lt;a href=&#34;https://bitbucket.org/&#34;&gt;BitBucket&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://trello.com/&#34;&gt;Trello&lt;/a&gt; and CI pipeline - and SourceTree for some git operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://brew.sh/&#34;&gt;Homebrew&lt;/a&gt; as package manager for utilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.docker.com/&#34;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt; as container manager - for complex product you can run locally kubernetes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/chrome/&#34;&gt;Chrome&lt;/a&gt; is my default browser.
I almost never use _Safari&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Firefox&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I retired &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.virtualbox.org/&#34;&gt;VirtualBox&lt;/a&gt; because I do not need any virtual machines.
They were replaced with Docker images, I stopped using MacPorts.
Homebrew is more than enough for my needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_daily_work&#34;&gt;Daily Work&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tools I used to perform administrative work are * &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.libreoffice.org/&#34;&gt;LibreOffice&lt;/a&gt; - going strong and better every year -, * Google Business for teamwork in the cloud using collaborative tools, * Apple Mail Client with GPG plugin for PGP and S/MIME secure email, * A local Swiss article &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.banana.ch/&#34;&gt;Banana&lt;/a&gt; for accounting and VAT reports for the federal government.
I bought it as soon as the company stopped requesting higher prices for macOS than for the other platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still have no need to use any Microsoft applications.
My findings are inline with the ones in my &lt;a href=&#34;../../2016/why-i-use-a-macbookpro-and-os-x/&#34;&gt;older blog&lt;/a&gt; in March 2016.
I hope Apple will still produce high-quality hardware and software in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only big macOS improvement I am waiting for from Apple is that Apple delegate the installation and update of Unix applications and utilities to Homebrew.
Apple is sadly always behind the release cycle of regular Unix programs.
Homebrew does a way better job to support software developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Clean Your Desk and Define New Year Improvements</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/clean-your-desk-and-define-new-year-improvements/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/clean-your-desk-and-define-new-year-improvements/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;div class=&#34;sect1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;_clean_your_desk_and_define_new_year_improvements&#34;&gt;Clean Your Desk and Define New Year Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sectionbody&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;imageblock left&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;../pics/2017-12-01-head.png&#34; alt=&#34;2017 12 01 head&#34; width=&#34;420&#34; height=&#34;360&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is Christmas time.
Clean your desk and the content of your workstation.
Upgrade your tools and your development environment to the actual version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is time to add automated build pipelines, TDD, ATDD, and Docker to your toolbox.
Embrace agile approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work focused and avoid overtime.
Prioritize outcomes instead of outputs.
Enjoy family life, practice sport, and pursue continuous training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_clean_your_desk&#34;&gt;Clean Your Desk&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;_digitalize_your_office&#34;&gt;Digitalize Your Office&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is time to sell the last fax device in your office and plan to remove your big printer.
Burn your paper documentation and discard your folders.
Please store all the information digitally and have an effective search application in your company.
Use Wiki to publish company data and store knowledge for all collaborators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have a professional handset and a good camera for video conferences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put all your documents on your company drive and index all this information.
Finding relevant data by keyword searching is a huge gain of time.
Another advantage is no more backup of workstations and notebooks.
All mission critical information is always on the company’s drives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;_socialize_with_your_team&#34;&gt;Socialize with your Team&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organize a real team room.
Colocate all your team members, design on big whiteboards.
Please use analog Scrum boards.
You need big whiteboards, analog Scrum boards, meeting corners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Restart your brown bag training program.
A Friday beer event is always a welcome event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Celebrate success after each major release of your products.
Another gain is tension just disappears when people talk around snacks and drink together a glass of wine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_upgrade_your_toolbox&#34;&gt;Upgrade your Toolbox&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a Java developer, it is time to use state of the industry tools and improve your daily work&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;olist arabic&#34;&gt;
&lt;ol class=&#34;arabic&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Java 9 JDK - If you are still working with Java 7 or earlier, you are a laggard&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;olist loweralpha&#34;&gt;
&lt;ol class=&#34;loweralpha&#34; type=&#34;a&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Java 8 public support will end middle of next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Java 10 shall be available next year.
The early releases are already online.
Download them and try the new features.
The local variable declarations are a huge improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are a laggard and security danger if you are still using Java 6 or earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gradle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;olist loweralpha&#34;&gt;
&lt;ol class=&#34;loweralpha&#34; type=&#34;a&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Build, deliver, and deploy your solution with one keystroke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continuous integration, delivery and deployment pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;olist loweralpha&#34;&gt;
&lt;ol class=&#34;loweralpha&#34; type=&#34;a&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never again configure manually a deployment by hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Test environments with Docker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;olist loweralpha&#34;&gt;
&lt;ol class=&#34;loweralpha&#34; type=&#34;a&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never say again, &lt;em&gt;it is working on my machine&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modern IDE such as IntelliJ IDEA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;olist loweralpha&#34;&gt;
&lt;ol class=&#34;loweralpha&#34; type=&#34;a&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very good Gradle support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very good JUnit 5 support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alt-Enter anywhere brings up context-sensitive options.
Run a test, create a test, create subclass, convert to closure, generate missing test methods, remove explicit type, split into declaration and assignment, introduce local variable.
The suggestions are limitless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great Java 8 support, suggesting lambda notation where appropriate!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even displaying anonymous inner class usage (collapsed) as if it was written using a lambda expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quality with PMD, FindBugs, SonarLint, or the build-in rules of IntelliJ&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Banish Flash from your workstation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_new_year_improvements&#34;&gt;New Year Improvements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;_sustainable_pace&#34;&gt;Sustainable Pace&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agile approaches state you should work at a sustainable pace, forty hours a week. Avoid working overtime during the evenings or weekends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy family time, practice sport, give back to the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work with your team, ideally collocated in a team room. Face2Face exchanges and pair working - pair design, pair review, pair programming, pair checkin - are training on the job occasions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;_hone_your_craftsmanship&#34;&gt;Hone your Craftsmanship&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some suggestions to hone your craftsmanship&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;ulist&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Practice coding dojos to improve your programming skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read good technical books, at least one book per quarter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn new shortcuts and plugins for your favorite IDE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Improve the agile, lean, Scrum, LeSS approaches in your department.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Refactor daily code and practice clean-code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Become a master of Git.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Increase self-awareness and work on your soft skills, teamwork shall improve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish you success, fulfillment, happiness and fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: What is Our Specialty as Agile Coaches at tangly?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/what-is-our-specialty-as-agile-coaches-at-tangly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/what-is-our-specialty-as-agile-coaches-at-tangly/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;div class=&#34;sect1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;_what_is_our_specialty_as_agile_coaches_at_tangly&#34;&gt;What is Our Specialty as Agile Coaches at tangly?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sectionbody&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;imageblock left&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;../pics/2017-05-01-head.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;2017 05 01 head&#34; width=&#34;420&#34; height=&#34;360&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have more agile coaches on the market than sand-corns on a regular beach.
They all promise the holly grail of agile product development, highly productive teams and perfect applications for internal and external customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why should any sane customer hire us to deploy or perfect their agile approach?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your overall goal is to continuously improve the products delivered to customers.
I am convinced to achieve ingrained success an agile coach shall:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;ulist&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coach team members how to reach technical excellence.
They build your solution, it shall fulfill the user’s requirements, be of high quality and affordable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn them to attain &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_craftsmanship/&#34;&gt;mastery&lt;/a&gt; and build awesome products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coach the team how to improve, focus and enjoy the work on a daily basis. &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flow_(psychology)&#34;&gt;Flow&lt;/a&gt; shall be natural for them,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coach the organisation how to adapt, provide the ground to have the best collaborators and become most successful in the market.
Use a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lean_startup&#34;&gt;lean approach&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, you need technical coaching, team coaching and organization coaching.
Avoid hiring management consultants with agile painting, coaches should understand software and product development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, your products shall improve.
Your customers shall be delighted.
How your highly qualified teams develop software shall become more effective and efficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First comes quality, effectiveness and only later efficiency.
Look at &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lean_software_development&#34;&gt;lean methods&lt;/a&gt;.
First we improve the quality-effectiveness for the customer, then the productivity and efficiency for the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_minimum_viable_change&#34;&gt;Minimum Viable Change&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;_what_is_coaching&#34;&gt;What is coaching?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;quoteblock&#34;&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coaching means that an experienced coach will work closely together with an organization to improve the organization’s product development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This usually involved shortening feedback loops and focusing on improved quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This faster feedback cycle leads to benefits such as higher productivity and more flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;attribution&#34;&gt;
— https://less.works/[LeSS]
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;_how_shall_you_coach&#34;&gt;How shall you coach?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You use &lt;em&gt;Minimum Viable Change&lt;/em&gt; (MVC).
So I am using yet another acronym.
Each MVC has a hypothesis about how to improve an aspect of your organization or your team.
It has measurements – often called KPI by management – to decide if the change was a worthy improvement.
For the savvy readers, it is a variant of PDCA, a cornerstone of all agile and lean approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our core strength at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tangly.net/&#34;&gt;tangly&lt;/a&gt; is we truly understand software technology and software craftsmen.
We consistently connect organizational MVC with technical MVC.
This is our special recipe for deep-rooted and lasting success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_three_ways_of_coaching&#34;&gt;Three Ways of Coaching&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To improve your organization, you need these three levels of coaching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;dlist&#34;&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt class=&#34;hdlist1&#34;&gt;Organizational coaching&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The coach works with multiple teams and the management to improve the organization and its structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;ulist&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Change processes to be customer-centric.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Improve organization to see the whole product and the customer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delegate decision-making processes to your teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remove functional silos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Redefine the roles of product managers, middle managers, quality managers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eliminate waste: processes and artefacts not adding any value to the customer products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt class=&#34;hdlist1&#34;&gt;Team coaching&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The coach works with one or a few teams to improve their team-working and LeSS practices.
It is common for a coach to take on the Scrum Master role.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;ulist&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implement MVC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Improve Scrum approach, teach agile values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduce &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.extremeprogramming.org/&#34;&gt;eXtreme Programming&lt;/a&gt; practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Improve decision-making, meetings, flow of customer value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn, teach, coach through the stages of Shu Ha Ri (守破離).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Empower the team to turn into the best of breed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt class=&#34;hdlist1&#34;&gt;Technical coaching&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The coach works with (or on) a team on their actual codebase in order to improve technical practices and adopt agile development techniques such as simple design, refactoring, unit testing, test-driven development and acceptance test-driven development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;ulist&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discovering “code/design smells”.
Places where code/design could be improved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explaining modern, “clean” code that is simple and easier to change and maintain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Refactoring “smells” into clean code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Test-driven development and test automation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continuous integration and continuous delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Specification by Example&lt;/em&gt; (Acceptance Test-Driven Development).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Efficient and effective working practices (IDE, automation).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Applying design patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_thoughts&#34;&gt;Thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that the right mindset is boosted by good practice, just as good practice cannot be achieved without the correct mindset.
When advising others, I spend much of my time trying to connect practice with a mindset, as they are symbiotic.
You truly need both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choose wisely your coaches.
Check they can coach at technical, team and organization level.
Senior coaches shall have a decade of experience.
Good coaches practice &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gemba&#34;&gt;Gemba&lt;/a&gt; and should restrain drawing too many slides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Fun at Workplace</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/fun-at-workplace/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2017/fun-at-workplace/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;div class=&#34;sect1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;_fun_at_workplace&#34;&gt;Fun at Workplace&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sectionbody&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;imageblock left&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;../pics/2017-04-01-head.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;2017 04 01 head&#34; width=&#34;420&#34; height=&#34;360&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is Spring in Switzerland.
We often have time for small talk because it is cold or rainy outside.
Quite a few of the discussions are about job opportunities, and how interesting and motivating the current activities are.
I selected two articles to help everybody to decide if your software development job is worth the effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just go through the questions and ask yourself if the current product provides the current settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_joel_test&#34;&gt;Joel Test&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Joel Test is slightly outdated.
Keep his questions and just do the following changes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;ulist&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you replace CVS with Git to reflect the current state of the industry?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Move from daily builds to continuous builds at check-in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember &amp;#34;Daily Builds are for Wimps&amp;#34;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not only fix bugs but also write the associated automated unit and acceptance tests.
Remember &lt;em&gt;Defect Driven Development&lt;/em&gt; to guaranty your customer.
He will never again see the same issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check that your specification also has acceptance criteria which can be automated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Microsoft developers, are you forced to use TFS instead of tools of your choice and why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you testers and quality experts integrated into your Scrum team and sitting in the same room?
Do you think about tester and quality as roles and not people?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do new candidates code and perform refactoring to achieve clean code during their interview?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codypowell.com/taods/2009/12/the-codypo-test-aka-8-questions-to-identify-a-lame-programming-job.html&#34;&gt;8 Questions to identify a lame programming job&lt;/a&gt;.
The questions are up-to-date.
His final remark is worth remembering&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No matter how great the potential projects and teammates might be, I don’t think you can do truly meaningful work in an environment where you, the developer, aren’t empowered to succeed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a company doesn’t get that, then they don’t get the software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_my_personal_list&#34;&gt;My personal list&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My personal list is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;ulist&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is respect a key value of your organization and your team?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you creating a meaningful product and improving the quality of life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you working in an agile team, preferably a Scrum team?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Has your team as sustainable development rhythm?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you using good software practice daily, such as TDD, ATDD, refactoring, check-in in Git master, CI/CD, deliver each day?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you contribute to the open source projects you are using during work time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are developing in Java, are you using IntelliJ IDEA as IDE?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take ten minutes to decide if your current job is good enough.
If not, it is time to regain ownership of your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Found a Limited Liability Company in Switzerland</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/found-a-limited-liability-company-in-switzerland/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/found-a-limited-liability-company-in-switzerland/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;div class=&#34;sect1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;_found_a_limited_liability_company_in_switzerland&#34;&gt;Found a Limited Liability Company in Switzerland&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sectionbody&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;imageblock left&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;../pics/2016-11-02-head.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;2016 11 02 head&#34; width=&#34;420&#34; height=&#34;360&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I left the company I founded 20 years ago and needed a new home to work and have access to social insurance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best legal construct in Switzerland and in Europe is to establish a limited liability company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need such a construct in Switzerland to work as a software specialist.
The legal Swiss institutions, such as taxes, social insurances, and accident insurances are challenging and almost unfair with freelancers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had to found a limited liability company with a capital of CHF 20&amp;#39;000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here the steps for the impatient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_foundation&#34;&gt;Foundation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;olist arabic&#34;&gt;
&lt;ol class=&#34;arabic&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.swissregistration.ch/&#34;&gt;Swissregistration&lt;/a&gt; wrote the statutes for the company and performed the foundation with certifying notary for CHF 780.
Six hours after the first phone call they sent me the electronic documents.
The next day, the documents were delivered in paper form.
It was really impressive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you can find a company you must deposit the capital into a special account.
I choose &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.postfinance.ch/&#34;&gt;Postfinance&lt;/a&gt;.
It is a well-known Swiss institute and their fee is only CHF 145.
They insisted I met one of their collaborators to fill their forms – probably never heard about web forms -.
I had bad luck.
They needed three weeks to create the account and send payment confirmation.
They were aware of the problem and very helpful, but it still took three weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon reception of the payment confirmation, I sent all signed documents to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.swissregistration.ch/&#34;&gt;Swissregistration&lt;/a&gt;.
The next day the company was founded, and I received the official paper documents a few hours later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zg.ch/behoerden/volkswirtschaftsdirektion/handelsregisteramt&#34;&gt;Handelsregisteramt Zug&lt;/a&gt; to register the company.
They were very nice but told me they had a lot of work.
Two weeks later, they finally registered the company and sent me the papers and an invoice of CHF 780.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few phone calls later &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.postfinance.ch/&#34;&gt;Postfinance&lt;/a&gt; converted the account into a regular account.
They give me access to the founding capital minus their fee&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the waiting time, I started to organise for the mandatory insurances you need in Switzerland&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;ulist&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BVG – the best offer was from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.axa-winterthur.ch/&#34;&gt;Axa Winthertur&lt;/a&gt;.
They also help me because the company CRIF AG wrongly classified the activities of the new company.
They never contacted me and their NOGA classification has a huge impact on my costs.
They are arrogant morons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BU/NBU – the best offer was from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.baloise.ch/&#34;&gt;Basler Versicherung&lt;/a&gt;
When starting a software startup I suggest not concluding any other insurances&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The government controlled social insurance contracts can only be initiated once the company is registered in the Swiss company registry.
The AHV center needed more than two weeks to confirm my registration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_lessons_learnt&#34;&gt;Lessons Learnt&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;ulist&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The costs of founding my limited company in Switzerland are CHF 1&amp;#39;705 or 8.5% of the capital of the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The state-owned companies and state services are very slow; in my case 20 times slower than the private ones.
On the bright side, their collaborators are very supportive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Public or big private companies, such as insurance firms, are incapable of sending documents or invoices electronically.
They only use paper mail.
Upon inquiry, their collaborators told me their processes are incapable of handling modern communication ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon foundation, you get pseudo-official letters from various companies to sell dubious services.
Just throw them away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The industry development office of Kanton Zug has no clues about start-up companies; the ones in Zürich and Luzern seem better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph text-center&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Now we are ready to create great products with our customers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please leave a comment if you know a better or less expensive way to found a Swiss liability company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/found-limited-liability-company-switzerland-marcel-baumann&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; was also published on LinkedIn)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: What is an Agile Company?</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/what-is-an-agile-company/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/what-is-an-agile-company/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;div class=&#34;sect1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;_what_is_an_agile_company&#34;&gt;What is an Agile Company?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sectionbody&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;imageblock left&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;../pics/2016-11-01-head.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;2016 11 01 head&#34; width=&#34;420&#34; height=&#34;360&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately, people often ask me what is an agile company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They have an understanding of agile software development techniques such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://scrumguides.org/&#34;&gt;Scrum&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lean_software_development/&#34;&gt;Lean Software Development&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kanban/&#34;&gt;Kanban&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.extremeprogramming.org/&#34;&gt;eXtreme Programming&lt;/a&gt; but no clue how a company could be agile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One way to approach this theme is to implement concepts of the above-mentioned agile approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are the pillars for iterative incremental improvements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_scrum_pillars&#34;&gt;Scrum Pillars&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;dlist&#34;&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt class=&#34;hdlist1&#34;&gt;Transparency&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You trust all collaborators to provide their best when working on the product.
They need full access to all relevant information: quality, progress, budget, people and financial data.
They use the data to select the best alternatives to reach the company’s goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt class=&#34;hdlist1&#34;&gt;Inspection&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You cherish a failure culture because inspections will find weak points.
You need a culture where people are never blamed.
One consequence is that you eliminate management by objectives, and bonuses in your company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt class=&#34;hdlist1&#34;&gt;Adaptation&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are ready to learn better approaches and truly believe there is a better solution.
Processes change regularly bottom-up, company’s budget can only be a rolling indicative budget, and planning has to be &lt;em&gt;continuously&lt;/em&gt; updated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also pursue desirable attitudes or values of agile persons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_scrum_values&#34;&gt;Scrum Values&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;dlist&#34;&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt class=&#34;hdlist1&#34;&gt;Commitment&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an employee you want to win, you are engaged.
Every manager truly believes you work best to achieve the goals.
If not, this manager made a mistake by hiring or keeping you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt class=&#34;hdlist1&#34;&gt;Courage&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are ready to say “I am wrong” because being wrong opens the door for improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt class=&#34;hdlist1&#34;&gt;Focus&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You daily optimise the customers’ value and thrive for excellence.
As a developer, you do not work on projects, you work on excellent products.
You provide value to your customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt class=&#34;hdlist1&#34;&gt;Openness&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You seek better ideas and ways of doing.
Openness requires transparency and respect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt class=&#34;hdlist1&#34;&gt;Respect&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You truly respect customers, team members, collaborators, and people.
In your team, I will not hear any disrespectful comments about people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_modern_agile&#34;&gt;Modern Agile&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://modernagile.org/&#34;&gt;modern agile movement&lt;/a&gt; defines guiding principles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;dlist&#34;&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt class=&#34;hdlist1&#34;&gt;Make people awesome&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dedicated collaborators want to give their best.
Give them a purpose, a goal, empower them and let them climb the mountain.
Thriving people need purpose, excellence and autonomy.
They are happier, healthier and more productive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt class=&#34;hdlist1&#34;&gt;Deliver value continuously&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maintain sustainable pace and stability, all divisions of the organisation should focus on customer value.
At the end of the day, successful products are the only reason you get your paycheck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt class=&#34;hdlist1&#34;&gt;Make safety a prerequisite&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People do their best in their daily work, you believe in McGregor Y theory.
Trust them and support them to become excellent.
You shall develop self-awareness to increase safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt class=&#34;hdlist1&#34;&gt;Experiment and learn rapidly&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You make mistakes, you learn and increase continuously the delivered value.
You have a learning culture, you inspect and adapt.
You can react to new opportunities faster than competitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_self_assessment&#34;&gt;Self Assessment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;imageblock left&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;../pics/2016-10-01-transformation-values.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;2016 10 01 transformation values&#34; width=&#34;420&#34; height=&#34;360&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above concepts are comprehensible.
How do you know if you are moving in the right direction?
A few concrete tests help you find out if you are an agile department or company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;ulist&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Be agile&lt;/em&gt; instead of &lt;em&gt;do agile&lt;/em&gt;.
Practice the above attitudes and do not just follow a checklist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nobody micromanages in your company&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Feel accountable&lt;/em&gt; instead of &lt;em&gt;being accountable&lt;/em&gt;.
You want to improve, and your company as a natural part of the daily work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Compliment every collaborator&lt;/em&gt; you are working with at least once a week instead of &lt;em&gt;evaluating weaknesses and criticising people&lt;/em&gt;.
Do you lead by example?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No management by objectives - MBO - or bonuses are established in your company&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every collaborator has access to all company data, every collaborator can request process and tool changes.
We favour &lt;em&gt;Individuals and interactions over tools and processes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You want to be excellent in your work.
You have a purpose and autonomy in your daily work&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team members take the decision to hire or to fire collaborators, not the department responsible or the human resources group.
Think about collaborators selecting their leaders, about managers being servants, about information available to all collaborators&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you say these essential sentences at least three times a week?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;ulist&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the most important one word, &lt;em&gt;Sorry.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the most important two words, &lt;em&gt;Thank you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the most important three words, &lt;em&gt;I was wrong.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and the most important four words, &lt;em&gt;Can I help you?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I truly believe that we all want a fulfilling job which improves our world.
I cannot understand other reasons to spend 40 hours and more per week for something less valuable.
Take the above principles and apply them to your daily work.
There are universal values to establish a working atmosphere you are proud of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I agree with all of you to desire a fulfilling job is only true if you earn enough money to pay your monthly bills.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_food_for_thoughts&#34;&gt;Food for Thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These ideas are not new.
You can delve in empirical evidence and discussions in books written by business management professors, CEO, and passionate agile advocates.
Below a list of mind openers (available as Amazon ebooks):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;hdlist&#34;&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;hdlist1&#34;&gt;
Reinventing organisations
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;hdlist2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A guide to creating organisations inspired by the next stage of human consciousness by Frederic Laloux,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;hdlist1&#34;&gt;
Accelerate
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;hdlist2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building strategy agility for a fast moving world by John P. Kotter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;hdlist1&#34;&gt;
Beyond budgeting
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;hdlist2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How managers can break free from the annual performance trap;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;hdlist1&#34;&gt;
The Leader’s Dilemma
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;hdlist2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to build an empowered and adaptive organisation without losing control; both books by Jeremy Hope,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;hdlist1&#34;&gt;
Holacracy
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;hdlist2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the new management system for a rapidly changing world by Brian J. Robertson,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;hdlist1&#34;&gt;
Deliver Happiness
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;hdlist2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A path to profits, passion and purpose by Tony Hsieh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;hdlist1&#34;&gt;
The Lean Startup
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;hdlist2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How today’s entrepreneurs use continuous innovation to create radically successful businesses by Eric Ries,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;hdlist1&#34;&gt;
Lean Novels
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;hdlist2&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;dlist&#34;&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt class=&#34;hdlist1&#34;&gt;The Lean Manager&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A novel of lean transformation;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt class=&#34;hdlist1&#34;&gt;Lead with Respect&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A novel of lean practice;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt class=&#34;hdlist1&#34;&gt;The Gold Mine&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A novel of lean turnaround; all three books by Freddy Balle,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;hdlist1&#34;&gt;
The Lean Mindset
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;hdlist2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask the right questions by Mary Poppendieck,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;hdlist1&#34;&gt;
Social Intelligence
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;hdlist2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new science of human relationships, by Daniel Goleman&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;hdlist1&#34;&gt;
Management 3.0
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;hdlist2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leading agile developers, developing agile leaders by Jurgen Appelo,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;hdlist1&#34;&gt;
The Fifth Discipline
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;hdlist2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The art and practice of the learning organisation by Peter M. Senge,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;hdlist1&#34;&gt;
Fearless Change
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;hdlist2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patterns for introducing new ideas; More Fearless Change: Strategies for making your ideas happen; both books by Linda Rising,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;hdlist1&#34;&gt;
Excellence Novels
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;hdlist2&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;dlist&#34;&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt class=&#34;hdlist1&#34;&gt;Build to Last&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Successful habits of visionary companies;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt class=&#34;hdlist1&#34;&gt;Good to Great&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why some companies make the leap… and others don’t;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt class=&#34;hdlist1&#34;&gt;How the Mighty Fall&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And why some companies never give in; all three books by Jim Collins,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;hdlist1&#34;&gt;
Google re:work
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;hdlist2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google blog about work environment and work techniques&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/what-agile-company-marcel-baumann&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; was also published on LinkedIn)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Why I use a MacBookPro and OS X</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/why-i-use-a-macbookpro-and-os-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2016/why-i-use-a-macbookpro-and-os-x/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;div class=&#34;sect1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;_why_i_use_a_macbookpro_and_os_x&#34;&gt;Why I use a MacBookPro and OS X&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sectionbody&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;imageblock left&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;../pics/2016-03-01-head.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;2016 03 01 head&#34; width=&#34;420&#34; height=&#34;360&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I loved Linux as a young developer.
I compiled new kernels during evening sessions.
I worked hard to install and configure drivers to support the hardware I had bought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I explored forums and talked with technical support specialists to activate hardware or support the resolution of my display.
I struggled days to have the correct drivers for the graphic card and communication components of my notebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I grew older and decided to enjoy my evenings and weekends with my family and friends.
Surely I would prefer to have no virus, trojan and other evils on my workstation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I went to macOS and Apple notebooks without regrets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_gains&#34;&gt;Gains&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The major gains upon migrating to OS X are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;ulist&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No virus scanners are necessary, the speed-up during complex programming and development activities is tremendous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No trouble when updating the operating system, updates are automatic, and often no new start is required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unix Command Line and Tools are available in the console.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://brew.sh/&#34;&gt;Homebrew&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.macports.org/&#34;&gt;MacPorts&lt;/a&gt; projects provide all known and less-known utilities and programs available under Linux
&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;[&lt;a id=&#34;_footnoteref_1&#34; class=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#_footnotedef_1&#34; title=&#34;View footnote.&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A long-lived notebook is still working and looking nice after five years of daily usage.
The performance is more than adequate for software development with Java 8/9/10/11 stack and C++.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last notebooks I had all lasted between six and nine years.
These computers were used daily the first five years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_daily_development&#34;&gt;Daily Development&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tools I really enjoy and use on a daily basis for software development – mainly Java - are&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;ulist&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jetbrains.com/idea/&#34;&gt;IntelliJ IDEA&lt;/a&gt; IDE,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Atlassian Cloud applications - BitBucket, HipChat, CI pipeline -,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://brew.sh/&#34;&gt;Homebrew&lt;/a&gt; as package manager for utilities,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Docker as container manager,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VirtualBox when I need a full-fledged virtual machine,
&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;[&lt;a id=&#34;_footnoteref_2&#34; class=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#_footnotedef_2&#34; title=&#34;View footnote.&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_daily_work&#34;&gt;Daily Work&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use these tools to perform administrative work are&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;ulist&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.libreoffice.org/&#34;&gt;LibreOffice&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Business for team work in the cloud using collaborative tools,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple Mail Client with &lt;a href=&#34;https://gpgtools.org/&#34;&gt;GPG&lt;/a&gt; plugin for PGP and S/MIME secure email,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A local Swiss application &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.banana.ch&#34;&gt;Banana&lt;/a&gt; for accounting and VAT reports for the federal government.
I bought it as soon as the company stopped requesting higher prices for OS X than for the other platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LibreOffice completely replaced Microsoft Office suite.
I stopped using OpenOffice after the strange behavior of Oracle with the application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never really regretted leaving Linux or &lt;a href=&#34;https://ubuntu.com/&#34;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt; behind me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnote&#34; id=&#34;_footnotedef_1&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;#_footnoteref_1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;. I use currently Homebrew. The available packages and the handling are excellent.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnote&#34; id=&#34;_footnotedef_2&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;#_footnoteref_2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;. The need of virtual machines for daily work is fading away
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
