<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Crm on tangly Components</title>
    <link>https://blog.tangly.net/tags/crm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Crm on tangly Components</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.tangly.net/tags/crm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Meaningful Identifiers</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/meaningful-identifiers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/meaningful-identifiers/</guid>
      <description>Identifiers are a key concept to successfully model complex business domains. They permeate how our modern civilization functions.&#xA;Could you imagine a country without a car registration number of vehicles, internet addresses, postal addresses or social security numbers?&#xA;Identifiers are identifiers.&#xA;Identifiers cannot be changed at any time.&#xA;Updating identifiers means introducing mapping relations between the old and the new values.&#xA;In computer science, identifiers IDs are lexical tokens that name entities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Value Objects as Embedded Entities</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/value-objects-as-embedded-entities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2021/value-objects-as-embedded-entities/</guid>
      <description>This post discusses the value object pattern, and the factory pattern, which are tactical patterns in the domain-driven design Domain-Driven Design approach.&#xA;Value objects represent typed values that have no conceptual identity in your domain. They can help you write better codes that are less error-prone, more performant and more expressive.&#xA;Value objects define the second kind of domain objects besides entities. Their main characteristic is immutability:&#xA;Attributes of a value object never change.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reference Codes</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/reference-codes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/reference-codes/</guid>
      <description>Reference codes are an old concept. They are often used in the relational database schema definition as enumeration values. The database specialists often call them lookup tables.&#xA;Reference codes are dynamic enumeration values. By dynamic, we mean you can add values without recompiling the source code.&#xA;In modern DevOps environments where deployment of a new version is performed in minutes, this advantage is somewhat shallow. We view reference codes more as strongly typed and efficient tags.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The power of Tags and Comments</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/the-power-of-tags-and-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/the-power-of-tags-and-comments/</guid>
      <description>A software architect models customer domains and maps them to excellent software constructs. The solution shall support future customer groups and expand to store additional information.&#xA;Tags, also called labels, provide an informal ontology to classify customer data.&#xA;Tags are extensible and are machine-readable.&#xA;Comments empower users to store relevant unstructured information.&#xA;Comments are only for human beings.&#xA;What are good approaches to provide searchable tags and labels and avoid wild growth of useless records?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Entities, Identifiers, External identifiers and Names</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/entities-identifiers-external-identifiers-and-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/entities-identifiers-external-identifiers-and-names/</guid>
      <description>A software architect models customer domains and maps them to powerful software abstractions [1]. Soon you correlate internal efficient identifiers, meaningful external identifiers, and domain entities.&#xA;You enjoy long conversations with the enterprise data architect and identify the system owning a specific external identifier.&#xA;How do you relate to external systems and communicate with other companies?&#xA;How do you define internal identifiers, which grow with application success?&#xA;How can you bridge the customer world with your software solution?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Journey Implementing Digital Invoices</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/a-journey-implementing-digital-invoices/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/blog/2020/a-journey-implementing-digital-invoices/</guid>
      <description>Our company has the ambition to digitize all our workflows since our inception. We proudly state we never bought a printer or a fax machine. Analog machines should become obsolete in the digital age.&#xA;Companies should be more environment-aware and save some trees. See our blog on A Journey to Be a Digital Company.&#xA;Switzerland finally introduced a digital payment slip. It uses a QR code and still assumes you need to print it.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
