<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gleam - Library to import and export domain objects to TSV and JSON data files on tangly Components</title>
    <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/gleam/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gleam - Library to import and export domain objects to TSV and JSON data files on tangly Components</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.tangly.net/docs/gleam/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Readme</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/gleam/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/gleam/readme/</guid>
      <description>Purpose Download and Documentation The library can be included in Maven as&#xA;&amp;lt;dependency&amp;gt; &amp;lt;groupId&amp;gt;net.tangly&amp;lt;/groupId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;artifactId&amp;gt;gleam&amp;lt;/artifactId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;version&amp;gt;0.2.7&amp;lt;/version&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/dependency&amp;gt; The library can be included in Gradle as&#xA;implementation &amp;#34;net.tangly:gleam:0.2.7&amp;#34; The documentation can be found under Commons documentation.&#xA;Awesome Sponsors and Developers Corporate sponsors are&#xA;tangly llc&#xA;Individual developers are&#xA;Marcel Baumann&#xA;Alexandra Junghans</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Release Notes</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/gleam/releasesnotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/gleam/releasesnotes/</guid>
      <description>Gleam Library Change Logs This document provides a high-level view of the changes introduced in the Gleam library by release. For a detailed view of what has changed, refer to the repository commits.&#xA;0.2.7 (2024-05-31) Update of library dependencies, update to JDK-21, and modern Gradle approach to build solutions&#xA;0.2.6 (2021-08-31) Update of the dependencies&#xA;0.2.5 (2020-08-31) Initial release of the library&#xA;Framework to generate the TSV representation of business entities</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>User Guide Gleam</title>
      <link>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/gleam/userguide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tangly.net/docs/gleam/userguide/</guid>
      <description>User Guide Gleam JSON Mapping Strengths The advantages of the Gleam JSON mapping library are:&#xA;Use POJO - Plain Old Java Objects - and do not require Java Bean naming conventions for getters and setters.&#xA;Support immutable record constructs of Java. The field values are retrieved from CSV record in the first step. The record is constructed with values in the second step.&#xA;Support heterogeneous collections and can instantiate the expected instances through a user provided discriminator function.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
